这是自由统治的终结!
This is the stop of free reign!
我们开始吧!
Here we go!
他们简直像跳探戈舞一样
And they all like a tango
他真是个自信的少年，不是吗?
He's a confident boy, isn't he?
我们开始吧!
Here we go!
很好，很好，很好!
Great, great, great!
这句听不出来
Cannot hear clearly？
我想一切都结束了
I think it's all over
欢呼
CHEERING
两个足球强国在世界杯决赛中相遇
Two great footballing nations meet in the World Cup final
这将是场载入史册的比赛
The past, the present and the future united
（法语）
(French words I don't know)
现在，世界上最盛大的体育盛会
And now, the greatest sporting occasion of the world
马上就要开始了
is about to begin
32支球队争夺足球的终极大奖
32 teams competing for the ultimate prize in football
一个人主导了整个过程
One man has dominated the proceedings
梅西!
Messi!
在今晚的决赛中，他将成为万众瞩目的焦点
And in tonight's final, all eyes will be on him
姆巴佩!
Mbappé!
很多朋友都希望他安息
Whom so many friends hope to rest
他又这样做了!
He's done it again!
奇迹少年!
The Boy Wonder!
这将是一场足以诠释足球之美丽的伟大比赛
This will be a good contest to the beauty of the game of football
你是个婴儿
You're a baby
哦，我会的
Oh, I shall
哦，我想说
Oh, I shall say
这就是你会得到的
This is what you'll get
当你测量它的时候
When you measure it out
法国和阿根廷都在争夺第三座大力神杯
Both France and Argentina are chasing a third World Cup
法国希望成为继1958年和1962的巴西之后
France hoping to become the first nation since Brazil in 1958
第一个二连冠的国家
and 1962 to retain the trophy
这是阿根廷的“护身符”利昂内尔·梅西第参加的第26次杯赛
Argentina's talisman, Lionel Messi, makes his 26th tournament appearance
打破了由洛塔尔·马特乌斯保持的纪录
beating the record held by Lothar Matthäus
基利安·姆巴佩可能会随法国队赢得他的第二个世界杯冠军
Killian Mbappe could win his second World Cup with France
在他23岁的时候
at the age of 23
梅西和姆巴佩领跑金靴奖
Messi and Mbappe lead the Golden Boot standings
每个人都有5个进球
with five goals each
金色的夕阳正照耀着卢塞尔体育场
There's a golden glow around the Lusail stadium
夜幕即将降临卡塔尔
Dusk has settled here in Qatar
这场比赛预计会有近9万人到场
A crowd of almost 90,000 expected
他们中的绝大多数似乎都支持阿根廷
The vast majority of them supporting Argentina, it seems
阿兰·希勒和里奥·费迪南德来到了演播室
Alan Shearer and Rio Ferdinand have made it this far
还有2014年随阿根廷队获得世界杯亚军巴勃罗·萨巴莱塔
Along with Pablo Zabaleta, a World Cup runner-up with Argentina
按照英国广播公司第一频道的惯例，
As is customary on BBC One for major football finals,
我们主要转播的是赛事本身
we're going to concentrate on the action
但如果你想看闭幕式，
But if you would like to watch the closing ceremony,
您可以到iPlayer, BBC体育网站
it will be live on iPlayer, the BBC Sport website,
或几分钟后点按红色按钮观看
and the red button in a few minutes
比赛计划在1:55开始
It's scheduled to start at five to two
巴勃罗，你现在心情怎样，兴奋还是紧张？
Pablo, excited, nervous?
真的很兴奋
Really excited
事实上，世界杯开赛以来我都比较平静
Actually, I've been all right the whole tournament,
但是今天此刻我很紧张
but today I'm so nervous right now
这是一场重要的比赛
This is a big game
重要得不能再重要了
They don't come any bigger
我没有发抖，但我现在确实太紧张了
I'm not shaking, but I'm just so nervous, of course
你们的队伍在2014年错失了良机
You missed out, obviously, in the final in 2014
你参加了比赛，但你没有赢得比赛
You played, but you didn't win the tournament
一定程度上来讲，我认为只有梅西在今晚的首发阵容中
I suppose in some ways, I think only Messi is in the starting lineup tonight from that team
但你一定是百感交集吧
but there must be some kind of mixed emotions for you
是的，当然
Yes, of course
我多么希望我还在更衣室中
I wish I was in that dressing room again
我们在2014年错过了一个大好机会
You know, we missed a big chance in 2014
在1990年意大利之后，用了24年
It took 24 years after Italy in 1990
再次进入世界杯决赛
to be again in a World Cup final
现在，8年过去了，我们再次迎来了一个巨大的机遇
Now, eight years later, we are again with a big opportunity
八年后，梅西是唯一一个
Messi is the only one eight years later
所以，是的，我希望我在球场上
So, yeah, I wish I was there on the field
百分百希望
A hundred percent
好吧，让我们来告诉你一些球队的新闻
OK, well, let's give you some of the team news
我们刚把他们弄进来
We've just got them in
阿根廷只有一个改变
There's just one changer for Argentina
迪玛利亚在这次比赛中一直受到大腿受伤的影响
Di Maria has been hampered by a thigh injury at this tournament
淘汰赛只打了九分钟，
and has played just nine minutes in the knockouts,
但他在中场右路为帕雷德斯换防
but comes in on the right-hand side of midfield for Paredes
塔利亚·菲科顶替阿库尼亚首发
Taglia Fico keeps his plays ahead of Acuña
而梅西，就像我之前说的，是球队中唯一参与了2014年世界杯决赛的球员
And Messi, as I said before, the only survivor from the team that started the 2014 final loss to Germany
另一边，法国队也饱受病痛的困扰
The French squad has been well beset by illness, hasn't it?
本周还有伤病问题
And injury issues this week
然而，迪迪埃·德尚在得知吉鲁从膝伤恢复这个消息之后大受鼓舞
However, Didier Deschamps was boosted by the news that Giroud has overcome a knee injury to start
维拉诺和皮马卡诺已经摆脱了一种类似流感的疾病
Verrano and Pimacano have shaken off a flu-like illness
为了形成中央防线
to line up in central defence,
拉比奥也恢复了中场首发的位置
and Rabio has also recovered to start in midfield
关于迪·玛丽亚的简短消息，巴勃罗
Quick line on Di Maria, Pablo
他被录取了，你觉得奇怪吗?
Is it surprising that he's got in?
他不怎么踢足球
He's not played much football
这并不令我惊讶
It doesn't surprise me
当他们在巴西赢得美洲杯冠军时，情况也是如此
It was exactly the same in Copa America when they won it in Brazil
他在决赛中被埃斯卡罗尼打伤了
He was injured by Escaloni playing him in the final
他在对巴西队的比赛中被抓住了
He's caught against Brazil
我认为这有点棘手，因为我们没有其他球员
I think it's a bit tricky because we don't have another player
来取代他
to replace him
他是我认为最有能力的人
He's the one that I think is driven ability still up there
作为最好的之一
as one of the best
他是今天能给特奥·埃尔南德斯制造麻烦的人之一
He's one of them that today can cause trouble to Teo Hernandez
是的
Yeah
令人垂涎的前景
Mouth-watering prospect this one
他什么都懂一点
He's got a bit of everything
上个月我们打了63场比赛，
Yeah, 63 games we've had over the last month,
最后是最好的两支球队，最好的两名球员
and it's ended up with the best two teams, the best two players
我等不及了
And I cannot wait
它应该是宏伟的
It should be magnificent
我们应该有目标
We should have goals
阿尔瓦雷斯和吉鲁也都进了4球
Alvarez, Giroux all on four goals also
格列兹曼举办了一场精彩的比赛，所以应该很棒
Griezmann's had a magnificent tournament, so it should be great
不，不，我保证
No, no, guaranteed
这应该是一部惊悚片，里约
It should be a thriller, Rio
你怎么看?
How do you see it?
是的,当然
Yeah, definitely
我认为有几个关键领域
I think there's key areas
左边是法国的薄弱区域
The left-hand side for France is their weak area
我相信我们以后再讨论这个问题
We'll discuss that later, I'm sure
但我认为，就像阿尔瓦雷斯说的，
But I think it's also, like Alvarez said there,
梦幻场景，两位超级巨星进入决赛
dream-dream scenario, getting two superstars in the final
两支伟大的球队，两位超级巨星正面交锋
Two great teams, two superstars going head to head
这可能是警卫的变动，
This could be the change in the guard,
也可能是每个人都想要的童话和信息
or it could be the fairytale and the message that everyone's asking for
我们拭目以待
So we'll see
我们会的
We will
巴勃罗，告诉我在世界杯决赛的早晨醒来是什么感觉
Pablo, tell me what it's like waking up on the morning of a World Cup final
知道你要去玩
and knowing that you're going to be playing
我记得，我的第一个想法就是今天
Well, I remember, my first thought was today's the day
当然，这是一个特殊的日子，
It's a special day, of course,
头天晚上很难睡个好觉，
and it was so hard the night before to get some good sleep,
因为有两个原因
because there were two reasons
首先，因为我以前从未有过的紧张和焦虑
Firstly, because of the nerves and that kind of anxiety that I never had before
其次，酒店外面有很多巴西人
But secondly, there were a lot of Brazilian outside the hotel
她会在凌晨两三点放烟花
She's letting off fireworks at 2, 3 am in the morning
即使你不是在和我比赛，
Even though you weren't playing against me,
这显然是竞争
it was obviously that rivalry
这是一次很棒的经历
You know, it was a great experience
对你来说，保持同样的生活习惯很难吗?
Was it difficult for you to keep your same routine?
是啊，太难了
Yeah, it was so difficult
因为你通常都有自己的套路，不是吗?
Because you have a routine normally, don't you?
当然可以
Of course
而里约，这只是世界杯决赛的其中一天
And Rio, it's just one of those days that is a World Cup final
然后你就会想，这要花多长时间
And then you're just thinking, how long is it going to take
有机会玩那种游戏?
to have an opportunity to play that kind of game?
所以阿根廷花了8年时间
So it was eight years for Argentina
哦，是的，不可思议
Oh, yeah, incredible
闭幕式正在进行中
The closing ceremony is just getting underway
记住，它在Red Button网站和iPlayer上直播
Remember, it's live on the Red Button website and iPlayer
如果你这周想看国际足联主席詹尼·因凡蒂诺，
If you want to watch FIFA President Gianni Infantino this week,
称这是有史以来最好的世界杯
called it the best World Cup ever
我就知道你会的
I had a feeling you might
马克·查普曼一直在思考人们将如何记住这场比赛
Mark Chapman has been reflecting on how the tournament will be remembered
冬天，2022年，还有世界杯
Winter, 2022, and the World Cup
这一切始于一种感觉
And it began with a feeling
今天，我感到卡塔里
Today, I feel Katari
一种感觉，无论是卡塔尔还是国际足联
A feeling that both Katar and FIFA
我们要按照自己的方式来做
were very much going to do this their own way
今天，我觉得自己是同性恋
Today, I feel gay
不管外界怎么想
Whatever the outside world may think
一个农民工
A migrant worker
死亡是生命中自然的一部分
Death is a natural part of life
一名工人死亡
A worker died
然而，奇怪的是，这是一种东西
However, it's strange that this is something
你现在就想谈的事
that you want to talk about right now
因凡蒂诺说
Inclusion was in, said Infantino
大家都欢迎
Everyone is welcome
我们的乐队解散了
Our bands were out
德国抗议
Germany protested
但沉默的却是他们的粉丝
But it was their fans who were silent
另一个沉默,
Another silence,
展现出有时沉默的力量
showing the power of sometimes saying nothing
阳光明媚，但彩虹上乌云密布
Lots of sunshine, but a cloud over rainbows
希望他们能让我们进去
Hopefully they'll let us in
尽管如此，足球还是成功了
The football, though, delivered
这对19岁的女孩来说是多么重要的一刻啊!
What a moment for the 19-year-old!
金童，一种沙特阿拉伯足球
The Golden Boy, a Saudi Arabian football
世界杯全场表演之一
One of the World Cup all-time shows
它在!
It's on!
这很特别
That is special
小心威尔士!
Look out for Wales!
是Reshford!
It is Reshford!
我们会走出更衣室
We'll walk out of that change room
让我们昂首挺胸，为彼此感到骄傲
to our heads held high and proud of each other
对于球迷来说，这届世界杯是独一无二的
For the fans, this World Cup felt unique
他们聚集在地铁上
They gathered on the metro
他们一天可以看两场比赛
They could take in two games in a day
哦，我的天哪!
Oh, my goodness!
现在，酒精创造了更友好的气氛
Now, alcohol created kinder atmospheres
小组赛阶段被誉为有史以来最好的一届
The group stage was hailed as the best ever
120年的目标,
120 goals,
大的表演,
big performances,
甚至更大的冲击
and even bigger shocks
日本进入16强
Japan reached the round of 16
以最难以置信的方式
in the most unbelievable way
这是澳大利亚足球史上的一个重要时刻
This is a huge moment in the football history of Australia
摩洛哥世界杯最精彩的时刻
Morocco's finest World Cup moment
像往常一样，我们有欧洲人
As usual, we had the Europeans
像往常一样，我们有南美人
As usual, we had the South Americans
但是世界上的其他地方制造了这个
But the rest of the world made this one
最多样化的淘汰赛阶段之一
of the most diverse knockout stages ever
不!
No!
现在是世界杯之旅的第二阶段
It's time for Stage 2 of the World Cup journey
梅西!
Messi!
Charlamagne !
Charlamagne!
内马尔!
Neymar!
汉密尔顿!
Hamilton!
非洲的历史
African history
第一支来自非洲大陆的队伍
The first team from the continent ever
进入世界杯半决赛
to reach the World Cup semi-finals
克罗地亚无疑是一个足球奇迹
Croatia surely are a footballing miracle
一切都归结为这一点
It all comes down to this
它向世界播放
It's played into the world
没有比这更大的了
Doesn't get bigger than this
他没打中!
He's missed it!
你知道，我的天哪，这肯定会让人难以忍受
You know, my goodness, it's going to be hard to live with for sure
足球归根结底是一些小细节
Football comes down to small details
梅西的梦想依然存在
And Lionel Messi's dream is still alive
法国连续进入世界杯决赛
France reach successive World Cup finals
还有一场比赛
One game away
有史以来最好的世界杯
The best World Cup ever
本届世界杯将永远被人们铭记
This World Cup was always going to be remembered
因为与众不同
for being different
对球员来说是不同的
Different for the players
对粉丝来说就不一样了
Different for the fans
对你来说不一样
Different for you watching
重要的场外问题必须记住
The important off-field issues must be remembered
但它也将被铭记
But it will also be remembered
为了崇高的目标，
for the sublime goals,
那些不可思议的时刻，
the incredible moments,
感谢你是最后一只天鹅
and for being the final swanson
这么多历史上的伟人
of so many all-time greats
这一切会以梅西最终得到他的双手而告终吗
Will it end with Messi finally getting his hands
在这个大的上面?
on the big one here?
或者法国能成功卫冕吗?
Or will France manage that rare feat of retaining it?
2022年卡塔尔
Qatar 2022
冬季世界杯
The Winter World Cup
令人难忘
Memorable
卡塔尔这里天黑了
It's getting dark here in Qatar
闭幕式仍将举行
The closing ceremony is still going to be held
别忘了你现在知道怎么看了
And don't forget you know how to watch that now
我们在揭幕战前谈过了
Well, we spoke ahead of the opening game
关于比赛的事情
about the fact surrounding the tournament
当然是国际足联的腐败
Corruption at FIFA, of course
早在2010年，农民工的待遇
Back in 2010, the treatment of migrant workers
以及LGBTQ的权利
and LGBTQ plus rights
这些问题依然存在
Those issues remain
至于比赛本身，
But as for the tournament itself,
显然，有一些积极因素
there are some, obviously, many positives
对我们广播公司来说，
For us broadcasters,
我们被允许在演播室里观看比赛
we've been allowed to watch the games in a studio
We've been allowed to watch the games in a studio
显然，我们被允许在演播室里观看比赛
Obviously, we've been allowed to watch the games in a studio
而不是在电视机上
rather than on a TV set,
忽略了比赛本身
overlooking the match itself
但这也是一种真正的多样性
But it's also been a real diverse nature
我是说，世界杯的支持者，
I mean, there always is to World Cup supporters,
但我认为这里的观众略有不同
but a slightly different audience, I think, here
我的意思是，北非在这方面表现突出
I mean, North Africa, for one, have been prominent here
我们有亚洲团队，沙特阿拉伯，
We've had Asian teams, Saudi Arabia,
击败阿根廷
beating Argentina
你能想象他们会说什么吗
Can you imagine, they'd be able to say
他们打败了世界冠军
that they've beaten the World Champions
这是一个巨大的结果
in Argentina today, so it's a huge result
这在很大程度上，
This has been very much that,
我们已经有了很棒的颜色
and great colours that we've had
在一些美妙的场景中
throughout some fantastic scenes
我是说，球员们亲吻和拥抱家人，
I mean, players kissing and hugging family members,
妈妈们，肯定会有大事发生的
mums, it's going to be definitely something
这件事会让我困扰很长一段时间
that will sit for a long time with myself
但是，当你看着它，你会说，
But it's also, when you look at it and you say,
哇，这个地方真的……
wow, this place has really
当你走到外面，看到粉丝们聚在一起，
When you go outside and see the fans together,
这就是区别
that's the difference
你通常会在不同的地方看到扇子，
You normally see fans sectioned off in different areas,
这是一些粉丝的聚集地
and that's the area where certain fans base are
我想可能是酒精的缺乏…
I guess the lack of alcohol might have played a
没有任何威胁的情况
There's been no kind of threatening situations
也许吧，是的，这是一件事
Maybe, yeah, that's the one thing
这里没有暴力事件，也没有任何形式的起义
There's been no violence or no uprisings of any sort here
大家都在一起庆祝
It's been everyone together celebrating
我们有过绝望，有过胜利，也有过失败，
There's been despair, there's been wins, losses together,
他们的脸上一直挂着微笑
and it's been with smiles on their faces
你对冬季世界杯有什么看法?
What about your thoughts on the Winter World Cup?
这是第一个，当然，我想是一个正数
It's the first one, of course, and I suppose one positive
从这个角度来看，世界上有些地方
from that as well, is there are parts of the world
那可能只能容纳，
that could probably only host, really,
晴朗的冬季世界杯，
the clear World Cup in the Winter,
这给了他们对未来的希望，
and it gives them sort of hope for the future,
如果他们再这么做的话
possibly if they do it again
是的，当然，我认为这是…
Yeah, definitely, and I think in the way this has been
即使是今天，在杯赛决赛的那天，我们也来到了体育场
We've come into the stadium even today on the Cup final day
我们进出的基础设施
The infrastructure for us to get into and from
体育场内外的人们都很壮观
people in and out of the stadiums has been magnificent
从这个意义上说
in that sense
我认为比赛的节奏对我来说很重要
And I think the pace of the games is the big thing for me
比赛比平时快
The games are quicker than normal
当你去参加比赛时，有些比赛很慢，
When you go to the tournaments, some games are slow,
有时你就像个行人
and you're pedestrian at times
我想今年这个时候的原因是，
I think the reason of the time of the year this is,
每个人都很新鲜，没有人会一瘸一拐地参加比赛，
everyone's fresh, and no one's limping into a tournament,
我想这是我们能说的最好的了
and I think it's the best we can speak
好吧，我认为有些比赛缺乏气氛
OK, I think some of the games have lacked atmosphere
这是毫无疑问的
There's no question about that
但我认为，当然是北非球队，
But I think, you know, certainly the North African teams,
当然还有南美球队，
and definitely the South American sides,
对我们来说很重要吗
have been very important in giving us
那种正常的足球氛围
that kind of normal football atmosphere
当然，我认为……
Absolutely, and I think
我认为卡帕尔蒂离南美洲很远，
I consider that Capaldi is far away from South America,
但我见过很多巴西和阿根廷球迷
but I have seen a lot of Brazilian and Argentine fans
即使是墨西哥人，我记得在小组赛阶段，
Even people from Mexico, I remember in the group stage,
阿根廷队，墨西哥队，
the game Argentina, the game Mexico,
气氛和球场都很棒，
the atmosphere and the stadiums have been great,
这就是你想看到的
and that's what you like to see
你知道，这对那些国家意味着什么
You know, what it means for those countries
来支持一个团队
to come to support a team
好好锻炼一下身体
and to enjoy a really good workout
艾伦，你对过去的几周有什么感想?
How do you reflect on the last few weeks, Alan?
我认为世界杯的现实更加残酷
I think the reality of the World Cup is even more stark
加里，当你一直生活在那种感觉
Gary, when you've been living in what feels like
上个月有个足球主题公园，是吗?
a football theme park for the last month, doesn't that mean?
如果迪斯尼有足球比赛，
If Disneyland did football tournaments,
但我们必须记住血、汗和泪
but we must remember the blood, sweat and tears
所有成就这一切的人
of everyone that's made it happen
我认为，国际足联做出补偿是正确的
And it's only right, I think, that FIFA compensate
农民工和他们的家庭
the migrant workers and their families
鉴于他们宣布他们已经
Given the fact they announced that they've made
75亿英镑的收入，他们可能负担得起
a £75 billion revenue, they probably afford it
他们有一个遗产基金
And they have a legacy fund
是的，他们也谈到了遗产基金，
Yeah, they talked about a legacy fund also,
但也有出色的球员和神奇的时刻
but also the brilliant players and the moments of magic
比赛毫无价值
A tournament is worthless
是关于梦想，摩洛哥，心痛，
It's about the dream, Morocco, the heartache,
哈利凯恩
Harry Kane
然后你就有了天赋异禀的梅西
Then you've got the genius and the God-given talent of Messi
我们已经拥有了这一切，我想它已经
And we've had all of that, and I think it's been
非常非常精彩的世界杯
a really, really good World Cup
好吧，回到今晚
OK, back to tonight
这是自1978年以来的第一届世界杯，
It's the first World Cup since 1978,
两队在进入决赛的过程中都输了一场比赛
where both teams have lost a game en route to the final
当然是阿根廷，1978年的冠军，
Argentina, of course, with the winners in 78,
可能是个吉兆，巴勃罗
could be a lucky omen, Pablo
下面是他们是如何做到的
Here's how they made it through
音乐戏剧
MUSIC PLAYS
他们突然就在这里不知所措了
And they're all at sea suddenly here
阿根廷，他们现在落后了
Argentina, and they're now behind
碧碧，这是第三个
Bebe, that is the third
他有他的目标
And he has his goal
梅西的统治
Messi for Reigns
阿根廷的救世主
Argentina's saviour
巴巴在等待
And Bapá waiting
巴布得分了
And Bapá is scoring
那是罢课
That was a study strike
Casserie为他打开了大门
Casserie opens up for him
哦，在那儿!
Oh, it's there!
梅西!
Messi!
它必须是
It had to be
Chiroux !
Chiroux!
奥利维尔·奇鲁
And Olivier Chiroux
成为法国队的进球纪录
becomes France's record goal scorer
哦，再来一秒
Oh, a second in
这是一种灾难
That's a scourge
他得分了
And he scores it
丽丝匆匆离去
And Lissé in a rush
好球，奇鲁，这次
Great ball, Chiroux, this time
非凡的奥利维尔·奇鲁
The extraordinary Olivier Chiroux
梅西成功了
Messi gets through
大师的杰作
Made by the master
Bapa,
And Bapá,
旋转
wheeling through
还有一个步兵
And a tap infantry
法国，阿根廷，
It's France, Argentina,
2022年世界杯决赛
in the 2022 World Cup final
如果你刚加入我们
And if you're just joining us,
这是球队新闻的提示
here's a reminder of the team news
马丁内斯成为第一个球员
Martinez becomes the first player
从阿斯顿维拉来到世界杯决赛
from Aston Villa to play in a World Cup final
奥图门迪第100次代表国家队出场
Ottomendi wins his 100th cap
这是一场不错的比赛
Not a bad game to do it in
塔利亚菲科保持着领先Acuña的位置
Tagliafico keeps his place ahead of Acuña
安吉尔·德·玛丽亚做到了
Angel de Maria has managed
淘汰赛只剩九分钟了
just nine minutes in the knockout stage
但从一开始，他就是个没用过的替补
But starts, he was an unused sub
2014年决赛
in the 2014 final
他们中间是梅西和阿尔瓦雷斯
Between them, Messi and Alvarez
得分或助攻
have scored or assisted 11
在他们目前的12个进球中
of their 12 goals so far
值得注意的是，梅西还没有进球
Remarkably, Messi is yet to score
在六项主要赛事的决赛中
in any of the six major tournament finals
他为他的国家效力
he has played in for his country
洛里斯只是第四位选手
Lloris is just the fourth player
连续担任某队的队长
to captain a side in consecutive
罗马尼亚世界杯之后，
World Cup finals after Rumaniga,
马拉多纳和邓加
Maradona and Dunga
但他可能是第一个同时赢得两项大奖的人
But he could be the first to win both
上梅尔科错过了半决赛
Uper Mercano missed the semi
带着病却要回来取
with illness but returns to take
卡纳特的地方
the place of Canate
之后韦兰也恢复了健康
Veran has also been past fit after
患有同样的流感样病菌
suffering with the same flu-like bug
作为拉比奥，他又回来了
As as Rabio, he is back in
在法法纳前面的中场
Central midfield ahead of Fafana
在他们2018年的英雄事迹之后
And after their heroics in 2018
巴普尔和格里兹曼也可以加入
and Bapé and Griezmann can join
瓦瓦，贝利，布莱特纳
Vava, Pele, Breitner
和兹丹是得分最高的球员
and Zdan as players to have scored
多次出现在世界杯决赛中
in multiple World Cup finals
而奥利维尔·吉鲁有机会
While Olivier Giroux has the chance
成为年龄最大的得分手
to become the oldest goal scorer
在世界杯决赛中
in a World Cup final
阿根廷和法国曾交手过
Argentina and France have played each other
此前在世界杯上三次
three times before at World Cups
淘汰赛阶段唯一的相遇
The only meeting in the knockout stages
四年前在俄罗斯
came four years ago in Russia
法国队4-3获胜，
France winning 4-3,
在埃迪埃·迪琼的帮助下
helped by Edidier Dichon,
激励大师班离开了
motivational masterclass that left
一种在世界之巅的感觉
a feeling on top of the world
人们必须理解
People have to understand
管理起来有多难
how difficult it is to manage
更衣室
a dressing room
有26名球员
It's 26 players
自负的人
with huge egos
和所有
and all
其中26个是不同的
26 of them are different
彼此干杯
to each other
作为国家队的主教练
And as a national team head coach
你需要能够导航
you need to be able to navigate
对一些管理者来说非常擅长
to some managers of very good at it
或者是挣扎
or the struggle
他们很难理解这种动态
They struggle to understand the dynamic
机会转瞬即逝
The chance sees it in a wink
它是负的
It's in the negative
理想是做得最少的人
The ideal is the one who did the least
3%
在速度
in speed
这是你的品质
it's your quality
它也是Edidier
It's also Edidier
还有大师班
and the masterclass
当你必须从盒子里出来的时候
When you have to get out of the box
当你不得不下车的时候
when you have to get out of the car
你得稍微靠一点
you have to lean a little bit
或者打右边
or hit on the right
这就是为什么dicchon知道
And that's why Dichon knew
进入2018年世界杯
going into the 2018 World Cup
我可以信赖保罗
I can rely on Paul
保罗将要做的事
Paul is going to do
98年我做了什么
what I did in 98
我们进入淘汰赛阶段
We start the knockout stages
前冠军的对决
with a clash of former champions
现在没有第二次机会了
No second chances now
今天
Today
那就是再见了
it will be Adios
或Awebois
or Awebois
塔利菲科输给了姆巴佩
Taglifico beaten to that by Mbappe
看着他走
watch him go
马斯切拉诺不会靠近他
Mascherano won't get near him
姆巴佩也倒下了
and Mbappe down
这是法国队的点球
It's a penalty for France
这是一种惩罚
It's a penalty for
法国
France
这是一种惩罚
It's a penalty for
法国
France
格里兹曼来了
Here comes Griezmann
法国领先
France have the lead
姆巴佩离开了
Mbappe leaves it
塔弗击中了它
Taver hits it
本杰明抗议者
Benjamin Taver
带着梦的打击
with a dream strike
这是他在法国队的第一个进球
for his first France goal
它进了
And it's in
Mbappe
观察我们的世界
Watch our world
有一个新的数字10
There's a new number 10
吉鲁让它通过了
Giroud gets it through
他又这样做了
He's done it again
男孩的奇迹
The boy wonder
法国有两个
has two for France
我在看
I was watching
法国
the French
当他们赢得世界杯时
when they won the World Cup in
我说过有一天我会
And I said one day I would like
做同样的事
to do the same
2018年
In 2018
梦想成真了
a dream became true
德尚的表现令人难以置信
Deschamps did incredible
低调的负责人
The understated man in charge
作为一名球员，他很谦逊
Unassuming as a player
一个球员和一个经理
a player and a manager
这已经完成并赢得了很多
that has done and won the lot
游戏所给予的一切
Everything that the game has to give
是他
is him
他是世界冠军
He's the world champion
你会在不同的道路上
You'll be on different roads
毫无疑问
without a doubt
但你将与生命联系在一起
But you'll be linked to life
和这个杯子相比
compared to this cup
第二件事
And the second thing
这关系到你，球员们
that concerns you, the players
所有的员工
and all the staff
这是从今晚开始的吗?
is that from tonight
你不再是从前的你了
you're no longer the same
你知道吗?
You know what?
这就是它给你的，不是吗?
That's what it gives you, isn't it?
足球不朽
Footballing immortality
如果你参加世界杯的话
if you're in the World Cup
我们都去过更衣室
We've all been in dressing rooms
你认为经理们的演讲
Do you think managers' speeches
真的能有所作为吗?
can really make a difference?
当然，是的，当然
Absolutely, yeah, definitely
我知道我们现在的心情是对的
I know we're in the right frame of mind
比赛前
before the game
有些人是非常不同的
Some people are very different
有些人希望有人跟他说话
Some people want to be spoken to
有些人需要被吼
Some people need to be shouted at
有些人需要说出真相
Some people need to tell the truth
有些人希望有人跟他说话
Some people want to be spoken to
有些人需要被吼
Some people need to be shouted at
有些人需要告诉他们
Some people need to tell them
被告知要换档什么的
to be told to change the gears, whatever
每个人都是不同的
Everyone's different
但毫无疑问，经理可以做到
But there's no doubt about what a manager can
应该会有所不同
and should make the difference
比赛中场休息前
before the game at half-time
显然在比赛中也是如此
and obviously during the game
这就是他们存在的意义
That's what they're there for
这就是为什么他们要花大价钱
That's why they pay the big books
他们的存在就是为了改变
They're there to make that difference
里奥，你曾经是队长
Rio, you were a captain
你做过演讲吗?
Did you make speeches ever?
我会逐个找个人
I'd go around to individuals
我的反应会非常迅速和敏锐
and I'd be very quick and sharp
信息简明扼要
and concisive of the information
我不会说太多的话
I wouldn't have too many words
比如说，它会是，
It would just be, for instance,
边路球员，尤指助理守门员
wide players, especially assistant goals
我昨天和保罗在健身房
I was actually with Paul yesterday in the gym
保罗·博格巴在照片里
Paul Pogba in the pictures there
还有马克龙总统和凡蒂诺
President Macron, Janium Fantino as well
我们在谈论经理
We were talking about the managers
我永远不会忘记弗格森
and I'll never forget Alex Ferguson
在大型游戏中，你通常会谈论玩家
In big games, you used to talk about players
他们的成长经历和他们来自哪里
and their upbringings and where they're from
他们的旅程是多么艰难
and how hard their journey's been
有些人谈论技能
and some people talk about skills
还有战术等等
and tactics and such
弗格森很擅长获取能量
Alex Ferguson was great at really getting the energy
气泡在流动，
and the bubbles flowing through,
回顾一下你从哪里走到现在
looking back at where you've come from to this point
不要让它溜走
and don't let it slip
我曾为一个叫路易斯·阿拉贡·萨默斯的经理效力
I played for a manager called Luis Aragonés
谁赢得了欧洲杯
who went on to win the European Championship
2008年与西班牙的比赛
with Spain in 2008
他是一个不可思议的人物
He was an incredible character
我记得比赛前他也有这个病
and I remember he had this thing before the game
他过去常把大家聚在一起
He used to get everybody together
在更衣室里
in the dressing room
他把所有人都挤了进去
and he huddled everyone in
他过去常常把球放在中路
and he used to put the ball in the middle
他总是确保每个人都能触到球
and he used to make sure everyone touches the ball
然后他会说，
and everyone and then he'd go,
砰!
BAM!
我记得六个月后
I remember after six months after doing that
他转身对我说，
he turned to me and he went,
加里，你不太喜欢这么做，对吧?
Gary, you don't really like doing that much, do you?
我说，不，不，我只是有点害羞
I went, no, no, I'm just a bit shy
说说迪迪埃·德尚
A word on Didier Deschamps
他做了一件了不起的工作
What a remarkable job he's done
他可以和佩莱埃尔和马里奥·扎加洛相提并论
He could equal Pelé and Mario Zagallo
作为唯一一个
as the only person
曾三次夺得世界杯冠军
that's had three World Cup triumphs
无论是作为球员还是作为教练
either as a player and or a manager
我想那一定很了不起
I think that must be something amazing
是的
Yeah
但你可以看到这对其他玩家意味着什么，
But you can see what it means for the rest of the player,
绝对像个父亲
like a father, absolutely
当你有一群玩家
And when you have a group of player
或者当你有一个所有人都追随的领导者
or when you have a leader that everyone will follow
并且会倾听，
and will listen to,
这将会产生巨大的影响
it's something that would make a huge difference
为足球队准备的
for the football team
这是有史以来最好的管理方式
The best piece of man management that ever happened
对我来说是特里·维纳布尔斯
to me was Terry Venables
你可能知道，在96年欧洲杯之前，
You probably know, leading into Euro 96,
在英国待了两年
England for two years
大约三周后，他把我拉到一边
and he pulled me to one side about three weeks
在比赛开始之前，他说，
before the tournament started and said,
无论接下来的两场友谊赛发生什么
whatever happens in the next two friendly games
你将是我的头号中锋
you will be my number one centre forward
我只是想让他对我有信心
and I just thought for him to have that belief in me
特别是当有
and particularly when there was
那么多其他前锋都在进球
so many other forwards around score and goals
给我巨大的信心
give me huge confidence
我就想我得出去得分
and I just thought I have to go out and score
我不能让他失望
I cannot let this guy down
你没有，艾伦，对吧?
You didn't, Alan, did you?
这是一个很好的进入故事的方式
It's a great way of getting into a story
你是如何赢得欧洲冠军杯金靴的
about how you won a Golden Boot in a European championship
做得很漂亮
That's beautifully done
卡塔尔最年轻的教练
The youngest coach out here in Qatar
是阿根廷的莱昂内尔·斯卡罗尼
is Argentina's Lionel Scaloni
他从来没有在俱乐部执教过
He has never managed at club level
但去年赢得了美国警察大赛
but did win the Cop America last year
蒂姆·维克里为我们带来了这名男子的内幕
Tim Vickery has the lowdown on the man
竞价跟随脚步
bidding to follow in the footsteps
塞萨尔·米诺蒂和卡洛斯·比拉尔多
of Cesar Minotti and Carlos Bilardo
斯卡罗尼是一个乡下男孩
Scaloni is a country boy
他来自一个叫波亚图的小村庄
He's from a little village called Poyatu
离罗萨里奥不远，
Not far outside Rosario,
哪座是阿根廷的第二大城市
which is Argentina's second city
当然在足球方面
certainly in footballing terms
作为一名球员，
As a player,
他不是一个伟大的人
he wasn't a great
但他能够保持在顶峰
but he was able to stay at the top
基于奉献精神，
based on dedication,
专业精神,
professionalism,
情报
intelligence
斯卡罗尼是教练组成员
Scaloni was on the coaching staff
在俄罗斯和对手
in Russia and the opponent
给他留下深刻印象的是
that left a big mark on him was
法国,
France,
谁击败了阿根廷?
who knocked Argentina
第二轮就出局了
out in the second round
当斯卡罗尼接手后，
When Scaloni takes over,
他是个十足的新手
he's an absolute rookie
马拉多纳说:
Diego Maradona said,
斯卡罗尼是个好人
Scaloni's a nice lad,
但他连指挥交通都不会
but he can't even direct traffic
他怎么会被派来管事
What's he doing being placed in charge
国家足球队的?我们都疯了吗?
of the national football team? Have we all gone mad?
快进四年，
Fast forward four years,
他开始组建球队
he starts building this team
36场比赛保持不败
that went 36 games unbeaten
就他的关系而言
In terms of his relationship
对于梅西来说，他们并没有太大的不同
with Messi, they're not that different
在年龄上，他们并没有太大的不同
in age and they're not that different
在教养
in upbringing
梅西来自罗萨里奥
Messi is from Rosario
斯卡罗尼有过这样的经历
and Scaloni had that experience
看到梅西
of seeing Messi
在阿根廷的更衣室里
in the Argentine dressing room
他们成为了合作伙伴
and they became a partnership
现在他们有了一个小组
Now they've got a group
Scaloneta诞生了
The Scaloneta is born
有一个神话
There's a mythology
围绕着这个团队
around this team
整个团队，
This team all together,
这支由梅西和他的弟子组成的球队
this team of Messi and his disciples
他们从小就崇拜梅西
that have grown up idolizing Messi
斯卡罗尼成功的关键
The key to Scaloni's success
是能够适应
is being able to adapt
他发现了这一点
And he found that out
对抗沙特阿拉伯
against Saudi Arabia
这是世界杯历史上最精彩的比赛之一
It's one of the World Cup all-time
冲击
shocks
而斯卡罗尼，他不得不重新考虑一下
And Scaloni, he's had to have a rethink
他是接地
He's grounded
他很接地气
He's down to earth
他在半决赛后的反应
His reaction after the semifinal
得分线使我们感到高兴
The score line flattered us
合法的儿子
A legitimate son of the
阿根廷的土壤
Argentinian soil
一点也不得意
Not carried away at all
停飞
Grounded
他干得真不错
Well, what a job he's done,
巴勃罗非凡的,真的
Pablo Extraordinary, really
我想马拉多纳知道
I think Diego Maradona knew
大多数关于足球的事情，他似乎已经得到了
most things about football, but he seems to have got
那个错了
that one wrong
在这次比赛中，他设法调整了一些事情
And he's managed to tweak things in this tournament
无论是在他的人事方面
both in terms of his personnel
还有他的阵型
and his formations as it's gone on
是的,当然不要害羞，
Yeah, absolutely Not being shy,
他做了很多改变
and he made a lot of changes
从一个游戏到另一个游戏
from one game to another game
这是真的
And that's true
我想当他接手的时候
I think when he took over,
过去有很多人抱怨
there were a lot of people who used to complain
说他缺乏经验
about his lack of experience
在俱乐部的层面上
at the club level and all that
你对阿根廷队有什么看法?
How is it going to do with the Argentinian team?
但我觉得他一直都很聪明
But I think he's been always really clever
被包围
by being surrounded by
还有前足球运动员
ex-football players as well
巴勃罗·伊马斯，塞缪尔，我们说过的
Pablo Imaas, Samuel, we spoke about
这对这群球员来说有多重要
how important it is for that group of players
这四个前足球运动员
to have those four ex-football
球员，每次他们说话的时候
players, that every time they talk
他们真的可以激励那些球员
they can really inspire those players
我认为当你是一名教练时
And I think when you are a coach
在国家队，你只需要
of the national team, all you need
选择合适的球员，
is picking the right players,
以梅西为中心组建一支球队
build a team around Messi
他做完了
and he's done
这就是他所做的这个团队
And that's what he's done And the team have
它是内置的他们100%投资，
built into it They're 100% invested,
真的吗?
really, aren't they?
尽他们所能
And giving everything that they can
给梅西一个施展才华的平台
to give Messi the platform to shine
绝对的然后是美洲杯，
Absolutely And then the One Cup America,
世界杯前的36场比赛，
36 games before the World Cup,
有些被击败，现在进入了世界杯决赛
some beaten and now in the World Cup final
但这是不可思议的
But that is incredible
我是说，每个球员
I mean, how every single player
阿根廷的总统一直在竞选
of Argentina have been running
两倍
twice as much
梅西
for Messi
他们一直在做艰苦的工作
They've all been doing the hard work
球的，
of the ball,
只是为了拿到球
just to get the ball
通过旋转球回来然后
by windball back and then
找到梅西的好位置
find Messi in good position
就像我之前说的
And like I said before
都是斯卡罗尼干的
that was all down to Scaloni
他建立了一个团队
that he's built a team
在和不在占有
in and out of possession
梅西
for Messi
这真是太棒了
It's been brilliant to see
看到这些我很自豪
and I'm so proud to see that
从所有的球员
from all the players
做这项工作是为了
doing this work for one of the
史上最伟大的球员
greatest players of all time
因为作为队友，你必须接受
Because you have to accept it as a team mate
就好像我要做所有的苦差事，
It's like I will do all the hard work,
肮脏的工作，随便你怎么称呼它
the dirty job, whatever you want to call it
那是因为我们知道我们有
It's because then we know that we have
这个数字10会产生
that number 10 that will produce
我们有这么大的动力
so much momentum for us
这将使情况有所不同
that will make the difference
我们到底看到了什么
what exactly we have seen in this
与阿根廷的比赛
tournament with Argentina
你只能这么做，玩家只会购买
You can only do that though and players only buy
当他们知道他们有一个天才的时候
into that when they know they've got a genius
如果这个人
If the person
他们这样做是为了牺牲
they're doing that for and sacrificing
他们自己的游戏部分
their own parts of their game for
不像他一贯那样高产
doesn't produce like he does consistently
他们闭上嘴说不
they shut down and say no
有很多相似之处
And so many similarities
真的有马拉多纳在
really with Maradona in
也是1986年
1986 as well
埃米·马丁内斯，Ria
Emi Martinez, Ria
我们先谈谈阿尔瓦雷斯
We'll talk about Alvarez first
因为他一直
Because he's been
在这次比赛中是一个真正的威胁
a real threat in this tournament
除了梅西
And alongside Messi
他们有某种合作关系
they've got some kind of partnership going
巴勃罗提到过
Pablo's mentioned the
就中场而言
midfield in terms of doing
公园中央的跑步
the run in the middle of the park
这两个的理解
The understanding that these two
而阿尔瓦雷斯却没有
have and bearing in mind Alvarez didn't
开始第一场比赛
start that first game
看看他是怎么描述自己的
Look what he does there in terms of himself
有两三个人盯着他
He's got two or three men on him
然后创造了那个空间
That then creates that space
对于梅西来说
for Messi there
我们知道你给不了他
which we know you can't give him
因为他的触感，技巧和完成度
because of the touch and the technique and the finish
他完全有能力
He's more than capable of
正如我所说的理解
The understanding as I said
他可能会失败然后他跑到后面
he can come short He then runs in behind
他一直在做什么
which he's been doing for the vast
大多数的
majority of the
比赛他过得很好
tournament He's having a great
他是锦标赛他的理解
tournament he is He's understanding
什么时候跑，怎么跑
of when and how to run
然后他得到了点球
He then gets the penalty
我们都知道
as we know
类似的事情又发生了梅西，发生了什么?
Similar thing again Messi what happens
他在来的路上了
he's on his way
好吧，只是一点点
And okay it's only a little
触摸，但在他体内和周围的是他
touch but it's him that's in and around him
只有他了解自己的比赛
It's him that understands his game
是他做了这么多
and it's him that's doing so much
因为我们已经看到了
of Messi's running because we've seen
梅西散步我是说这是个天才之作
Messi walking I mean this is the piece of genius
我们已经看过了
that we've watched
很多次了我们永远也得不到
so many times We'll never get
看腻了我的意思是
tired of watching it I mean
梅西从抛球中走出来
Messi gets out there from the throwing
但看看阿尔瓦雷斯
but just watch where Alvarez
是走了他知道去哪里吗
is going Where he knows where to go
因为他知道会发生什么
because he knows what's going to happen
他知道梅西有那么好他可以这么做
He knows Messi's that good He can do that
对任何防守球员来说，他可能已经做到了
to any defender and he's probably just done it
敬锦标赛的捍卫者什么是
to the defender of the tournament What a
他们一直是合作伙伴
partnership they've been
他就是那个
And he's the one that
如你所见
as you can see there
冲刺是他得到了那支球队
the sprints He's the one that gets that team
在公园的更远的地方，我很受伤
further up the park and hurting
团队和跑在他后面
teams and running him behind
他有一个fab他真的出现了
He's had a fab He's real emerged
作为一个成熟的人才
as a proven talent
我认为这就是阿尔瓦雷斯所说的关键点
And I think that's the key point of what Alvarez is saying there
他跑在后面防守者们
is that he runs in behind The defenders then
退后一步，创造了一个大空间
step backwards which creates that big space
让梅西在其中发挥作用你给某人
for Messi to operate in You give someone
喜欢他那种空间他是
like him that kind of space He's
就像我们在整个比赛中看到的那样
devastating as we've seen all through the tournament
在图片的另一端
At the other end of the picture
这是一个很好的故事那不是很久以前的事
it's quite a story It's not that long ago
是吗?他是
is it? He was
阿森纳的替补门将，他来了
reserve keeper for Arsenal and here he is
他赢得了美洲杯他一直是
He's won the Copa America He's been a
扑点球的超级明星，他是
superstar in saving penalties and he's
也很有个性我正要说
quite a character as well I was going to say
对我来说最突出的一点是
one of the things that stands out for me is
他的性格，你比我了解得多
he's character and you know more than me
巴勃罗，而是你看待对方的方式
Pablo but the way that you see the other
当他赚大钱时，球员们会去找他
players go to him when he makes big
时刻和他交流，甚至
moments and he communicates and even
我和那些经历过变革的人谈过
I've spoken to people that have been in the changing
跟我说走就走，他有点
with me and say off to pitch he's a bit
古怪的很多门将都是这样的
wacky A lot of goalkeepers are like that
但他做出了重大的扑救
but he's made big saves
在非常关键的时刻
at very critical moments
是的，绝对的，甚至在
Yeah absolutely and even in the
美洲杯
Copa America
我想是哥伦比亚队
against I think it was Colombia
他在跟
He was talking to
我会吃的，兄弟
I would eat bro
我没有说你可以的粉丝
There were no fans that I said you can
听到一切
hear everything
只是在播放
Just playing those
心理游戏，你知道的
mind games you know for the
前锋
striker
他在说什么?
What's he saying there?
我不能在电视上说
I cannot say on TV
即使在训练中
Even in training
当你做这些的时候
when you're doing those
小游戏，他
small side games and he's
总是和前锋说话
always talking to the striker
难以置信的性格
Unbelievable character
我为他感到高兴，因为他
I'm so pleased for him because he's been
等了这么久才拥有
waiting for so much time to have
这是他的时刻，他正在做
his moment and he's doing it
让我们从法国的角度来看
Let's get a French perspective
在游戏中凯利·萨默斯是
on the game Kelly Summers is with
前法国国家队
former France International and
联合国秘书长
Secretary General of the
法国足球联合会劳拉
French Football Federation Laura
乔治
Georges
劳拉·乔治当然知道
And Laura Georges certainly knows a
关于重大场合的一两件事
thing or two about big occasions for
法国有七大调
France playing in seven major
为她的国家参加比赛劳拉
tournaments for her country Laura
今晚是另一个重要的时刻
tonight is another huge occasion for
但是法国人是怎么回来的
the French but how are people back at
家给你的感觉来到这里
home for you feeling coming into this
游戏吗?法国有信心做到吗
game? Is there confidence France can
保留他们的奖杯?对不起，我不能
retain their trophy? Sorry I cannot
说
say
法国人有多自信?
How confident are the French feeling?
我们开始了比赛，这是
We started the tournament and it was
复杂我们失去了很多球员
complicated We lost so many players
在失去之后
after losing
我们就像我们的防守者
We were like our defenders
前锋
forwards
每个人都说，好吧，会的
Everybody was like okay it's going to be
一场复杂的竞争
a complicated competition but
然后从屏幕游戏开始
from the start then screen games
我们获得越来越多的信心
and we gained more and more confidence
今晚我们知道这将是一个艰难的过程
tonight We know it's going to be a tough
游戏我们知道我们的
game We know how good our
法官
judges are
我们知道这将是一场艰难的比赛
We know it's going to be a tough and
比赛很激烈，但我们很自信
aggressive game but we're confident
因为我们知道有这么多的快乐
because we know there's so much joy in
那些球员都很年轻
those players and they're so young
当我们看到他们玩耍的时候，我们会感到精神振奋
and refreshing when we see them play
所以我们很有信心，但我们知道
so we're confident but we know it's
会很复杂这不是一个好主意
going to be complicated It's not a good
时间是听不到音高的
time is it to not be able to hear pitch
在世界杯决赛中，迪迪埃是球队的一员
side at a World Cup final but didier
德尚，他应该得到多少荣誉
Deschamps how much credit does he deserve
感谢你让这支队伍来到这里?
for getting this team here?
作为一个幸运的人，我们知道这一点
We know that as a lucky guy
他赢得了一切作为一名球员
he's winning everything As a player
他赢得了世界杯，赢得了欧洲杯
he won the World Cup, he won the Euro
他是一位伟大的领袖
and he's been a great leader
在场上，在场外
on the field, outside the field
他赢得了一切
he's winning everything and
他和他的队友带来了什么
what he brought with his teammates as
这有点像一个球员
a player it was a little like
想要赢得一切他是
wanted to win everything He was
带领团队
leading the team
和每个球员交谈
talking to every player and
所以今天这就是他带来的
so today this is what he's bringing to
球员们喜欢自信和信任
the players like confidence, trust
还有很多的关心
and a lot of care
他希望他们能够实现
and he wants them to achieve
更好，更像
better and to be like
参与，真正参与
involved like really engage
每一个行动劳拉
every action Laura
非常感谢，祝你们今晚好运
thank you so much, the best of luck tonight
享受它现在加里给你一个想法
enjoy it Now Gary to give you an idea
这对法国来说有多重要
how bigger occasion this is for France
整个法国联邦都买了
the entire French Federation have bought
他们所有的员工都在这里
all of their employees out here
如果法国能做到，会是什么派对
will be some party if France can do it
今晚
tonight
哦的赌注
Oh bet
姆巴佩已经做到了
Kylian Mbappe already has
9个世界杯进球
nine World Cup goals to his name
如果他今天得分，他就会超车
if he scores today he'll overtake
盖德·穆勒成为最年轻的球员
Gerd Muller as the youngest player
达到两位数只是
to reach double figures Just
真的是法国选手赢得了这场比赛
really French player to have won the
以前的金靴他赢了
Golden Boot previously He won it
有13个，就像
with 13 and just like
梅西当然是他的队友
Messi his teammate of course
卡塔尔人拥有的巴黎圣日耳曼
at the Qatari owned Paris Saint-Germain
姆巴佩也被选中了
and Mbappe was marked out for
从小就成为明星
Stardom at an early age
基利安，巴黎土生土长的孩子
Kylian the Paris born and bred kid
在纽约北部郊区长大
grew up in the north suburbs of the
的国家我们家住的公寓
country The flat where the family
活生生地看着
lived was literally looking
如果你愿意，可以在当地体育场上空
over the local stadium if you want
他在当地的邦迪俱乐部工作
of the local club Bondi where he started
所以从很小的时候起，他就
so from a very young age he spent
他的周末你也知道
his weekends even you know
平日晚上也在附近
weekdays evenings as well there near
球场上总是铺着足球的冰
the pitch always with the football ice
费
fee
周围
Around
我觉得是8和
I would say eight and
九个人从巴黎出发
nine people around Paris starting
说这孩子是邦迪人吗
saying is this kid a Bondi who's
会很棒的每一场比赛
going to be amazing Every single game
他在那里打了五、六、七分
he played there was five six seven
各大俱乐部的球探
scouts from all the big clubs
在欧洲，他本可以离开的
in Europe he could have gone
不管怎样，他决定去
anyway and he decided to go to the
喷泉学院
Fountain Academy
然后他选择了摩纳哥
Then he chose Monaco
因为他觉得这是对的
because he felt that was the right
他成为职业球员的道路
path for him to become a professional player
17岁首次亮相
making his debut at 17
成为最年轻的球员
becoming the youngest player to
在摩纳哥一线队踢过球
ever play with the first team of Monaco
超越了亨利，然后成为
overtaking Thierry Henry then becoming
为摩纳哥进球的最年轻球员
the youngest player to score for Monaco
超过了亨利和我
overtaking Thierry Henry as well and I
我想这又给了他信心
think that again gave him the confidence
在那之后，他再也没有
to go further and after that he never
真的回头看了
really looked back
巴黎圣日耳曼已经签下了基利安
Paris Saint-Germain have signed Kylian
姆巴佩165亿美元
Mbappe for 165 million
来自摩纳哥的英镑
pounds from Monaco
我18岁时来到这里
I came here at 18 years I was
我很有才华，但我没有
talented but I was not
超级巨星，现在我是超级巨星
a superstar and now I'm a superstar
他想和最好的球员一起打球
He wants to play with the best players
一直都是，但另一方面
all the time but on the other hand
他也希望巴黎圣日耳曼是
he also wanted PSG to be
抢劫和俱乐部建设
heisting and the club to build
我猜他周围的一切
everything around him which I guess
当梅西到来的时候，一切都是关于
when Messi arrived it was all about
梅西
Messi
有一种神秘感
There was this kind of cryptic
在Instagram标签上的故事
story on Instagram hashtag
pivogame在巴黎
pivogame In Paris
他在前场独自踢球
he plays on his own upfront with
内马尔和梅西
Neymar and Messi kind of
在他身边玩耍，而他真的不喜欢
playing around him which he doesn't really
比如他想做什么
like what he would like to do
我有一个前锋
is have a striker
在单前锋的位置上，他是
in that lone striker role and he's
两个中有一个
one of the two that plays off that
前锋，在他后面打
striker, plays behind which is what happens
因为当他和吉鲁搭档的时候
with the national team because when he plays with Olivier Giroud
他经常和格列兹曼在一起
he's the one with Griezmann often
只是为了发挥它
to just play off that
前锋
striker
Mbappe !
Mbappe!
第一个在世界杯上进球的青少年
The first teenager to score in a World Cup
贝利之后的决赛
final since Pele
法国正在夺下王冠
France are running away with the crown
他有一个梦想
He had a dream to be
和贝利处于同一水平
at the same level as Pele
他假设了
and he assumed it
贝利似乎是
Pele who seemed to be
寻找我的继任者
looking for my successor
我想你可以看到
I think you can see with
他的那种表演
the kind of performances that he's given
在过去的四年甚至更长时间里
in the last four years and even more
他就是这样的人
complete for what he is
他热爱这项运动，你看出来了
He loves the game, you see it
他的动作，他的方式
on his movement, the way he's
用球，不错的动作
using the ball, a nice move
干得漂亮
a nice touch
基利安更成熟，更有经验
Kylian is more mature, he's more experienced
他已经长大了
he's grown into this
超级巨星的地位
superstar status
成为世界级的球员
into this world-class player status
当我在球场上
When I'm on the pitch
我知道我压力很大
I know I have a lot of pressure
我准备好了，我说好，没问题
I'm ready for that, I say okay, no problem
他只在乎数据，他想成为那个人
He's all about the stats, he wants to be the one
用大写字母写着他的名字
with his name written in big letters
就在最上面
right there at the top of
足球的世界
the world of football
我喜欢玩大游戏，这就是原因
I like playing big games, it's why
我住在我家，我12岁了
I live my home, I'm 12 years old
就为了玩这个游戏，现在
just for playing this game and now
我在这里
I'm here
他只是觉得我想要世界杯
He's just thinking I want this World Cup
我不在乎对手是谁
I don't care who I play against
我想要另一个复制品奖杯
I want that other replica trophy
在我巴黎的房子里
in my house in Paris
真是个了不起的年轻人
Truly remarkable young man really
他恐吓阿根廷
he terrorized Argentina
四年前，我怀疑他是否能做到
four years ago, I wonder if he can do it
一样的，如果他这么做，他会
the same and if he does he'll
有两枚世界杯冠军奖牌
have two World Cup winners medals
23岁时，他的生日快到了
by the age of 23, his birthday is coming up
当然是在周二
on Tuesday, of course
那将是一份多么好的礼物啊
what a present that would be
多么了不起的球员啊，听着
What a player, listening to that
PSG支付
PSG paid
165亿英镑
£165 million from
知道在23-24岁的时候
knowing that at the age of 23-24
只要他们愿意，很容易做到
they could easily, if they wanted to
从中赚取巨大利润
make a huge profit on that
这是不可思议的，一个球员是什么
It's incredible, what a player is
我想
I suppose
有时候最大的力量
sometimes the biggest strength
一个团队和一个球员
of a team and a player
也可能是
can also possibly be
他们的弱点也是如此
their weakness as well
对后面的空间进行了开发
and there's been an exploitation of the space behind
这已经成为本届世界杯的一个主题
it's just become a theme of this World Cup
我们已经重点介绍了一些游戏
It has, a couple of games we've highlighted
这里有很大的空间
this but there's a big space
在赫尔南德斯左后卫附近
around Hernandez in the left back area
因为他和姆巴佩之间的距离
because the space between him and Mbappe
大到他回不去了吗
is so big he doesn't get back
他们承认，他根本不会回来
at all, he doesn't come back, they concede
在这个游戏中，这里
in this game, here again
你会想如果他是左后卫你会对他大吼大叫
you'd like to think if he was the left back you'd be screaming at him
只是为了回到那里
just to get back in there
不要轻易让球进
and don't allow the ball easy
穿过线
through the lines
他不做任何辩护
he doesn't do any defending
我想是8%我们一会儿会看图表
I think it's 8% we'll see a graphic in a minute
8%的时间
8% of the time
在所有这些接触中
of all of these touches have been
在他自己的半场
in his own half
这很疯狂，它向你展示了这一点
so it's crazy, so it shows you that
他没有辩护的意志
he's got no will to defend
但他没能再进去
but he doesn't get back in there
我说如果我在中场
and I said if I'm in midfielder
我会说拉比奥或者别的什么人
I'll be saying that Rabbeo or someone
快回去，别再这么容易晕过去了
get back in there and stop these easy passes out
因为我们把队伍挪到一边去了
because we're shuffling teams down one side
但他们总是知道自己能逃出去
but they always know they can get out
那边的球队很可爱
that side there and teams are cute
摩洛哥，他们也加入了
Morocco, they were getting in that
区域不断通过游戏
area constantly through that game
他们在惩罚
and they were punishing
埃尔南德斯
Hernandez
他们侥幸逃脱了惩罚
they got away with it
我们刚才说的状态
the stat we were talking about there
这太疯狂了，难以置信
it's crazy, it's unbelievable
不过他在下半场的触球还是相当不错的
his touches in the other half are quite good though
你可能会侥幸逃脱
you probably get away with it
我想你会接受的
I think you accept that
如果他给出了他现在的输出
if he gives you the output he's doing now
要助攻5个进球，这家伙想要决定重大比赛
5 goals to assist, and this guy wants to decide big games
当然，如果你在后面防守的话
absolutely, if you were defending behind
你是右后卫
you were a right back
如果你在一个球员后面防守，就像这样
if you were defending behind a player that's like that
不回来了，你会担心吗?
not coming back, would that concern you?
这对后卫来说是个问题
that's a problem for a fullback
通常边锋应该是这样的
normally winger is supposed to
一起来帮忙
double up and help
防守边后卫
fullbacks in defence
当你没有的时候
when you don't have
像这样的球员的帮助
help from a player like
我们已经看到Barbejo不会回溯
we have seen Barbejo doesn't track back
这可能是个问题
it could be a problem
即使在今天，DiMaria
even today DiMaria
对一个
against one
绝对
absolutely
我认为这是法语的弱点
I think that's the weak side of French
当然，他会带来改变
but of course then he makes the difference
展望未来，他是一个真正的威胁
going forward, he's a real threat
我不确定莫利纳
I'm not sure that Molina
而不是今天往前走，我们会想
rather than going forward today we'd be thinking
我不能不放过这个人
I can't not leave this man alone
因为那样的话问题就大了
because then it would be a huge problem
本届世界杯的另一位巨星
another of the big stars of this World Cup
也是世界杯的明星之一
was also one of the stars of the World Cup
四年前，安东尼·格列兹曼
four years ago Antoine Griezmann
是谁重塑了自己
who's reinvented himself
还是埃迪·钱珀重塑了他
or did Eddie Champer's reinvented him
作为一名中场控球球员
as kind of almost a holding midfield player
和创造者
and creator
并为此获得了极大的赞誉
and deserves great credit for that
感谢他接受了这件事
both him for accepting that
还有经理看了他一眼
and the manager for looking at him
在中场，因为球员
in midfield because of the players
他们已经丢失了
that they've had missing
我们提到博格巴，我们提到坎特
we mentioned Pogba, we mentioned Cante
也
and also
他所做的防守工作
the work that he does defensively
但别忘了他创造了
but don't forget that he has created
本届锦标赛有21次机会
21 chances in this tournament
哪个比谁都多
which is more than anyone
本届世界杯
at this World Cup
但我认为这是他最好的作品
but I think that his best work
法国人去过那里吗
has actually been there when France
一直处于压力之下
have been under pressure
经常发现自我的是他
it's him that has often found himself
在这些位置上
in these positions
你看到的是最后一个人
you're looking at the last man
在辩护中
in defence there
他澄清的次数
the number of times he's cleared it up
他阅读比赛的次数
the number of times he's reading of the game
并且能够发现问题
and being able to sniff out problems
像这样
like that
如果他不在那里，那球就直飞
if he's not there then that ball goes straight
一个摩洛哥球员
to a Moroccan player
它在网的后面
and it's in the back of the net
所以在防守端他绝对做到了
so defensively he's been absolutely
伟大的，并提供了他的团队
magnificent and offered his team
那么多，那么多
so so much which then gives
正如我们所说的远期交易平台
as we've said the platform for the forwards
给吉鲁和巴约珥
for Giroud and Bapé
如果不是梅西
if it wasn't for Messi
然后是巴普莱
and then Bapé
他肯定在上面
he I'm sure would be up there
他让你吃惊了吗
has he surprised you in the way
他已经适应了那种角色
he's adapted to that kind of role
防守端也是如此
defensively as well
我现在对他更尊敬了
I've got even more respect for him now
这是一个世界级的中锋
this was a world class centre forward
他现在几乎是在防守
he's now playing in almost a defensive
中场位置
midfielder position
你必须有游戏智慧
and you have to have game intelligence
在游戏智能中能够做到这一点
in game intelligence to be able to do that
在这个层次上执行
and execute at this level
在另一边也很有成效
and be so productive on the other side
对我来说，这是非凡的
for me it's phenomenal
它只是证明了它有多简单
it just proves how much easier it is
来捍卫国家联盟
to defend the National League
让我们去看看凯利·萨默斯
let's go pitchside where Kelly Summers
和亚历克斯·斯科特一起沉浸在气氛中
is soaking up the atmosphere with Alex Scott
这里的大气是怎样的
and what an atmosphere it is down here
球场边，加里，这里有法国球迷
pitchside Gary there is French fans in here
但是有很多阿根廷球迷
but there is a lot of Argentinian fans
亚历克斯，我们看过很多这样的比赛
Alex we've been at so many of these games
但这里的气氛很特别，不是吗
pitchside but this atmosphere is special isn't it
真是不可思议
it really is incredible
其实我是来参加半决赛的
I was here actually for the semi-final
休息一天，我在看比赛
day off and I was watching the game
这是我第一次经历
and it's the first time I'd experienced
阿根廷球迷
the Argentinian fans
和凯莉，这太不可思议了
and Kelly it was incredible
他们太吵了，但在这里真的很好
they were so loud but it's nice actually being here
我们就在法国球迷的旁边
we're right next to the French fans as well
所以我们得到了它的两边
so we're getting both sides of it
但这里的气氛令人难以置信
but it's an incredible atmosphere
我们刚刚听到了球员的名字
we just heard the names of the players
当时宣读了姆巴佩和梅西的名字
when Mbappe and Messi's names were read out
可以理解，他们得到了最大的芯片
understandably they got the largest chip
就像人们关注的焦点一样
as much as the focus has been on them
今晚的捍卫者
the defenders tonight
他们需要在上面，不是吗
they're going to need to be on it aren't they
我们的工作室非常平衡
our studio is very balanced
显然加里和阿兰都是前锋
obviously Gary and Alan are strikers
然后是防守队员里奥和巴勃罗
and then the defenders with Rio and Pablo
我也这么认为
I just think as well
很明显，这将是一个巨大的防御
obviously defensive it's going to be huge
我们知道梅西和姆巴佩的魔力
we know the magic of Messi and Mbappe
但我觉得应该去掉感情因素
but I think take the emotion out of it
防守端是1v1的战斗
defensively it's about those 1v1 battles
防守者真的
and the defenders really
做好他们的工作
stepping up and doing their jobs
试图阻止那魔法
to try and stop that magic
但我们知道当你看法国队的时候
but we know when you look at the French team
你去阻止姆巴佩
you try and stop Mbappe
他们一直在讨论这件事
the guys have been talking about it
还有他们参加过的比赛
and the games that they've been in
但对我来说，这是关于1v1的战斗
but for me it's about those 1v1 battles
不带感情
taking the emotion out of it
我只是在做今天的工作
and just doing the job today
在这里感觉很特别，不是吗
it does feel special doesn't it down here
有很多人穿着梅西的球衣
there's so many people in Messi shirts
我们离这里只有20分钟的路程，真是太幸运了
what a privilege we're around 20 minutes away
从世界杯决赛开球开始
from kickoff in a World Cup final
可能是梅西的最后一次
potentially Messi's last
在这里感觉很特别，不是吗
it does feel special down here doesn't it
就像我那天来的时候说的
like I said when I was here the other day
每次梅西拿球的时候
every time Messi was on the ball
我忍不住鼓掌
I couldn't help but just clap
它只是不断地产生
it was just producing moments after moments
在今天的决赛现场
down here at the final today
看着他玩耍
and watching him play
我要好好享受每一刻
I'm going to take every moment in
感觉很特别，就像我说的
it does feel special and as I said
还有20多分钟
with over 20 minutes to go
这种气氛只会越来越好
this atmosphere is only going to get better
我想我们会喜欢这个的
I think we might enjoy this one
他就在那儿
absolutely there he is
他本人
the man himself
1003年奥运会
1,003 games
总共791个进球
791 goals in total
阿根廷国家队出场171次
171 caps for Argentina
96个进球
and 96 goals
今晚和佩尔佩尔齐平
tonight with moving level with Pelé
12日在世界杯上
on 12 at World Cups
关于史上最伟大球员的争论
the debate about the greatest player of all time
当然会继续
will continue of course
但对我来说，他在那里
but for me he's up there
在前1名
in the top 1
我很好胜
I'm very competitive
我真的很想赢得一切
I really want to win it all
好朋友，亲切
good friend, cordial
合作伙伴
partner
我具备所有这些品质
I had all those qualities
我找他的时候
when I was looking for him
我感到一阵持续的打击
I felt a continuous hit
从一个球对着墙
from a ball against a wall
他拿着球出来了
and he came out with the ball
在他腋下
under his arm
我要去打球
I was going to play the ball
总是这样
it always happened
1003年奥运会
1,003 games
这是一项一般性意见
it was a general comment
来自邻居
from the neighborhood
给那个说
to that boy who said
他将成为未来的马拉多纳
he was going to be the future Maradona
比赛中最好的选手
the best player of the game
你是我们选中的
you were chosen by us
第二个，我们看看
the second one, let's see
告诉我
tell me
你想把这个冠军献给谁?
who do you want to dedicate this championship to?
敬我的父亲，我的叔叔
to my father, my uncle
还有我所有的家人
and to all my family
作为球员，你的偶像是什么?
what is your idol as a player?
马拉多纳
Maradona
马拉多纳的东西
things from Maradona
荒谬,well-dominated
absurd, well-dominated
听着，我告诉你
look, I'll tell you
你想邀请他吗?
do you want to invite him?
没有
no
把它弄进去
working it in
德国
Germany
是世界冠军吗
are champions of the world
不久之后
shortly afterwards
情绪变了
the mood changed
天气很冷
it was cold
你不能和马拉多纳相比
you can't compare it with Maradona
有一种特别的需求
there was this extraordinary demand
从
from
阿根廷
Argentina
那是因为他的表演太精彩了
that because he performed so fantastically
和巴塞罗那
with Barcelona
他不知怎么的
he somehow
决定不表演了
had decided not to perform
和阿根廷关系很好
that well with Argentina
美洲杯是南美洲的欧元
the Copa America is the euros of South America
进入决赛是非常困难的
to get to the final is very hard
没有简单的游戏
there's no easy games
所以在2015年
so in 2015
阿根廷队在决赛中对阵智利队
Argentina played Chile in the final
在点球大战中0- 3落败
3-0-0 lost on penalties
2016年也发生了同样的事情
same thing happened in 2016
在美国，是百年美洲杯
in the US, in the Copa America Centenario
谁罚丢点球很麻烦
it's messy who misses the penalty
3 - 0
3-0
那是一个非常艰难的时刻
it was a very difficult moment
对我们来说
for us
这是第三次决赛
that was the third final
我们连输了
that we lost in a row
所以我们非常非常难过
so we were very, very sad
它来了
here it comes
一切都结束了
it's over
没有人离开了
there's no one left
但
but
没有人离开了
there's no one left
我希望
I wish
没有标题
there was no title
和团队在一起
with the team
这是非常悲伤的
it was very sad
很惊讶
very surprised
因为
because
我们的队长
our captain
我们的领袖
our leader
要离开球队吗
was going to leave the team
这非常困难
it was very difficult
最终
eventually
整个
the entire
足球协会
football association
重建本身
rebuilt itself
雇佣经理来确保
hired managers that would make sure
他很舒服
he was comfortable
他回来了
and he returned
等待结束了
the wait is over
这是梅西的时刻
this is Leonel Messi's moment
阿根廷
Argentina
2021年
are the 2021
美洲杯冠军
Copa America champions
我见过他
I met him
他非常情绪化
he was very emotional
很好
very nice
知道我们所经历的
knowing what we had experienced
我们的谈话
the talks we had had
他觉得他需要它
he felt that he needed it
这是一个伟大的成就
and it was a great achievement
我为他感到高兴
and well, I'm happy for him
对我们所有人来说
and for all of us
他赢得了一切
he won everything
金球奖冠军联赛
Ballon d'Or Champions League
他拿着那个杯子就像他是孩子一样
he had that cup like he was the baby
他把所有的奖杯都放在一边
he left all the trophies aside
为了赢得这场比赛
to win this one
最后他为他们演奏了好几次
he ended up playing for them quite a few times
你永远无法确定
you can never be sure
当你看到有天赋的年轻球员时，你能吗
can you when you see talented young players
接受
accept
对于被选中的少数人
for a chosen few
当然，这太感人了
absolutely, it's just so emotional
我的意思是
I mean
我想对梅西说的是
what I would say to Messi is
享受今晚吧
just enjoy it tonight
无论发生了什么
whatever happened
谢谢你，梅西，是你成就了我的人生
thank you Messi for making my life
更神奇的是他的足球
more amazing with his football
一直都是
it's always been
和梅西并肩作战是我的荣幸
a pleasure to play alongside Messi
祝他好运
and good luck to him
今晚去阿根廷
and to Argentina tonight
引用迪迪埃·德·尚的话
sort of quote from Didier de Chant
实际上是一些法国人
saying actually some French people
我想看到梅西赢得世界杯
want to see Messi win the World Cup
这很不寻常，不是吗
which is extraordinary isn't it
他进的那些球
the goals that he scored
我们在找助攻
we're talking to the assists
但也有一些小事
but it's also the tiny things
当他从空间里爬出来的时候
when he wriggles out of spaces
它会从我们的座位上掉下来
that gets up off our seats
我非常喜欢这些细节
it's those details that I've really enjoyed
我们都可以看看目标
we can all look at the goals
我们会年复一年地观察它们
and we'll look at them for years and years
但这些事情有时
but these are the things that sometimes
不在亮点规则上
aren't on the highlights rules
小扫描
the little scans
扫身是他比赛中非常重要的一部分
the scanning is such an important part of his game
而是控球的能力
but the ability to control the ball
就像那样被包裹在他身上
that's wrapped into him like that
世界上其他球员都输掉了那个球
every other player in the world is losing that ball
控球出现了失误
there's a turnover in possession
但这是他的触觉，他的意识
but it's his touch, he's awareness
他再次扫描了球场
he scans the pitch again there
调查对手和队友的位置
surveying where the opponents and where teammates are
但这是第一次接触
but then it's the first touch
这是思维的速度
it's the speed of thought
这就是他与众不同的地方
that separates him from the others
他有能力看到别人的进攻并把他逼死
the ability to see people coming and closing him down
在这么短的时间内
in that short window of time
再次扫描
again scanning there
我们稍后会讲到他为什么在那里扫描
we'll come back to why he's scanning there later
再看一次，这是一次扫描
look again there's one scan
他又扫描了两三次
he's scanning again two or three times again there
四次
four times
只是接收而已
just receiving it
六次之后他才接球
six times before he's receiving the ball there
这就是区别
that's the difference
优秀的玩家会浏览一两次
the good players scan once or twice
他很擅长这个，但是他之前扫描过
the greats at this but again he's scanned earlier
因为这个原因
in this for that reason there
玩弄记忆
playing off memory
他所做的是非凡的，我们已经看到了
it's phenomenal what he does and we've seen this
我可以一直看下去
I could watch this this bit forever
就像艾尔之前说的
off the throw in there and like Al said earlier
对手可能是锦标赛的捍卫者之一
that's against probably one of the defenders of the tournaments
你会说比他强
stronger than him you would say
这是诡计
it's the guile
诡计，然后是能力
the trickery and then the ability to
有决断力
have the decisiveness
对队友位置的理解
the understanding of where teammates are
最后一个球是不同的
and that final ball is just different
他花很多时间走路
he spends a lot of time walking
但是通过扫描
but doing that scanning
如果你能生产的话，你可以那样走路
you can walk like that if you can produce
他将要做的事情
the moments that he's going to do
他那样走是因为他在调查
he's walking like that because he's surveying
他正在球场周围看一看
the pitch he's having a look around
他在哪儿，他想干什么
where's he, what's he trying to do
他为什么要盯着我
why is he going to mark me
如果有人有资格，那就是他
if anyone's entitled to he is
就像下棋一样
it's like a game of chess
他很害羞，但这些天他是个领袖
he's being pretty shy but he's a leader these days
他在35岁时打满了每一分钟
he's played every minute at 35
我们有他的团队谈话
and we've got his team talk
从美洲杯决赛
from the Copa America Final
看一看
have a look
45天没见家人
45 days without seeing our family
45天
45 days
他说了什么?他说他是一个父亲
what did he say? he said he was a father
他是一个父亲，他不能见他的女儿
he was a father and he couldn't see his daughter
他做不到
he couldn't do it
他看了他一会儿
he saw him for a little while
有一段时间
for a little while
因为我们有一个目标
because we had a goal
我们有一个目标，但我们还差一步
we had a goal and we're a step away
走开一步，你就知道了
a step away and you know
一切都取决于我们
that it's all up to us
赢得杯是我们的责任
it's up to us to win the Copa
这就是我们要出去的原因
so that's why we're going to go out
我们去拿杯咖啡
we're going to get that Copa
在阿根廷与我们的家人作战
Argentina to fight against our families
我们的朋友，那些经常去阿根廷的人
our friends, the people who always go to Argentina
最后一个带这个的
the last ones with this
你不需要赢的机会
you don't need the chance of winning
本届杯赛必须在阿根廷举行
this Copa had to play in Argentina
他把她带到这里来了
and he brought her here
他把她带到这里，这样我们就能
he brought her here so that we could
让她给她做标记
get her to mark her
这样我们才能自信和冷静
so that we can be confident and calm
她要带她回家
that she's going to take her home
良好的团队谈话
good team talk
今天起作用了
it worked today
我能看到他们走出去
I could see as they're walking out
拿着漂亮的金杯
with that beautiful gold trophy
最受追捧的
the most sought after
在足球
in football
谁要把它带回家
who is going to take it home
巴勃罗，你愿意吗?
Pablo, will you do it?
我的预测，我希望如此
my prediction, I hope so
但这是迷信
but it's superstition
比赛前
before the games
我有信心
I'm confident
你觉得梅西今天会打开它吗?
do you think Messi will turn it on today?
是的，是的
I do, yeah
我想这已经写在星星上了
I think it's written in the stars
我真的希望明星能赢
for the star to win, I really do
我想他的名字会传遍整个比赛
I think his name will be all over this game
艾米纳姆，准备参加他们的世界杯
Eminem, set for their World Cup
最后的弓
final bow
世界杯
the World Cup
好了，我们快到了
well we're close now
到2022年
to the 2022
世界杯决赛
World Cup final
一点烟火
bit of fireworks
在体育场中央爆炸
going off in the middle of the stadium
希望会有一些烟花燃放
hopefully there will be some fireworks going off
当这两支球队在球场上比赛时
on the pitch when these two teams play
有这两位伟大的球员
with these two great players
这是值得期待的事情
it's something to look forward to
有两个伟大的国家在争斗
there's two great nations going at it
在这场比赛中有很多历史
a lot of history in this competition
但对我来说，次要情节对我来说有点
but for me, the subplots are a bit for me
我都等不及了
that I'm here for, I can't wait
会是换岗吗
is it going to be the change of the guard
从梅西手中接过火炬
passing over Torch from Messi
让那一代人和巴佩来接手
and that generation and Bapay to take over
还是说这将是一场非常艰难的比赛
or is this going to be the very tough finish
像梅西这样的人
for someone like Messi
这是最后一支舞吗?
could it be the last dance?
当然，这是梅西最后的机会
absolutely, last chance for Messi
当然，你必须享受它
of course, you have to enjoy it
我之前说过
as I said before
有了梅西，我们一直是一支伟大的球队
we've always been a great team with Messi
我想所有阿根廷人都知道这一点
I think all Argentinians know that
所以希望他们会有一场精彩的表演
so hopefully they'll be doing a great performance
享受一个美好的夜晚
and enjoy a good night
你觉得这样很好
you think this would be good
对国家也是如此
for the country as well
超越体育
beyond sport
我们的国家正处于危机之中
we're a country where we're all in crisis
你知道，金融危机
you know, financial crisis
人们只会忘记一晚上
and people will forget just for a night
问题的意义
meaning about the problem
就为了看这场比赛
just to watch this game
希望这群球员
and hopefully this group of players
能带来这么大的成功吗
can bring so much success
祝我们的国家和世界人民快乐
and joy to our country and our world people
令人难以置信的图片
fabulous pictures
艾伦，就在两队之前
Alan, just before the two teams
出来
come out
你怎么看?
how do you see it going?
我想会的
I think it'll be
我觉得不是很紧
very tight, I don't think
法国会介意阿根廷拥有
France will mind Argentina having
球，我希望他们能击中他们
the ball and I hope that they can hit them
休息的时候，我们真的讨论过
on the break, we've really talked about
我们从巴佩那里知道的速度
the pace that we know that from Bapay's
知道了，他们就会这么玩
got and that's how they'll want to play
我知道他们会想要画十字架
I know they'll want to get crosses in
因为吉鲁和格里兹曼会这么做
for Giroux and Griezmann will do that
他必须在防守端尽自己的一份力
and he'll have to do his bit defensively
你确实在比赛开始时给了他们小费
you did tip them at the start of the tournament
艾伦，我得给你点赞
Alan, I'll give you credit for that
如果他们赢了，我会称赞你的
I'll give you credit if they win
所以假设你不会改变
so presumably you're not going to change
不，我坚持吃
no, I'm sticking with them
和那个家伙在一起
with that guy there
我想他的时代到了
I think it's his time
这将是一个怎样的职业，怎样的道路
what a career and what a way it would be
为他结束了国际水平
for him to end the international level
里约，你在比赛开始前选择了法国
Rio, you picked France before the start of the tournament
所以我假设你会坚持下去
so I'm just presuming you're sticking
和他在一起
with him
巴勃罗，现在描述一下你的情绪
Pablo, describe your emotions now
来吧，我们去阿根廷
come on, let's go Argentina
让我们去
let's go
这是世界杯决赛
it's the World Cup final
法国对阿根廷
France against Argentina
你的评论员是杰梅因·格纳斯
your commentators are Jermaine Genus
和盖伊·莫里
and Guy Mowry
谢谢你，加里，大家下午好
thank you Gary and good afternoon everyone
2022年，这些是球队
2022 and these are the teams
第22届世界杯
for the 22nd World Cup
最后
final
进入大陆
and into continental
冲突，一场智慧的较量
clash, a battle of wits
意志，技巧和风格
and will, skills and styles
团队和个人
teams and individuals
以及这一切的美好
and the beauty of it all
是不是有很多故事可以讲
is that there are many stories that could be told
但我们不知道是哪一个
but we don't know which one
将被书写
will be written
很少有人能走这条路
few get to walk this path
更少，得到多于一个
fewer still, get more than one
为比赛中最伟大的荣誉而努力
shot at the greatest glory the game has to give
但对于法国队的六名球员来说
yet for six of the French squad
有机会把他们的名字加到名单上
there's the chance to add their names to the list
12个人中，只有12个人
of 12, only 12 men
谁打过两场
who've played in two
世界杯决赛胜利
World Cup final wins
首先
and for one
在阿根廷阵营
in the Argentina camp
这是第二次也是最后一次机会
this is the second and last chance
为了增加荣耀
to add that glory
无可置疑的伟大
to undoubted greatness
要完成这个集合
to complete the set
结束足球
to finish football
在戏剧之前
before the drama
开始发展
starts to develop
这种情况已经持续了一段时间
and it already has been doing for some time
主要归功于
thanks to mainly
阿根廷的支持
the Argentina support
在人群中
in the crowd
我们将站着观察
we will stand to observe
国歌
the national anthems
这有时会
which can sometimes
热血沸腾
stir the blood
就像火柴本身一样
just as much as the match itself
请
please
如果可以，请保持站立
please remain standing if able
为了国歌
for the national anthem
法国的
of France
国歌
the national anthem
胜利
victory
即使寡不敌众
even with heavily outnumbered
Le马赛
Le Marseille
还是冰球吗?
are still pucks
熟悉的人物
familiar figures
所有人
one and all
它们已经成为固定装置
they've become fixtures
在我们所有人的生活中
in all of our lives
在过去的一个月中
over the last month
让我们最后检查一下
let's take one last check
在之前的阵容上
on the line-ups before
行动开始了
the action begins
阿根廷队守门员
for Argentina, goalkeeper
埃米·马丁内斯成为第一个
Emi Martinez becomes the first
阿斯顿维拉球员在世界杯决赛中的表现
Aston Villa player in a World Cup final
还是4
with a 4 again
和尼古拉斯的关系没有改变
an unchanged one with Nicolas
奥塔门迪代表他的国家
Otamendi representing his country
我说了一百遍了
for the 100th time
安格尔·德·玛丽亚被认为足够健康
Angle de Maria is deemed fit enough
回到可能开始的地方
to return to start in what is likely
这是他的国际告别
to be his international farewell
而布莱顿的亚历克西斯
Whilst for Brighton's Alexis
麦卡利斯特，还有更多的事情要做
McAllister there's much more to come
23岁的他已经是最好的球员之一了
he has at 23 been one of the best
比赛中的年轻球员
young players at the tournament
朱利安也是如此
and the same can be said for Julian
曼城的阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez of Manchester City
谁只进了四个球
whose four goals have only been
作为足球裁判的荣誉
the honour of refereeing football's
最盛大的场合是
biggest occasion goes to
西蒙Marciniak
Simon Marciniak
前波兰顶级选手
a former top level player in Poland
所以，也许我们可以从中吸取教训
so perhaps there's a lesson there
对于专业人士来说，靴子就不一定了
for professionals the boots don't necessarily
必须完全挂掉吗
have to be hung up completely
还有他的同胞
and his compatriot
托马斯Kwiatkowski
Thomas Kwiatkowski
负责…
is in charge of
VAR室
the VAR room
法国队队长
France captain
雨果·卢尔德站在历史的边缘
Hugo Lourdes stands on the brink of history
没有哪位球员曾两次领跑世界杯
no player has led two World Cup
最终获胜队伍
final winning teams
拉法·瓦兰和达约·阿波卡诺
Rafa Varan and Dayo Abomacano
两人都从营地的病毒中恢复了吗
have both recovered from the virus in the camp
后者返回开始的地方
the latter returning to start in place of
利物浦的易卜拉欣·奥卡纳特
Liverpool's Ibrahim Okanate
回到他的阿德里安·拉比奥
back to his Adrian Rabio
取代法法纳出任中场
replacing Yusuf Fafana in midfield
安托万·格列兹曼在哪里有了新发现
where Antoine Griezmann has been a revelation
作为目标创造者
as the goal maker
然后是进球者
and then goal scorers
奥利维亚·吉鲁和基利安·姆巴佩
Olivia Giroux and Kylian Mbappe
还有两天就是他的24岁生日了
his 24th birthday in two days
时间
time
他可能赢得了两届世界杯
he may have won two World Cups
在它到来之前
before it's here
杰梅因属
Jermaine Genus
就在我身边
is alongside me
我认识杰梅因
and I know Jermaine
你被噪音吹走了
you have been blown away by the noise
尤其是在我们的左边
particularly from away to our left
那些阿根廷球迷
those Argentina fans have been
不朽的
monumental
真是太荣幸了
well what an absolute pleasure
今晚就在这里
it is to be here this evening
你是对的，那些阿根廷球迷
and you right guy those Argentinian fans
哇，好吵
wow what a noise
绝对的
absolutely sensational
但法国的反应并不坏，不是吗
but the French response wasn't bad was it
还有很多
and there's so much
让我们期待今晚在球场上的比赛
for us to look forward to on this pitch tonight
展示了这么多才华
so much talent on display
只是现在已经等不及了
just can't wait for it to get going now
熟悉的
the familiar
开球倒计时
countdown to kickoff
只是这一次
only this time
12月18日在沙漠里
on the 18th of December in the desert
这是最后的倒计时
it is the final countdown
我们走吧
away we go
阿根廷希望赢得世界杯
Argentina looking to win the World Cup
南美洲
for South America
自从
for the first time since
法国是否已经竞标进一步建设
has France bid to further build
欧洲和他们自己的统治地位
European and their own dominance
他们保留了
and they retain
他们举起的奖杯
the trophy that they lifted
四年半前在俄罗斯
in Russia four and a half years ago
罗德里戈·德·保罗
Rodrigo de Paul
谁是第一个提出异议的
is the first to take issue
带着一个铲球
with a tackle
以后还会有更多这样的事情发生
there'll be plenty more of those to come
我认为有一件事可以直接看阿根廷
I think one thing straight away to look at with Argentina
很多人认为
a lot of people thought
我们的阵型更像是4-4-2
there was going to set up in more of a 4-4-2
迪玛利亚阵型
formation with Di Maria
在右手边，但看起来他要
on this right hand side but it looks like he's going to be
在上面，作为三的一部分
up top as part of a three
阿尔瓦雷斯和梅西
with Alvarez and Messi
在左边
on the left
金色的勇敢
Golden Brave
似乎就是这样
seems to be the way
来自莱昂内尔·斯科洛尼
from Leonel Scoloni for this one
几乎可以肯定是吗
is almost sure to be
的本质
an essence of
在早期阶段互相试探
feeling each other out in the early stages
在演播室里讨论过吗
has been talked about in the studio
梅西和他的表现
Messi and what he does
或者是他没有做的事
or maybe what he doesn't do
随着游戏的成型
as the game takes shape
看,等待
watching, waiting
准备好了吗?
ready to make it
就像账单上写的那样
as it's been billed
他时刻
his moment
马西尼亚克对德保罗很生气
Marciniac has angry words for de Paul
裁判显然觉得有
referee clearly feels there was
复仇的元素
an element of revenge
在对拉比亚的推动中
in that push on Rabia
他就像那个德·保罗
he's like that de Paul
勇于挑战
aggressive in the challenge
裁判不喜欢这样
referee didn't like it
或者现在还在和他说话
or still talking to him now
让他冷静下来
telling him to calm down
巨大的吼声
a huge roar
祝贺阿米尔为阿根廷队投球
greets Amir throwing for Argentina
梅西持球
Messi on the ball
德·玛丽亚在看
De Maria having a look
在交付之前
before delivering
这是德·保罗
there's de Paul
再一次来自梅西
and again from Messi
他试着把阿尔瓦雷斯抬起来
he tried the little lift in for Alvarez
谁越位了?
who was offside
但是他做了
but he made
Hugo Larisse第一次登记
Hugo Larisse register his first
这是晚上的工作
bit of work for the night
他越位了，但是
he was offside but
这里有一些关于
a couple of little insights there as to
梅西给了你什么
what Messi gives you
在游戏的早期
early on in this game
那里有很多空间
there's a lot of space there
特别是在up和之间
in particular between up and
梅尔卡多和
Mercado and
在左边
on this left hand side
埃尔南德斯必须这么做
Hernandez are going to have to
认真考虑一下谁去
have a real think about who goes
去对付他
in there to deal with him
这一举动遭到了
a move that was met by an
经理赞许地点点头
approving nod from the manager
裁判很不高兴
the referee is unhappy with
马上去梅尔卡多
up and Mercado straight away
超过了梅西
over the top of Messi
别介意我
don't mind me some
让梅尔卡多告诉他你在那里
up and Mercado let him know you're there
他只是借给了他一点
he has just lent on him a little
有点太过分了
bit too much
我不认为这是真的
the shots I don't think was
对那个任意球很满意
happy with the free kick
被给予
being given
只有三支球队赢得过世界杯
only three have won the World Cup
作为球员
as players
和经理
and manager
他是其中之一
he's one of them
还有弗恩斯·贝肯鲍尔
along with Ferns Beckenbauer
和马里奥
and Mario
Zagalo
Ramira
最后迪玛利亚
finally Di Maria
精细的控制
exquisite bit of control
Macalester
玛丽亚（女名）
Maria
被二人组拦住
stopped by a duo
Kunde
和Dembele
and Dembele
Mbappe
Rabio
送掉
given away
作者:Teo Hernandez
by Teo Hernandez
昆德刚好能找到
Kunde just enough on it to find
Dembele
Griezmann
阿尔瓦雷斯踢得漂亮
nice flick from Alvarez
拉里斯看着这一切
and Larisse watched it all
落入他的魔掌
the way into his clutches
正如亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特放飞的那样
as Alexis Macalester let fly
是啊，法国队开局很糟糕
yeah well the French have started the game poorly
触球过多
too many loose touches
阿根廷正在捡球
and Argentina is picking up the ball
马卡莱斯特在那次射门中表现出色
Macalester on that occasion good strike on goal
我只是需要静一静
just need to settle down a little bit
他的法国方面
his French side
在左边
to the left
相信很多
sure many
塔利亚·菲卡赢了，但只是短暂的
won by Talia Fika but only briefly
和
and
埃尔南德斯
Hernandez
逼退
forced back
不能完全控制
not in complete control
尼西犯规了
Nessie commits a foul
任意球法国队
free kick France
幸运的是
a bit fortunate that
一些埃尔南德斯
some Hernandez
不知道尼斯湖水怪做错了什么
not sure what Nessie's done wrong there
已经在下降了
already going down
马卡莱斯特来了一次袭击
there's a strike from Macalester
也经常搬家
moving a lot as well
拉里斯很好地抓住了这一点
Larisse did well to hold on to that
不是冰壶，但有一点摇晃
wasn't curling but there was a fair bit of wobble on it
是的
yeah
一个被关在军营里的人
one who was confined to Barracks
为这场比赛准备了两天
two days in the build up to this match
病毒在整个
virus spread throughout the
法国营
France camp
所有好的
all okay
胡利安·金格就是这样
Hullian Ginger has been the way
Griezmann
相信很多
sure many
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
一只胳膊压在拉皮奥身上，这是一种牵拉肩膀的动作
with an arm on Rappio it was a tug of the shoulder
这将是法国队的任意球
it will be a free kick for France
有人在看吗
anyone who's been watching
阿尔瓦雷斯在本届世界杯上的表现
Alvarez at this World Cup
今晚可以期待很多吗
can expect a lot of that this evening
不停地跑
doesn't stop running
为他工作
working for his side
找特奥·埃尔南德斯
seeking out Teo Hernandez
上麦卡诺似乎是
there's Upper Meccano who seems to be
在攻击模式下
in aggressive mode
尼斯湖水怪插了一个进去
Nessie slots one through
对于Macalester
for Macalester
在对阵昆德的比赛中运气不错
with a good fortune against Kunde
现在是迪玛利亚
Di Maria now
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
丢球又赢回来
loses possession and wins it back
迪马利亚
Di Maria
德保罗
DePaul
罗德里戈·德保罗，球转到后面去了
Rodrigo DePaul it's deflected behind
他跑得很快
he came off the run
这是一个阿根廷角
and it is an Argentina corner
在左手边
on the left hand side
在天空中，蓝色和白色变得忙碌起来
in the sky blue and white got busy
更多来自阿根廷的好东西
more good stuff from Argentina
在左手边
on the left hand side
迪玛利亚创造了机会
Di Maria creating the chance
本可以去任何地方的
could have gone anywhere this
兰德斯伸出腿想弄点什么
Randers sticking out the leg trying to get something on it
我觉得阿根廷
I get the feeling that Argentina
在左手边感受一下
just feel that on that left hand side
迪玛利亚对阵昆德
with Di Maria against Jules Kunde
他们有一些东西他们有更好的东西
they've got something they've got the better
他们打败了他
they've got the beating of him
尼斯湖水怪的交付
Nessie's delivery
Q在罚球点
Q on the penalty spot
现在它们断裂了
now they break
不是最好的球
wasn't the best ball in
来自莱昂内尔·梅西
from Lionel Messi
保罗，这个更好
DePaul that's a better one
在空中，但不会消失
up in the air but not away
拉里斯决定待在家里
and Larisse has decided to stay at home
当他来取钱的时候
when he does come to get it
他找不到出路
he couldn't find a way through
但他被裁判的哨声救了出来
but is helped out by the referee's whistle
一开始防守很好
it was initially some really good defending
法国的中心
by the French centre ofs
我想是的
I think it was
Verran
他一开始就想起来了
he got his head on it initially
我知道是拉比奥
I know it was Rabiot
刚到一个很重要的位置
just getting in a really important spot
在球门中间
in the middle of the goals here
还有一些队友走到一起
and a couple of teammates coming together
罗梅罗和拉里斯
Romero and Larisse
今天不是朋友吗
have that, not friends today
罗梅罗
Romero
似乎被推入了拉里斯
seemed to be pushed into Larisse
作者:Upper Mercano
by Upper Mercano
这是造成的
it's caused
马刺队和法国队的门将
the Spurs and France goalkeeper
最麻烦的
the most trouble
和妻子海洋不安地看着
and Wife Marine looks unanxiously
这是
it's
第20次出场
his 20th appearance
在世界杯决赛中
at the World Cup finals
有史以来最多的守门员
the most ever by a goalkeeper
他已经超过了曼努埃尔·诺伊尔的19个
he's overtaken Manuel Neuer's 19
今天
today
当他的肋骨被肘击中
when he's took an elbow right in his rib
他会从托特纳姆的训练中知道的
as he'll know from Tottenham training
克里斯蒂安·罗梅罗很可靠
Cristian Romero is pretty solid
他从不浪费时间
he doesn't mess about
好吧，虽然有一点轻推
right though there was a little nudge
从上梅坎科搬到他身上
from Upper Mercano into him
所以这不是什么严重的事情
so this isn't anything too serious
我想罗梅罗不会介意的
I don't think Romero minded that
反正他在看拉里斯
he was looking at Larisse anyway
金吉和蜂蜜不会解决这个问题的
Ginger and Honey won't sort this one out
这是他第一次长时间的谈话
this is his first lengthy conversation
第四名官员是
with the fourth official who is
Ismael Elfat
美国的，但是
of the USA but
摩洛哥出生
Morocco born
多么精彩的比赛啊
what a good tournament
他的国家有过
his nation have had
他的出生地
his birth nation
令人难以置信的精彩故事
incredible brilliant story
Larisse
可以继续吗
will be okay to continue
接下来的几分钟别逗他笑就行了
just don't make him laugh for the next few minutes
我只是想说明一下
just making the point
Marciniak先生认为
to Mr Marciniak that he thinks
有一点
there was a little bit of
这是恶意的
foul intention about it
拉里斯到节礼日就36岁了
Larisse will be 36 on boxing day
奥利维尔·吉鲁已经36岁了
Olivier Giroud is 36 already
13年
13 years
在bape senior
in Bapes senior
吉鲁已经证明了自己
Giroud has proved himself
对法国事业同样重要
to be just as important to the French cause
作为他年轻的伴侣
as his young partner
在过去的几周里
over the last few weeks
格列兹曼赢了
won by Griezmann
这是常有的事
and as is often the case
德保罗为阿根廷解决了这个问题
DePaul sorted it out for Argentina
马丁内斯
Martinez
这是他第一次真正的
first time really he's had any sort of
球的手感
feel of the ball
对着阿尔瓦雷斯
and towards Alvarez
公羊已经覆盖了
the ram has that covered
你可能会想
you would think
阻止不了朱利安·阿尔瓦雷斯
doesn't stop Julian Alvarez
德保罗
DePaul
梅西
Messi
迪马利亚
Di Maria
再次寻找梅西
looking for Messi again
保罗又找到他了
DePaul's found him again
是阿尔瓦雷斯来做结案陈词
it's Alvarez who does the closing
而且它
and it
他的手臂在闭合吗
was closing with his arms
抬起并与球接触
raised and making contact with the ball
法国队任意球
France free kick
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
就像我们说的，经常跑步的人只是抓住了他的手臂
as we said constant runner just catches his arm there
这场比赛是阿根廷先开始的
Argentina really started this game
更好的
the better
把球打到左手边
the ball out to that left hand side
和迪玛利亚在一起似乎是现在的主题
with Di Maria seems to be the play at the minute
他的腿可能不够长
he might not quite have the legs
但正如我们所见
of yesteryear but as we've seen
已经做了几次了
in a few touches already
第一次控制仍然很精致
the first time control is still exquisite
第二口给天使·迪·玛丽亚
second bite this for Angel Di Maria
他是一个没有上场的替补
he was an unused substitute
当阿根廷在2014年进入决赛时
when Argentina got to the final in 2014
Dembele
Mbappe
有什么机会?
what have the chance
折磨那些在他面前的人
to torment those in front of him yet
他在那里做得很好
he's done well there
拉比奥寻找回报
Rabio look for the return
马丁内斯有
Martinez has it
Mbappe
然而第一眼
yet first sight
注意
look sharp
没法把球传给他
couldn't quite get the ball back to him
Rabio
他一开始就被饿死了
he's been starved initially in this game
杀死Mbappe
killing Mbappe
我们喜欢他的时刻，我敢肯定
we love his moment I'm sure
罗梅罗
Romero
Mbappe
拉比奥得到了球，但只是
Rabio got to the ball but only to
推动它
nudge it
现在是迪玛利亚了
into the path of McAllister now Di Maria
谁看到的球比别人多
who's seen as much of the ball as anybody else
蓝色和白色
in blue and white
现在是梅西
and now Messi
没法一直开到迪玛利亚
couldn't work it all the way back through to Di Maria
然后谁看起来好像他越位了
who then looked as though he might be offside and is
只是对他们的生意更精明一点
just a little sharper about their business
阿根廷的人比
Argentina than those in
深蓝色的
darker blue
是的，我想阿尔瓦雷斯只是觉得
yeah I think Alvarez just thinks
他就能把这个人带到迪玛利亚
he can lead this one through to Di Maria
显然越位
clearly offside
你说得对，伙计，他们只是看起来有点
you're right guy they just look a little bit
更忙了，持球更犀利了
busier a bit sharper on the ball
并不是真的创造出来的
not really created that
机会还很大
big chances yet
你能感觉到它来了
you can feel it coming
国际足联世界排名是可以参考的
FIFA World Rankings are anything to go by
他们通常不会
and they usually aren't
它是
it is
阿根廷对法国排名世界第三
Argentina ranked 3 in the world against France
目前排名第四
ranked 4 and yet
法国成为热门
France made marginal favourites
由许多
by many
赛前
pre-match
这个看起来有点迟钝
this look a little bit sluggish
在这场比赛中，我知道有人在谈论
in this game I know there was talk about
营地里有病毒
a virus in the camp
这是真的还是假的
that's true or not but
那种触感还不太到位
the touch just isn't quite there
现在他们被抓在球上了
at the minute they're getting caught on the ball
毫无疑问他们会
no doubt they'll
努力融入比赛，但这已经
work their way into this game but it's been
他们起步缓慢
a slow start from them
是奥斯曼帝国
it was Ottoman
迪马利亚
Di Maria
努力把球保持在里面
to work to keep the ball in
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
谈到了优秀的年轻球员
talked about good young players
我们也见过类似的
and we've seen the likes of
巴迪奥和英格兰的裘德·贝灵汉
Badiol and England's own Jude Bellingham
恩佐·费尔南德斯是另一个
Enzo Fernandez has been another one
谁真的来过4号
who's really come to the 4
21岁
21 year old
本菲卡中场
Benfica midfielder
只打了三场
only played in three
取而代之的是友谊赛
friendlies as a substitute
在比赛开始之前
before this tournament began
我们必须有一个光明的未来
and we must have a bright future
因为本菲卡给了他
because Benfica have given him
13号
number 13
谁愿意属于尤西比奥
who wants to belong to Eusebio
大的鞋子
Big Shoes
有些责任但是
some responsibility that but
就像你说的，他们显然相信他
as you said they obviously believe in him
它充满了奔跑
it's just full of running
这个中场
this midfield
阿根廷的费尔南德斯·德·保罗
of Argentina Fernandez de Paul
麦卡利斯特，他开局不错
McCallister who started this game really well
你很清楚他们的工作
you know their jobs quite clearly
费尔南德斯也许需要一段时间的传球
Fernandez could maybe do with a spell of passing
但特奥·埃尔南德斯更有罪
but Teo Hernandez has been guilty more
比一次失去所有权
than once of losing possession
被德·保罗拉了回来
pulled back by de Paul
梅西失球
missed by Messi
迪玛利亚在错误的时间得到了它
Di Maria got it at the wrong time
就在它下面，弹起的时候
right underneath it as it bounced up
它只是在晃动，不是吗
it's just bobbling isn't it
兄弟会又把球给丢了
again Frats giving the ball away
他只顾自己
he's just keeps himself
在泳池里，这是一个可爱的削减
inside the pool it's a lovely cutback
梅西没能把握住
Messi couldn't quite get on it
他在跳德·玛丽亚舞
he's bobbling into de Maria
你可以看到他真的很专注
you can see he's really concentrating
试着把声音压小，但是
to try and keep it down but
在他较弱的一面
on his weaker side
他没能做到
he couldn't quite make it happen
他们在那边拧螺丝钉
they're turning the screw out there
梅西更多地参与其中
Messi a lot more involved
开场17分钟
in the opening 17 minutes
在这个比赛中，他已经参加了很多场比赛
than he has been in many games at this competition
他们赢了很多次球
well they're winning so many second balls
阿根廷，他只是坐着
Argentina and he just sits
在前面的小空间里
in that little pocket of space in front
所以当他们赢球的时候
of the back four so when they win it
他只是第一次碰到他
he's just first pass into him
他每次都是自由的
he's free every single time
看看瓦兰的时间
look at the time for Varan
Dembele
紧随其后的是
followed very closely by
阿根廷的独角鲸莫利纳右后卫
Narwhal Molina in Argentina right back
他也得到了前面泳池的支持
he's got the support at the pool in front of him as well
看到登贝莱不要惊讶
don't be surprised to see Dembele
漂流到中部地区
drift into central areas
如果这种情况继续下去
if that continues
返回
returned
Dembele
他有个法式掷球
he's got a French throw
在那里
there
肯定是曼尼自作主张
for sure Manny had made himself
可用
available
回到
it's back to
先是阿兰，现在是麦卡诺
first for Aran and now for McArno
然后是特奥·埃尔南德斯
and on to Teo Hernandez
然后回来
and back back
得到了很好的回报
really nicely returned
泰奥·埃尔南德斯随后罚下任意球
Teo Hernandez then down free kick
为法国
for France
吉鲁就要开始舔了
and Giroux will be starting to lick
球
the ball
我觉得这是个错误
I think it was a mistake from
保罗甚至不确定是否能抢到球
DePaul not sure even challenges for the ball
我们只是把他夹在那里
we just kind of clips him there
这绝对是一个任意球
it's definitely a free kick
有点笨拙
it's a bit clumsy
第一点
the first bit of
积极性
positivity
法国在这场比赛中的表现
for France in this game
要建立一些东西
something to set up
慢慢来
take their time
很好，它穿过了禁区
very good it crosses into the box
我认为
I think
我们可以看到
we can see
他会瞄准哪里
where he's going to be aiming
01:29:09,600 --> 01:29:11,600
就在那个地方
right into that spot
过了头
over the top
大家都来了，奥利维亚·吉鲁
everybody came Olivia Giroux
有点太有女人味了
with a little too much women vigor
他给了一个任意球
he's giving a free kick
他们的裁判
their referee
所以换个角度看
so another look at it
吉鲁似乎在攻击它
and Giroux seems to attack it
除了他的眼睛，什么也没有
nothing but his eyes on the
球对他是公平的
ball in fairness to him
这是爬过几具尸体
this is climbing over a few bodies
但
but
这是一个幸运的任意球
they've been a fortunate free kick
待给予
to be given
我想是因为他跳得很早
I suppose the idea was that he jumped early
并阻止迪玛丽亚从地板上下来
and stopped Di Maria getting off the floor
反正那场比赛只有一个赢家
there was only one winner in that contest anyway
奥利维亚·吉鲁今天得分了
Olivia Giroux scores today
他将成为历史上最年长的射手
he will become the oldest ever goal scorer
在世界杯决赛中
in a World Cup final
令人难以置信的职业生涯
incredible career
真的是
really is
还在做
still be doing it
在他这个年纪是顶级的
at the top level at his age
是不同的阶级
is different class
现在的持有者
current holder of that
长期以来一直是尼尔斯
and for a long time has been Niels
瑞典的利德霍尔姆
Lidholm of Sweden
进球了
scored his goal
1958年，在他36岁之前
in 1958 before he turned 36
参加
梅西
Messi
莫利纳
Molina
他确实喜欢向前冲
he does like to get forward
迪·保罗就像热尔曼说的那样
and Di Paul as Germain has said on that side
使他能够那样做
enables him to do that
自己
himself
吉鲁在追
there's chase by Giroud
由阿尔瓦雷斯演奏
play that by Alvarez
迪马利亚
Di Maria
可爱的臀部旋转
lovely swivel of the hips
迪玛利亚倒下了
down goes Di Maria
阿根廷点球
penalty Argentina
裁判毫不犹豫
no hesitation from the referee
登贝莱靠得太近了
Dembele got too close
看起来很笨拙
it looks clumsy
你必须说你能马上看出迪玛利亚想要做什么
you have to say you can see what Di Maria wants to do straight away
它叫登贝莱
it goes by Dembele
让我越过你
let me get across you
那你得做个决定了
you've got a decision to make then
很难看出是否有真正的接触
it's hard to see if there's actual contact
它几乎等于零
it is next to nothing
但它确实是
but it is something
它看起来很小
it looks minimal
他们会好好看看的
they'll have a good look at it
我相信
I'm sure
迪玛利亚肯定是这么想的
it was definitely in Di Maria's mind
你可以看出那种感觉是
you could tell the feeling was
当他从他身边走过的时候，离他远点
when he went by him stay away from him
他想下去
he wanted to go down
裁判相信了
and the referee bought it
我认为这对他们来说是很难转变的
I think it would be a difficult one for them to turn
关掉VAR
to turn down on VAR
如果我完全诚实的话
if I'm totally honest
这是因为手臂接触了
well it's because the arm has made contact
但肯定还不足以让迪玛利亚陷入困境
but surely not enough to send Di Maria sprawling
我认为问题在于一旦裁判判罚
I think the issue is once it's been given by the referee
就是这样
that's it
必须把它看作是一个明显的错误
it's got to be looked upon as a clear and obvious error
我不确定他们会这么看
and I'm not sure they will look at it as that
虽然接触很少，但是
it was minimal contact but
我想是登贝莱的穷人
I think it was poor from Dembele
只要他从他身边经过就得离他远点
he's just got to stay clear of him once he goes by him
他得把胳膊拿开
he's got to keep the arms away
现在
and now
重点是
the focus is on
梅西
Lionel Messi
梅西的分数
Messi scores
所有这些目标
all of those goals
所有这些神奇的职业生涯中的时刻
all of those moments in a magical career
一个简单的击球
a simple stroke of the ball
从12码外
from 12 yards out
最好的
tops the line
一个目标
a goal
在最重要的比赛中
in the biggest match of all
献给最伟大的球员之一
for one of the greatest players of all
看看焦点
look at the focus
最酷的男人
the coolest man
在大楼里
in the building
当他需要的时候
when he needed to be
有几个步骤
a couple of steps
艾娃看着拉里斯
Ava looks at Larise
让他坐下
sits him down
他把它插在底部的角落里
he sticks it in the bottom corner
他们是阿根廷更好的一面
they've been much the better side of Argentina
他们应该带头
and they deserve to take the lead
本届世界杯决赛
in this World Cup Final
没有播放器
no player
之前得分
before scored
进入16强
in the round of 16
半决赛和决赛
the semifinal and the final
以前从未有过这样的球员
there hasn't been a player like this before
阿根廷赢了
Argentina won
法国零
France nil
而法国人需要的是唤醒球
when it was the wake up ball that the French needed
自从开球以来，他们一直没有取得进展
they've not got going since kickoff
我们觉得有什么东西要来了
we felt like something was coming
左手边
that left hand side
我们很早就谈过了
we spoke about it early
和迪玛丽亚在一起
with Di Maria
就是那种感觉
just that feeling
他能战胜朱尔斯·康迪
that he could get the better of Jules Cundey
他最终成为了他胜过的登贝莱
he ended up being Dembele that he gets the better of
但对斯科洛尼来说
but so far for Scoloni
没有更好的开始了吗
could not have started any better
在那出戏里
in that play
是时候让其他10个人试着融入比赛了
time for the other 10 to try and get into the match a bit more
柔软的处罚
soft penalty
严厉的处罚
harsh penalty
登贝莱付出了代价
Dembele paid the penalty
很容易被打败
for being beaten so easily by
迪玛丽亚的运动
Di Maria's movement
他完全出卖了自己
he sold himself completely
他必须站起来，防守得更好
he's got to stand up and defend much better
Dembele
现在反对它
against it now
他是斯蒂芬
he's Stefan
他做了加法
he did the addition
长期的得力助手
long time right hand man
有几句话作为回应吗
had a few words by way of response there
回到半决赛
back to the semi-finals
而法国没有
and France did not have it
以任何方式对付摩洛哥
their own way by any means against Morocco
再看看这个
again look at that
每次法国队拿球
every time France have the ball
有很多人站着看
there's a lot of standing and watching
没有运动
there's no movement
在球中移动太慢
the move in the ball too slow
传球太直了
the passes are too straight
阿根廷很容易防守
it's so easy for Argentina to defend against
有Giroud
there's Giroud
他为法国队进了三球
he's down three kick for France
那是罗梅罗的铲球
that was Romero with the tackle
回到对英格兰的阵营
back to the quarters against England
两个是
two they were
不完全是
not exactly
也不是那种完全自由自在的风格
in full free-flowing style in that one either
但他们找到了办法
but they found a way
现在他们必须想办法回去
now they have to find a way back
可以从这里开始
might start here
这是毫无疑问的
there's no doubt that
这个概念作品令人毛骨悚然
the concept piece is eerily
你会给团队带来很多问题
you can cause teams a lot of problems
这个人的产品质量很好
quality delivery from this man
在空中的后臂
at the back arm in the air
而格列兹曼将拥有
and Griezmann will have
再来一次
to do it again
费尔南德斯下台了
down went Fernandez
他捂着眼睛
he's holding his eye
我不知道发生了什么，但是
I'm not sure what's happened here but
费尔南德斯似乎不太高兴
doesn't seem happy Fernandez
他正在收拾残局
he's sorting out the melee
这没有什么
that's nothing
真的没什么
really is nothing
拿两个格里兹曼
take two Griezmann
相同的程序
same routine
他现在正对着包厢讲话
he's gone down on the air to the box now
裁判把那个球给了阿根廷
the referee has given that one to Argentina
看起来像是头撞了一下
and it looks like a clash of heads
他在呼吁立即关注
he's calling for immediate attention
费尔南德斯扶着他的肋骨
Fernandez is holding his ribs
梅西低头抱着头
Messi down holding his head
这就是为什么
that's why
费尔南德斯有他的手
Fernandez has his hand
梅西在他的脑海里，谢天谢地，梅西醒了
it's Messi in his head, thankfully Messi's up
我觉得还可以
seems fine I think
费尔南德斯看起来也不错
Fernandez seems okay as well
我一直都是这样
I've been like that
比赛开始前几个小时
for hours before this game kicked off
阿根廷、墨西哥或摩洛哥
Argentina, Mexico or Morocco
给你们，锦标赛的粉丝们
for you the fans of the tournament
我想阿根廷就拿去吧
I think Argentina just take it
摩洛哥紧随其后
Morocco just behind
有幸去看了摩洛哥的一场比赛吗
was very fortunate to go to one of the Morocco games
他们
and they
完全，不仅接管了体育场
completely, not only took over the stadium
但在本届世界杯上赢得了很多人的心
but won the hearts of so many people at this World Cup
这是一个不可思议的故事
it's been an incredible story
但
but
每次你走进来看到
every time you step in and see
这些阿根廷人的蓝色和白色
the blue and white colours of these Argentinians
和
and the
他们的歌声
the voice with their songs
它只是抓住了你
it just grabs you
不同级别
different level
但后来他们到了巴西
but then they were in Brazil
也是在2014年的里约
in Rio in 2014 too
但这并没有阻止德国人获胜
and it didn't stop the Germans winning
阿根廷已经做得更好了
Argentina have already gone one better
因为他们没有发现一枪打中目标
because they didn't register a single shot on target
在比赛的正常时或加时赛中
in normal or extra time in that game
梅西
Messi
泰欧·费尔南德斯赢得角球
wins the corner courtesy of Teo Fernandez
另一端的噪音
the noise at the other end
又上升了一个档次
goes up a notch once more
这是梅西的一个更好的提升
it's a better lift in by Messi
他要再试一次
he's going to get another go
但是他站在越位位置，所以他不会
but he is standing offside so he won't
再试一次
get another go
吉鲁的防守很好
good defending from Giroud
因为这是一个很难处理的问题
because a difficult one to deal with
因为它很低
because it was low
它并不是真正的高度
it wasn't really at the height
让他去攻击任何一个小动作
for him to go and attack any little flick
或者尼克在近柱是个大问题
or nick at that near post is a massive problem
所以它是
so it was
这是必须的
big header that was needed
他在做噩梦
he's having a nightmare
从他第一次触球开始
from his first touch in the game
他直接从戏剧中走出来了
he went straight out of plays
判了点球后，他无法守住球
giving the penalty away he can't keep the ball
他看起来有点内向
he's looked a little within himself
肢体语言
the body language
梅西
Messi
晃过登贝莱
shimmies past Dembele
麦卡利斯特致迪玛利亚
McAllister to Di Maria
他把十字架弄得一团糟
he's made a mess of that cross
到处都有太多的空间
there's too much space everywhere
但他们玩得很开心
but they're enjoying themselves
他现在是阿根廷人
he's Argentinians at the minute
每个人都想要球
everybody wants the ball
玩得很自由
playing with a lot of freedom
他在两边都给法国队打了边路
he's put them wide for France on both sides
迪玛丽亚心情很好
Di Maria in the mood
泰奥·埃尔南德斯几次把球丢了
and Teo Hernandez has given the ball away a few times
在另一边
on the other side
和经理
and Beppe
当他需要帮助时，他是如何帮助的
how did he help when he needed it
所有的面
all of the facets to
让法国队表现出色的比赛并不存在
France's game that makes them good are just not there
特鲁梅尼没跟上球
Truimeni's not getting on the ball
没看到安托万·格列兹曼的消息
not seeing anything from Antoine Griezmann
不管有没有球，这都是他们最大的组成部分之一
with or without the ball and that's been one of their biggest components
在这次比赛中
at this tournament
可以说是最好的之一
and arguably one of the best
比赛中的球员
players at the tournament
绝对是最好的年轻球员和贝佩
definitely the best young player and Beppe
没有踢
not had a kick
德保罗
De Paul
梅西让它继续前进
kept it going to by Messi
麦卡利斯特
McAllister
梅西转身
Messi with the turn
把球传给迪玛利亚
and the ball Di Maria's way
他只是在错误的地方被抓住了
he was caught just on the wrong bit of
攻击模式，但很好
strike pattern but it's a good
无论如何都要及时到达那里
response to get there in time anyway
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
整个靴子都掉错了地方
came off the wrong part of the boot all together
目标越宽越好
well well wider the target
需要一些努力吗
would have been some effort
你可以看到他为什么把它放在上面，它坐得很好
you can see why he took it on it sat up nicely
迪玛利亚只是把它藏起来
Di Maria just keeping that in
在那里
there
32分钟后
32 minutes in
阿根廷
Argentina
一球领先
with the one goal lead
梅西
Messi
试图摆脱做不到的麦卡特尼
trying to get away from up on McCartney who couldn't do it
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
费尔南德斯，请原谅
Fernandez I beg your pardon
德保罗的球进了
De Paul's ball in
茎腹向外
stem belly away
只是暂时的喘息
only temporary respite
顺便说一下，这是一个大铲球
big tackle that by the way
从麦卡特尼上你可以看到梅西在排球
from up on McCartney you could see Messi lining it up
必须到达那里才能完成挑战
had to get there make the challenge
亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特的小突破
little break forward here from Alexis McAllister
还是得掐我自己
still have to pinch myself
观看布莱顿队的球员
watching a Brighton Hove Albion player
在世界杯决赛中，他做到了
in the World Cup final and he has been
每场比赛都很精彩
magnificent pretty much every game
麦卡特尼面临着巨大的挑战
there's that big challenge from up on McCartney
有点像你的真命天子
a bit your right guy
麦卡利斯特
McAllister
好比赛
good tournament
这个中场的顶级抽签
top draw in this midfield
看起来很稳定
looks really settled
爱尔兰血统
Irish ancestry
把眉毛画得太过分了
plays the eyebrows too far
别忘了1986年
let's not forget in 1986
乔·布朗是阿根廷队的后卫
Joe Brown was at the back for Argentina
何塞·路易斯·布朗
Jose Luis Brown
Mollina
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
1986年是最后一次
1986 was the last time
阿根廷人要这样称呼自己
that Argentina got to call themselves
世界冠军
world champions
但
but
有些象征性地
somewhat symbolically
这是第一次举办世界杯
this is the first World Cup that's taken place
自
since
马拉多纳之死
the death of Diego Maradona
当我们这些人长大了
as those of us old enough
他的这一年太不顺利了
no all too well was his year
向加里点了点头
with a nod to Gary
梅西
Messi
迪马利亚
Di Maria
塔里亚菲科
Talia Fico
尽管有马科斯·阿库尼亚，他仍然保住了自己的位置
retaining his place despite Marcos Acunha
他又有空了
being available again he started
更多的比赛
more games at the tournament
塔利亚·菲科在对阵
Talia Fico did really well against
摩洛哥的防守
Morocco defensively and
在左手边上下跳动
pumping up and down that left hand side
是的，他已经开始了
yeah he's already
开始冒险向前走
started to venture get forward
左边还有一个选项
another option down that left hand side
让弗朗茨做更多的事
something more for Franz to
担心
to worry about
他们还有比这更严重的问题
a minute they've got bigger problems than that
开不了二挡
can't get themselves out of second gear
这可能对弗兰兹有帮助
that might help Franz
罗梅罗过去有一点误判
a bit of a misjudgment in the past from Romero
到莫利娜·罗梅罗，然后被
to Mollina Romero then beaten by
姆巴佩只给他留了一点
Mbappe just left a little bit on him
确保他不能完成任务
to make sure he couldn't complete the job
姆巴佩说得很好
nice though from Mbappe
里面有点磨损
it's a little worn inside
梅西扭转了局面
Messi turns it
有请阿尔瓦雷斯，他成功了
out to Alvarez who gets it through
这就是麦卡利斯特
and that's McAllister
看着迪玛利亚
looking at Di Maria
阿根廷遥遥领先
Argentina well on top
在世界杯决赛中
in the World Cup final
过去的男孩们都起来了
and all the boys of yesteryear are up
庆祝那一天
celebrating that one
我们将讨论团队目标
we'll talk about a team goal
我喜欢它在拐角处的样子
loving it on it round the corner
麦卡利斯特和梅西
by McAllister and Messi
而且他总是一个乐于奔跑的人
and he's always a willing runner
麦卡利斯特，但他能找到通道吗
McAllister but can he find the pass
问题是
is the question
爱它在上面
loving it on it
但是那个球才是最重要的
but it's that ball there that's the important one
最后一球
the final ball
看他眼睛里的专注
look at his eyes the concentration
迪玛利亚的球总是弹跳起来
from Di Maria always bounces it
进入守门员的地面
into the ground over the keeper
一个完整的团队
a complete team
阿根廷进球
goal for Argentina
他们真是活该
what on they thoroughly deserve
他们在梦境中
and they're in dreamland
他们也一样
and so are they
阿根廷，为我哭泣吧
do cry for me Argentina
迪玛利亚也无法阻止他们
Di Maria can't hold them back either
布莱顿的那个男孩进的球
a goal made by the boy from Brighton
由一位前巴黎公民得分
and scored by a former citizen of Paris
阿根廷2
Argentina 2
法国0
France 0
绝对值得
absolutely merited
他们不会相信他们面对的是什么
they won't believe what they're facing
此刻他们是辉煌的阿根廷
at the minute they've been brilliant Argentina
但他们万万没想到会有这样的比赛
but there's no way they expected a game like this
缺乏强度
the lack of intensity
从法国
from France
你吓了我一跳，下面毫无疑问
you surprised me there's no doubt down there
在球场上，他们必须做到
on the pitch they must be
对他们拥有的自由感到震惊
in shock at the freedom they have
信心的节奏
confidence rhythm
没有比这里更适合球员的地方了
there's no better place to be as a player
想象一下那些球员现在的感受吧
only imagine what those players are feeling right now
自由地玩耍
playing with freedom
不用担心，在世界杯决赛中调整一下
no fear tune it up in a World Cup final
有歌迷在你身后唱歌
with those fans singing behind you
闯进了麦克阿里斯特的箱子
barge into the chest of McAllister courtesy of Cunday
更多的碰撞
more of a collision
多说些闪开的事
much about getting out of the way
那他在进球中的作用呢，麦卡利斯特
what about his part in that goal McAllister
尼克一转身就走了
the nick around the corner and then he's off
没有人能抓住他
no one can catch him
他在过去几年里一直在建造
he's been building over the last couple of years
然后他就被点燃了
and then he's sparked into life
在这个英超赛季开始的时候
at the start of this Premier League season
在前六场比赛中为海鸥队打进四球
four goals in the first six games for the Seagulls
他说加泰罗尼亚语已经成年了
he's come of age in Catalan
他很享受陪伴
he's enjoying company
最高级的
of the highest order
在这里感觉很自在
and at home in it
Verran
Chouameny
Chouamény
这一点很明显
obvious point to make
法国队一定要进下一个球吗
is that France absolutely must score the next goal in the game
在法国中场被杀
getting killed in midfield France
超负荷的人进来了
the overloads messy dropping in
游泳池运行力的质量
the quality in the running power of the pool
就是那支法国队有些不对劲
just something not right in that France team at all
到目前为止，它的发展方式
and the way that it's gone so far
埃米利亚诺·马丁内斯还不如和我们一起看呢
Emiliano Martinez might as well have watched it with us
向吉鲁方向前进
up towards Giroud
就是这样
that's all it was
莫利纳
Molina
吉鲁让拉米罗有点着急
Giroud makes Ramiro hurry a bit
这是一个球
that's a ball that was
有意的
intentional
我觉得现在很重要，对吧
I think it matters now does it
迪马利亚
Di Maria
他在上面
he is on it
是他让这一切顺利进行的
he's the man that got this going
在阿根廷
for Argentina
因为他在去年的美洲杯决赛中打进了制胜球
because he scored the winner in the Copa America final last year
这就结束了他们长期的
which ended their long run of
国际干旱
international drought
现在看看这个迪迪埃·德尚做了双重改变
now look at this there is a double change being made by Didier Deschamps
半场结束前
before half time
登贝莱走了
Dembele is off
吉鲁也要去
and Giroud is going as well
吉鲁曾为之苦恼
Giroud who had been troubled by
他膝盖的问题导致他
a problem with his knee that caused him to
在过去的几天里，少参加一些训练
sit out a bit of training over the last few days
所以《哥伦比亚》开始了
so Colomouane is on
谁在半决赛中上场44秒后进球
who scored 44 seconds after coming on in the semi-final
Marcus Chouam是
and Marcus Chouam is
早在他预料到之前就进入了
entering way before he anticipated doing as well
我一点也不怪他
I don't blame him at all
迪迪埃德尚
Didier Deschamps
他在看我们一直在看的东西
he's looking at the same thing we've been looking at
一支在球场上不存在的球队
a team that's non-existent on the pitch
显然是在挣扎
obviously struggling with something
作为一个团体，他们多带了一个
as a group they were carrying one too many
在我看来
in my opinion
刚看到愤怒的乔·基夫
just got a glimpse of fury Jor-Keyf
和骄傲的父亲莉莲·图拉姆
and proud father Lillian Turram
现在正常地在看台上
in the stands now normally
你会喜气洋洋你的心将会爆炸
you'd be beaming your heart will be bursting
看到自己的儿子在世界杯决赛中表现出色
seeing your own son get on in a World Cup final
但莉莉安·特拉姆更关心的是
but Lillian Turram will be a little more concerned about
现在的比分
the scoreline right now
我想从法国的角度来看
I think from a France point of view
如果这些球员是健康的
if these players are fit
然后他们会过得更好
then they're going to be much better off
这对德尚来说是一个艰难的决定
It's a tough call for Deschamps
因为很明显吉鲁
because obviously Giroud
在比赛中给了他这么多
had given him so much in the tournament
然后贝雷特扮演了他的角色
then Belet played his role
他不得不在中场休息前打电话
he's had to make the call before half-time
我想在那里立竿见影
trying to make an instant contribution there
但是他给了对方一个任意球
but he has given away a free-kick
但这意味着姆巴佩会从中路穿过
but it means Mbappe will go through the middle
有一种想法是，他们可能会从一开始就这么做
there was a thought that they might do it from the start
而且可能不得不这么做
and might have to do it
向迪玛利亚驶去
tied out towards Di Maria
星期一跑步
running at Kunday
这会杀死他们
it's killing them
Kunday这次可以在他的图表上加上一种风格
Kunday can just put a style on his chart this time
那个球已经开了一整天了
that ball has just been on all day
就这么浮在了昆迪的头上
just floated over Kunday's head
他已经尽力了
he's doing his best out there
他只是需要一点支持
he just needs a bit of support if anything
姆巴佩走在前面
Mbappe is leading the way
几乎可以肯定这是他最后一次参加国际比赛
almost certainly his final international appearance
这就是他今年所暗示的
that's what he's hinted at this year
不止一次
more than once
而本届世界杯将是他的最后一次冒险
and this World Cup would be his last venture
为了他的国家
for his country
我们知道这将是他在世界杯上的最后一场比赛
messy we know this will be his last game at the World Cup
它是否会
whether it will be
告别了所有的国际
farewell to internationals all together
我们还不知道
we don't know yet
我们希望不会
and we hope not
Opa McCona
Mbappe
得想办法让姆巴佩加入比赛
got to find a way to get Mbappe into this game
他是踢左路还是中路
whether he plays on the left through the middle
不管他在哪里，把球给他
wherever he is just get him the ball
姆巴佩，这是一次鲁莽的尝试
Mbappe that was a rash attempt
从罗梅罗第一个到达那里
to get there first from Romero
我认为早一点的那个犯规了
I think the foul has been given for the earlier
对埃尔南德斯的挑战
challenge on Hernandez actually
我觉得罗梅罗没碰他
I don't think Romero touched him
靠运气而不是判断
by luck rather than judgement
我想肯定是运气使然
I think definitely by luck
需要冷静下来
needs to calm down
Opa McCona
Kunday
Opa Mbappe
这又是一个代换
there's the substitute again
他只是在做他被要求做的事
and he's trying to do what he's been asked to do
所有的
all of them
在那种情况下，乱追乱追
with the messy on that occasion chasing back
有一段关于阿根廷的短促和咆哮
there's a snap and a snarl about Argentina
而且都是以积极的方式
and all in a positive way
就在那里看
that's watching there
额外时间为7分钟
seven minutes of additional time is indicated
待添加
to be added
看看德保罗
just looking at DePaul
只是为了获得额外的优势
just little things to get an extra advantage
在姆巴佩的耳朵里有一句持续的话吗
was having a sustained word in the ear of Mbappe
就在他走过的时候
just as he walked past
我想他就是那个2比0的人
I think he was the one at 2-0
就像开球前一样
just as before kickoff was
对着队友大喊大叫
screaming and shouting at his teammates
继续
keep going
这还不够
this is not enough
这是出
that's out
当时在找迪玛利亚
looking for Di Maria that time
他完成了他们的任务
he did their shot
不会退缩
does not hang back
他不得不斥责他的队员
he has to give his players a dressing down
在更衣室里
in the dressing room
的语言
the language
会有一点熟吗
will be a little bit ripe in there
我不确定我是否需要
I'm not sure I'll need to
他们都是经验丰富的玩家
these are experienced players
一些世界冠军
some world champions
在这个群体中
in this group
我想自己会说的
I think it will be said themselves
他们知道自己离目标还很远
they know they are nowhere near where they need to be
让我们回到游戏中来
let's get back into this game
转身
turn around
球
the ball
对埃尔南德斯的指控
given against Hernandez
正在向他解释
being explained to him now
他没心情听你说
he's not in the mood to hear it
几乎什么都没有
again, barely anything
我觉得里面没有太多东西
I think it's not much in it
但你一戴上胸钉就走了
but the minute you're going with your studs up
现在
right now
通常情况下，它是给定的
more often than not it's going to be given
他只是比德保罗高一点
he was just a little higher than DePaul
保罗和埃尔南德斯
DePaul and Hernandez
从一开始就关系不好
not being on great terms from the start
迪玛利亚表现得很好
Di Maria has just been great
从一开始
from the start
我想大多数阿根廷人
I think most of the Argentinian side
迪玛利亚，中场三人组
Di Maria, that midfield trio
德保罗的麦卡利斯特
of McAllister, DePaul
和费尔南德斯
and Fernandez
主持节目
ran the show
提醒一下
a little note of caution
对于那些喜欢阿根廷的人来说
for those who fancy Argentina
为了赢得这场比赛
to win this
有心有脑
with hearts and heads
他们在这次比赛中有两场没赢
they have failed to win two games at this tournament
在中场休息时领先
when in front at halftime
这在世界杯上没有发生过吗
which hadn't happened to them at a world cup
从1930年的决赛开始
since the final of 1930
包括2-0领先
including from being 2-0 up against
在四分之一决赛中击败荷兰队
the Dutch in the quarterfinals
所以弗朗茨要回一个
so Franz get one back
它真的又开始了
and it really is on again
几乎没有什么宝贵的迹象
there has been precious little sign of anything
来自卫冕世界冠军
from the defending world champions
到目前为止
so far
一种绝望和呼唤
a despair and call of
蓝啤酒
Ale Le Bleu
如果你能看出来的话
if you can just about make it out
巴普尔对自己要求太高了
Bapé asks too much of himself
针对Ramira
against Ramira
玛利亚失去控球权
Maria loses possession
内存
Ram
Guadanacana
Taram
挑战
challenged by
Moullina
掷球
comes to the throw
不是他渴望的那个任意球
not the free kick he was craving
斯科洛尼的门将
for the goalkeeper of Leonel Scoloni
在他的技术领域的边缘走来走去
marching up and down the edge of his technical area
不断与他的球员沟通
constantly in communication with his players
德尚有着完全不同的风格
Deschamps has a rather different style
他仍然坐着
he remains seated
在大部分比赛中
for most of the contest
这是一个很好的挑战
that's a good challenge
格列兹曼被第二个挑战打败了
Griezmann though is beaten to it by the secondary challenge of
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
他们整场比赛就是这么做的
that's exactly what they've had the whole game
在阿根廷互相扶持
in Argentina back in each other up
巨大的讨论
huge discussions
那个人在中场休息
at half time for that man
他能让他的球队重回赛场吗
can he get his team back into this game
他已经做了一些改变
he's made a couple of changes already
著名的人
man famously
被描述为运水者
described as a water carrier by
埃里克·坎塔纳
Eric Cantanar no less
米歇尔·普拉蒂尼曾经怀疑他是否得到了圣水的祝福
Michel Platini once wondered if he'd been blessed with holy water
这就是他，这就是他的成功
such was his, such is his success
作为一名球员和教练
as a player and coach
恐怕上半场他的球队一直在原地踏步
I'm afraid in this first half his team's been treading water
以球员和教练的身份看待这一切
seeing it all as a player and a manager
你需要每一盎司的经验
you need every single ounce of that experience
Griezmann
哪条路?阿根廷的方式
which way? Argentina's way
你知道，这是阿根廷比赛中最精彩的部分
that's been the best part about Argentina's game you know
你说你想要什么伟大的目标
you say what you want about the great goals
放一些肉豆蔻在这里，那里
some good play, a couple of nutmegs here and there
但他们在无球状态下的那种强度
but that intensity they have without the ball
很难匹配
it's difficult to match
Ramira
对迪玛丽亚来说，这太过分了
too much on that for Di Maria
小心麦克风
mind the mic
法国队的替补球员在上场后表现得相当不错
the French substitutes have done pretty well since coming on
Colo Moana强调了这一点
and that was emphasised there by Colo Moana
只是有了更多的能量
there's just been a little bit more energy
来自这里的人
from here man from
图拉姆在另一边
Turram on the other side
把牌拿出来是因为尽管事实如此
the cards out here because despite the fact
恩佐·费尔南德斯倒下了
that Enzo Fernandez is down
这将是法国队的任意球
he's going to be a France free kick
等他能站起来，他就会收到罚单
and when he's back to his feet he will get the booking
《莫阿纳岛》的表演太精彩了
that was brilliant from Colo Moana
他的压力太大了
he was under so much pressure
他必须滚一个，旋转
he had to roll one, spin
就像跑在后面
like a running behind
我以为他是想避开黄牌
I thought he was trying to swerve the yellow card
部分已确认
the portion is confirmed
这是七分钟的时间，所以
and that's the seven minutes up so it's
根据…的自由裁量权
under the discretion of
Simon Marciniak，这就是传说
Simon Marciniak now and it is that fabled
得分的好时机
good time to score
阿根廷保持高位
Argentina keep a high line
格列兹曼想把球投到线后
Griezmann looks to put it in behind that line
他做到了，但米兰还没到
he's done that but Miran won't get there
休息前不会有任何东西回到法国
and there won't be anything back for France before the break
这就是高线的美妙之处
that's the beauty of a high line
这球很难，格列兹曼的球踢得很好
it's really difficult, it's a good ball from Griezmann
这就是突破口
and that is the break
没有时间做更多的事情了
no time for anything more
但现在是阿根廷的时代吗，他们已经成功了一半
but is it Argentina's time, they are half way there
多亏了一个有点混乱的判罚
thanks to a little messy penalty
奖项还有待商榷
the award of which will be debated
最后一道是迪玛利亚料理
and then a Di Maria finish
在阿根廷的举动之后
after an Argentina flowing move
在前场的
downfield
这是他们应得的，他们掌控一切
they deserve this, they are in control
中场休息的时候阿根廷也是如此
and that half time it's Argentina too
法国现在
France now
上半场真是一边倒
what a one-sided first half
那是在世界杯决赛中
that was in a World Cup final
法国队一枪未射
France didn't manage a single shot
基利安·姆巴佩根本没有进球
at goal at all, Killian Mbappe didn't have
上半场有很多触球
many touches in that first half
他能在第二秒扭转局面吗
can he turn things around in the second
阿根廷队上半场表现如何
what's the first half performance from Argentina
他们从一开始就很激动
sensational, they've been from the very first minute
他们进攻法国
they went after France
法国对此无能为力
France couldn't cope with it
他们看起来根本就没有腿
didn't look as if they had any legs at all
你要关注你的玩家
you're looking to your players
你的队友，你的球迷
your teammates, the fans on the big occasion
你在说我们有什么
you're saying what have we got
我们能交出最好的表演吗
can we turn in our very best performance
阿根廷就是这么做的
and Argentina have done exactly that
经理再次获得了巨大的荣誉
great credit again to the manager
做了另一个决定，让迪玛丽亚回来
made another decision bringing Di Maria back in
他是上半场表现最好的球员
and he's been the best player in the first half
里约，真是出奇的一边倒
Rio, extraordinarily one-sided really
我是说法国看起来很平
I mean France look flat
我不知道营地里有没有病毒
I don't know whether they've had a virus in the camp
我们不知道这是否影响了他们
we don't know whether that's affected them or not
但撇开这些不谈，阿根廷一直表现出色
but put that aside, Argentina have been excellent
我觉得从战术上来说斯科洛尼是对的
I think tactically Scoloni's got his spot on
中场四人
the four in midfield
我们在法国的数字是3
our number in the French three in there
我们增加了一个数字，这样梅西就有5个了
we've added a number in there to make it five with Messi
他们在那里欺负他们
they're just bullying them in there
他们更有攻击性
they're far more aggressive
坚韧，他们看起来更饥饿
the tenacity, they look hungrier
当他们有机会的时候
and when they've had the opportunities
到目前为止，他们在这场比赛中表现得非常冷静
they've been absolutely clinical in this game so far
我给了你一点时间让你冷静下来
I've given you a little bit of time to compose yourself
是的,没有
yes, no
你一定是，我是说你……
you must be, I mean you're
出来吧，还有45分钟
just come out, 45 minutes to go
但从阿根廷出发的45分钟非常棒
but it was a fantastic 45 minute from Argentina
我是说，你知道的，要先发制人
I mean, you know, on the front foot
从比赛的第一分钟开始
from the first minute on the game
踢得好，控球速度快
playing good football, high tempo on the ball
我想我是不是从斯科洛尼来把迪玛利亚移到左边
I think whether I'm from Scoloni to move Di Maria on the left
而且，他这次也很火
as well, he's been on fire this
45分钟
45 minutes
我们当时谈过，他有多重要
you know, we spoke about it then, how important he was
我为迪玛利亚感到高兴，是的
for that team and I'm so pleased for Di Maria, yes
好吧，让我们回顾一下判罚结果
OK, let's run through the penalty decision
关于那次接触，还有些疑点
there's an element of doubt as to the contact
艾伦谈迪玛利亚
Alan on Di Maria
不，那是我的点球，我觉得……
No, it was a penalty from me, I think it's
你必须仔细观察才能发现它
you've got to look very closely to spot it
但肯定有接触，而且他在跑
but there's definitely contact and he's running
在速度
at pace
他发现自己身处迪玛利亚的太空
he finds himself in space there Di Maria
对阵登贝莱，他上半场踢得很糟糕
against Dembele who had a really poor half
当然，他被脱掉了，他不应该
and of course was taken off and he should never
像那样转身
get turned like that
他拼命想要回去
he's trying desperately to get back in
但如果你看迪玛利亚的左腿
but if you just watch Di Maria's left leg
第二个是近角度
and the close angle in the second
他的左腿，可以触球
he's left leg, that makes the contact
你可以看到，然后他必须
there you can see and then he has to
这导致他踢自己
that causes him to kick himself
这是一个点球，踢得很好
and it's a penalty, really good play
来自迪玛丽亚，但很可怕
from Di Maria but terrible
从Dembele
from Dembele
阿尔瓦雷斯也踢了个好球，可惜没有
Great ball from Alvarez in there as well, wasn't there
致迪玛丽亚
to Di Maria
你喜欢多酷就多酷
and as cool as you like
在这次锦标赛之前，他从来没有进过一个致命一球
before this tournament he'd never scored a knockout goal
梅西，现在他每轮都进一个球
Messi, now he's scored one in every round
不,是的
No, yes
真为梅西高兴
So happy for Messi
平静,人
Calm, man
看看梅西的下场吧
Look what happens for Messi
巴勃罗，你想要什么
Pablo, what would you like
来听听一些评论
to hear a little bit of commentary
从你的家乡?
from your homeland?
肯定有一些疯狂的人
There must be some crazy ones
好了
There you go
欢呼
CHEERING
家人也在庆祝
The family celebrating as well
这是鲁道夫·德保利
That was Rodolfo de Pauly
和阿里尔·塞诺辛
and Ariel Senociin
为我们做这些
doing that for us
你能想象我们现在为阿根廷做了什么吗?
Can you imagine what we're doing for Argentina now?
你懂我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
屠杀，粉丝，夏天
Carnage, fans, summer
然后我认为其中一个目标
and then I think one of the goals
在比赛中
of the tournament
这个目标有很多伟大的作品
There's so many great pieces to this goal
这是阿根廷的一个伟大的团队进球
it's a great team goal from Argentina
第一个
First
他们赶出
they dispossess
欠薪，很好的掩护
and back pay, great cover in there
但我想让你看看我们的经理
but here I want you to have a look at the manager
看着他，站起来，挤
look at him, get up, squeeze
直接挤戏，他们就是这么做的
squeeze the play straight away, they do that
他们强迫他们翻车
they force a turn over
这是一个非常棒的第一次球
it's a fantastic first time ball into
对梅西
to Messi
一个漂亮的转弯处触球
a great touch round the corner
这是关于决策的
and then this is about decision making
把握时机，然后保持冷静
timing and then composure
迪玛利亚完成得很好
great finish from Di Maria
我认为他是上半场比赛中表现最好的球员
I think he's been the best player on the pitch in that first half
然后这就是
and then this is just
锁匠，梅西本人
the locksmith, Messi himself
华丽的
magnificent
传球，移动，完美
passing, moving, perfection
这个目标是
that goal is
构筑得很好
great build up
迪玛利亚，那球可不容易
and Di Maria, that wasn't easy ball
只是有点运气而已
it was just a bit of luck
梅西的天才
the genius of Messi
麦卡利斯特的愿景
the vision of McAllister
用天使收尾
finishing with an angel
阿根廷的中场
that midfield of Argentina
一直都很好
have been really good
他们一直打得很好
they've been playing so so well
如果你认为
well if you think
阿根廷
the Argentine
解说员对第一个解说感到兴奋
commentators got excited with the first commentary
听听这个
have a listen to this one
GOOOOOO
他将是第二个
he's going to be the second one
在演播室
on the studio
就是他
that was him
我想他会说那是个进球
I think he's going to say it was a goal
而且是非常好的一个
and a very good one
很棒的东西，你们都谈到了它的重要性
fabulous stuff, you all talked about the importance
以及迪玛利亚的重要性
and the significance of Di Maria
以及他被赋予的角色
and the role he's been given obviously
由教练
by the coach
斯科洛尼，他带来了很大的改变
Scoloni and he's made such a difference
在这场比赛中，美国杯决赛
in this game, the cup of America finals
是啊，上半场真是火极了
yeah it's been on fire in the first half
这方面最好的选手之一
one of the best player on that
我这么说
pitch and I say that
以前他有多重要
before how important he is
因为他在运球
for that scene because he's dribbling
能力依然存在
ability is still there
他是最好的之一
he's one of the best
他付钱，当你拿到球的时候
he pays and when you get the ball
你总是让球员上场
you always take players on
他是一个伟大的球员
and he's such a great player
他不年轻，长得很像
he's not young, he's very similar
给梅西，但他仍然
to Messi but he's still
尽自己最大的努力
performing his best
他给了他们一个律法时间
he's given them a Torah time down that
这边，这是
side and this is
典型的阿根廷
typical of what Argentina
一直做得这么好的方面是什么
have been doing so well in terms of
把球弄回
getting that ball back at the
最早的机会
earliest opportunity
这是另一个好机会
and that's another good chance
但这都是因为他们赢了那个球
but it's all because of them winning that ball
在中场的关键位置
in those key positions in midfielder
我们已经展示过一次了
and we've already showed that once there
有处罚
with a penalty
当他欺骗他的时候，不是吗?
when he fools him doesn't he?
当他不上场时，我们看了阿根廷队的比赛
we watched Argentina play when he didn't play
梅西得到了球
and Messi gets the ball
他们没有那么一点魔力
they haven't got that little bit of magic
他加了一点额外的香料
he adds that extra bit of spice
他坐上了这条船的尾部
and he got on the end of this one
而是他画的次数
but the amount of times he just draws
一两个球员不在位置上
one and two players out of position
让梅西这样的人得到解放
that frees up someone like Messi
我认为他给球队带来了不一样的平衡
I think he adds such a different balance to this team
他们完全占据了统治地位
they've just been totally dominant
在每一个位置
in every single position
我的意思是，法国队还没有接触过阿根廷的禁区
I mean France have not had a touch in Argentina's box
一点也不
not a touch
难以置信的真
incredible really
梅西，他显然打进了点球
Messi he scored his penalty obviously
再加上一些魔法，他就进化了
and a couple of bits of magic and he's evolved
第二个进球也是如此
in the second goal as well
你知道
you know
他赢得了一切
he's won everything
他可以把靴子穿上
he could just put his boots up
把它们挂起来，说声谢谢
hang them up and just say thanks
但即使球的重量在那里传递
but even that the ball the weight of that pass there
人们有时会说你太过分了
and people sometimes say you go over the top
但他让这些事情看起来很简单
but these things he makes them look easy
但事实并非如此
but they're not
普通玩家在这些方面大多是错误的
the normal players get most of these things wrong
通常情况下，他会让这看起来像
on a regular basis he makes this look like
这只是他日常生活的一部分
he's just part of his normal day doing this
但这是一件困难的事情
but it is difficult stuff
他是一名非凡的足球运动员
he's just a phenomenal footballer
我在你去体育馆之前说过
I've said this before you go to a stadium
当他演奏的时候
when he plays
10分满分，它很棒
10 out of 10 it's great
但如果他打了6分
but if he plays a 6 out of 10
你还是带着东西离开体育馆
you still leave the stadium with something
你做了别人做不到的事
you've done something that no one else can do
我很惊讶他能有这么大的空间
I'm amazed the space that he's being able to
发现自己
find himself
你可以看到10到15码内没有人
I mean you can see look there's no one within 10 or 15 yards
他的
of him
法国离它很远
France are miles off it
巴普尔没有追回来
and Bapé doesn't chase back
他们显然和其他球队一样
they've obviously like other teams in this tournament
已经认识到
have recognised that
这也是梅西喜欢踢的地方
and that's an area Messi likes to play in anyway
他更像是一个玩家
he's more like a player
他的位置很好
he's in good positions
拿起球，他就
get on the ball and he's just
从那里运球进攻
dribbling all bashing from there
我是说你不能给予
I mean you can't give
有人有这么长的空间吗
anyone that amount of space that long
梅西是本届杯赛的最佳球员
Messi the player of the tournament
问题是尽管他们是免费对抗
the issue is though they're playing free against
5在那里
5 in there
他们在中场有4人，梅西就像一个多余的替补球员
they've got 4 across the midfield and Messi drops in as that extra spare player
所以他们有2个人空闲
so they've got 2 players spare
你给了他这样的人空间和时间
and you're giving someone like him space and time
这是自杀
it's suicidal
他们做了双重替换，艾伦
they've made a double substitution Alan
你知道
you know
看起来我们有他在看的照片
it looks like well we've got pictures of him looking
让我们说有点沮丧吧
let's say a tad frustrated
如你所料
as you'd expect
完全可以理解
totally understandable
他对自己和团队的表现很生气
he's angry with his and his team's performance
它们需要能量
they need energy
这对前锋来说并不容易，不是吗
it's not easy for a striker though is it
当你的球队被完全控制的时候
when your team's being completely dominated
他很难坚持下去
it's very difficult for him to press
因为他做不到
because he can't do that
很多时候
a lot of the time
而巴普尔不会经常这么做
and Bapé won't do that a lot of the time
这就是他们和那个团队的问题所在
and that's been the problem for them and that team
是他们坐得太远了吗
is that they've sat too far off
他们控制着
and they're controlling
这正是前半部分发生的事情
and that's exactly what's happened in the first half
当你被拖走的时候，你是这样评价的吗
when you used to get dragged off did you used to rate it like that
我从来没有被拖走
I never got dragged off
你不礼貌地漏掉了一个
you left out one so by rude
我们先不说这个
let's leave that
这确实让他丢了工作
it did cost him his job
想要预览一下吗?
Fancy a sneak preview
对来年的展望
of what next year holds in store
在iPlay
on iPlay
在一起
together
我们点燃炉火
we light the fire
欢迎来到凡尔赛宫
welcome to Versailles
我们在找六个强盗
we're looking for six robbers
还有三吨黄金
and three tons of gold
现在发生了很多事，但这非常
there is a lot going on right now but this is very
兴奋
excited
让我们展望未来
let's look to the future
你知道这很危险，对吧
you do know this could be dangerous don't you
我不会承认我没做过的事
I am not confessing to something that I didn't do
我值得有所作为
I deserve to be something
我只是对我所看到的感到敬畏
I am just in awe of what I am seeing
那我们最好开始吧
well then we best get started
2023年新功能
new for 2023
在BBC iPlayer上播放
on BBC iPlayer
莱昂内尔·梅西的纪录片
the Lionel Messie documentary
还可以在iPlayer上下载吗
is also still available on iPlayer
我想现在可能会有更多的浏览量
I think it might get a few more views now
年度体育人物
sports personality of the year
将于周三举行
takes place on Wednesday
BBC七点差一刻
BBC one quarter to seven
周三晚些时候请注意
later on Wednesday look out for
欧洲冠军
the champions of Europe
bbc1040
BBC one 1040
一个星期后我们会回来
we'll be back a week tomorrow with
每日比赛
match of the day
节礼日BBC 1台1050
boxing day BBC one 1050
疯狂的
bonkers
这真的是
this really is
在新一季之前
before the new series
开始看所有剧集
starts watch all episodes
《窝打老道》在BBC iPlayer播放
of Waterloo Road on BBC iPlayer
玩家几分钟后就会回来
players will be back out in just a few minutes
所以当这两支球队在俄罗斯相遇时
so when these two teams met in Russia
四年前，基利安·姆巴佩
four years ago Kylian Mbappe had a
中场休息时的特别任务
special mission at half time
前法国新闻官菲利普
former France press officer Philippe
图安接了这个故事
Touran picks up the story
当他还是孩子的时候，他有梅西的海报
when he was a kid he had messi posters
在他房间里
in his room
在对阵阿根廷的比赛之前
before the match against Argentina
他说
he said
我要梅西，我绝对要梅西
I have to messi, I absolutely have to messi
中场休息时
and at half time
他甚至没有料到比赛会结束
he hadn't even expected the end of the match
中场休息时我们遇到了麻烦
at half time we were in trouble
他脑子里有东西
he had his stuff in his head
他去看梅西了
he went to see messi
他有一个梅西
he had a messi
在比赛结束时
and at the end of the match
他自拍了一张
he took a selfie
然后寄给了他爸爸
and he sent it to his dad
向他展示梅西
to show him the messi
梅西
messi
我想知道我们是否要弄脏他的衬衫
I wonder if we have to mess his shirt
在这个游戏的最后
at the end of this game
你交换过衬衫吗
have you ever swapped shirts
你不会在中场休息的时候做的
you wouldn't do it at half time
你们在中场休息时换了衣服吗?
have you swapped shirts at half time?
不，你不会那么做的
no you wouldn't do that
如果是马拉多纳的话我会的
I would if it was kind of Maradona
真希望我1986年就做了
I wish I had it done in 1986
比拉尔多对此很生气
Bilardo was mad about this
记住阿根廷的文化
remember the culture of Argentina
比拉尔?
Bilardo?
也许是因为他想要
maybe because he wanted it
他知道它值750万
he knew it would be worth 75 million
不管它是多少英镑
pounds whatever it was
史蒂夫·霍奇，祝他好运
for Steve Hodge good luck to him
几年后
a few years later
你的衬衫收藏真不错
you've got quite a good collection of shirts
是的，很好的衬衫收藏
yeah a good collection of shirts
尤其是歌曲播放器
especially the song player
我选中间的
I choose the mid
你可以在那里放一张照片
you could have a picture there
那是我
that's me
这是第一场加泰罗尼亚德比
there was the first Catalan derby
我们在巴塞罗那的比赛
that we played in Barcelona
然后
and then
比拉尔多穿19号球衣
Bilardo was wearing number at 19
在那一刻
at that moment
这真的很酷
that's really cool
我搬回了西班牙
I moved back to Spain
我完成了我的帽子
and I finished my hat
他身上满是衬衫
and he was full of shirts
装在盒子里之类的
in boxes and all that
我认为这是件好事
and I think that's always good to have
一个家和博物馆
a home and a museum
和所有的衬衫
with all the shirts
里奥，你们交换过衬衫吗
Rio did you ever swap shirts
那是你的癖好吗?
was that a thing for you?
我可能做得不够多
I didn't do as much as I probably did
我觉得我应该多做点
I think now I should have done it more
我有一些不错的
I've got some good ones
里瓦尔多
Rivaldo
它们是我最喜欢的两个
they're my two favourites
我真的没有一件衬衫
I don't really have one shirt
足球已经发生了变化
things have changed in football
没人想要你的，这就是原因
no one wanted yours that's why
我确实在比赛结束时换了衣服
I did swap shirts at the end of that game
我想是鲁杰里
I think with Ruggieri
你还记得阿根廷队的中卫吧
you remember the centre half that played for Argentina
他最近以10美元的价格卖掉了它
he sold it recently for a tenner
真的吗?
really?
一点小新闻
a little bit of news
英国简介
briefly about England
英足总已经确认
the FA have confirmed
加里·索利斯盖特会继续留任
that Garry Salisgate will stay on
作为英格兰队主教练
as England manager
他在上周的四分之一决赛后说
he said after last week's quarterfinal
他被法国打败了，所以他会慢慢来
defeat to France that he would take his time
在对他的未来做出决定之前
before making a decision over his future
现在我们来看看欧元
so we've gone now to the Euros
下半场时间到了
it's time for the second half
有梅西
there's Messi
他的亲密
he's close
你的评论
your commentators
杰曼·朱尼斯和盖伊·莫里
Germain Junis and Guy Mowry
谢谢你，加里
thank you Garry
我们将尽我们最大的努力
we will do our level best
来匹配我们的水平
to match the levels of our
联赛上半场
league in the first half
我很想尝试一下吹球
I'd love to have a go at a goal call
就像那样一次
like that just once
也许不是
maybe not
我们把衬衫换回去了
we've swapped shirts back
杰曼的不适合我
Germain's didn't fit me
我们都准备好了看看阿根廷是否
and we're all set to see if Argentina
可以继续
can continue
他们在前45分钟停在哪里
where they're left off in the first 45 minutes
也许更重要的是给我们
and perhaps more importantly to give us
一个合适的场面来看看法国
a proper spectacle to see if France
能唤醒自己
can rouse themselves
并达到之前的高度
and hit their previous heights
没有进一步的更改
no further changes made
在中场休息时
during the half-time break
所以就做了这两个改变
so just those two changes that were made
上半场快结束了
towards the end of the first half
迪迪埃·德尚
by Didier Deschamps
他没有
he was not
闲逛
hanging around
迪马利亚
Di Maria
工作室是对的
the studio were right
他们在歌颂他
they're singing his praises
在半场
at half-time
不仅是他的，而且
not only his but
经理因为
the manager because
他马上就发现了这一点
he spotted straight away that
左边那个人
whoever on that left-hand side
似乎是个策略
seemed to be a ploy
在最初的45分钟里，它确实奏效了
it's definitely worked in that first 45 minutes
稍微往下一蘸，够到球
little dip to get to the ball
阿尔瓦雷斯会再来一次的
Alvarez who will get to it again
保罗
to Paul
回到费尔南德斯身边
back with Fernandez
拉里斯不得不来取
and Larisse had to come and get it
他来的有点晚
and he came and got it a little belatedly
但至少他做到了
but at least he got there
我想他差点就停下了
I think he almost stops his run
我在照片上看不出来
I can't really see it in those pictures
但是他在
but he was in
这个已经过时了
and that one's out
热烈欢呼
to a huge cheer
来自阿根廷的支持者
from those Argentina supporters
这颗恒星
the star
迪迪埃·德尚想要的
Didier Deschamps would have wanted
在我确信是一些之后
after what I'm sure was some
半场谈话
conversations at half-time
45分钟，他的法国队
45 minutes his French side
他们在为自己的生命而战
they're in the game of their lives
试图找到一些东西
trying to find something
有
there's been
BBC iPlayer上的一个节目叫
a program on BBC iPlayer called
如何赢得世界杯
how to win the World Cup
我们从中瞥见了
in which we got a glimpse of
迪迪埃·德尚
some of the ways in which Didier Deschamps
对他的球员进行集体演讲
speaks to his players as a group
就像我们看到的那样
and as we have seen in that
他说话不拐弯抹角
he doesn't mince his words
只是这些词
just whether those words
能在45分钟内生效吗
can have effect now in the next 45 minutes
我们在前半部分看到的
and what we saw in the first half
它必须相当清楚
it must be reasonably clear
不管那是什么虫子
that whatever it was the bug
穿过了法国队的帽子
that went through the France cap
这对他们产生了某种影响
it's had some sort of effect on them
现在它显然是一种能量
right now it's clearly an energy
问题
issue
就是走不动了
just can't get going
期待麦卡纳
look forward to Mccana
马丁内斯说交给我吧
Martinez says leave that to me
节礼日被提及
Boxing Day was mentioned
他将为阿斯顿维拉效力
he'll be an action for Aston Villa
对利物浦
against Liverpool
我们认为
we think
他可能会再请几天假
he might be extended leave for a few
阿尔瓦雷斯会打败他的
Alvarez will beat him
这将是一场法国式的投掷
and it will be a France throw
在
in
这次轮到阿根廷了
this one goes to Argentina's way
法国不败
France unbeaten
以及他们最近的10场世界杯比赛
and their last 10 World Cup matches
对阵南美球队
against South American sides
那是在阿根廷举行的世界杯
since the World Cup that was in Argentina
1978年
in 1978
当他们输给东道主的时候
when they lost to the hosts
那是很久以前的事了
it's been a long time ago
意大利人直接进来了
Taliafico straight in
挑战
to challenge
Colomuani
在帮助下
and again with assistance
来自迪玛利亚
from Di Maria
法国现在有了昆达
France have it now with Kunda
格列兹曼让它运行
Griezmann was letting it run
克里斯蒂安·罗梅罗不让
Cristian Romero was not letting
还有人接近过吗
anybody else get anywhere near that
这是迪玛利亚
and here's Di Maria
德保罗想在另一边结束
DePaul wants it over on the other side
德保罗
DePaul
技术很好
technique was good
直接对着卢里兹
just straight at Luriz
搬家的一切都很好
everything about the move was good
只要他们赢了
as soon as they win it
它们就在你身上
they're just on you
巴菲克可能得自己做了
and Bafek might have to do this on his own
Griezmann
不转移
doesn't deflect
Colomuani的方式
Colomuani's way
艾米·马丁内斯的方式
the way of Emi Martinez
是
is
的方式
the way of
Colomuani
和
and
莫利纳
Molina
Griezmann
早春作物
Rabia
来自德保罗的整洁
Neat from DePaul
小声点好吗
does well to keep it down
那是犯规吗
Is that a foul throw
阿根廷现在要把球扔回去
Argentina is to throw it back in now
我想可能是吧
I think it might have been
在如此高的水平上
at such a lofty level
这是一个星期天的比赛
it is a Sunday game
但
but
秋天结束
autumn ending
一般
the general
阿根廷队的后卫
at the back for Argentina
这是一场怎样的比赛啊
what a match in which to bring up
一个世纪的出现
a century of appearances
为了他的国家
for his country
不过我犯了个错误
made a mistake there though
Colomuani很快就发现了他
Colomuani was quickly in on him
看看这个
look at that
我想他在角落里，不是吗
I think he's got the corner hasn't he
他也做得很好，拿到了这个弯角
he's done really well to get the corner as well
我觉得是费尔南德斯在支持他的人
I think it was Fernandez backing up his man
秋天结束了你犯的错误
autumn ending you made the mistake
它在法国的那一头
and it's at the France end
尽管如此
such as it is
Griezmann
和马丁内斯
and Martinez
让它看起来好像是最简单的工作
makes that look as though it is the easiest job
在这个世界上
in the world
他们接受得很好
they took it well
我得回法国
need to get back France
早春作物
Rabia
那是一个漂亮的铲球
that's a good tackle
特奥·埃尔南德斯阻止了德保罗
Teo Hernandez stops DePaul
送出球却不能守住球
from delivering but can't then keep the ball
在后来
in afterwards
他希望和他一起
he's hoping along with his
受伤的卢卡斯兄弟
injured brother Lucas
他在队里的位置是谁
who's placed he took in the team after the
在对阵澳大利亚的第一场比赛中
well during the first game against Australia
成为第三对获胜的兄弟
to be the third set of brothers to win
一起参加世界杯，但看起来
the World Cup together but it looks
此刻，这是一个渺茫的希望
a forlorn hope just at the moment
继瓦尔塔之后，奥斯曼
following the Valtas, Ottmar
1954年和弗里茨
and Fritz in 1954
当然还有贾丁家
and the Jardins of course
阿根廷的角落
Argentina corner
而且一点也不着急
and not in any great rush about it
即使在这个相对较早的下半场
even at this relatively early second half
阶段
stage
他们不会的
they won't be
试图控制他的下半场
trying to manage his second half
慢慢来
taking their time
分手
breaking it up
不让它进入任何类型的节奏
not allowing it to get into any type of rhythm
在这一点上，做适合你的事情就好
just do what suits you at this point
拉比亚紧随其后
being followed by Rabia
早春作物
Rabia
它来自梅西，卡里斯曼驻扎
it comes from Messi, Karisman was stationed
他想找到那个近柱
he's trying to find that near post
梅西显然是想制造点什么
Messi obviously trying to set something up
有几次他
there's a couple of times that he's
向那里开了一枪，那里已经清空了
fired one into there that's been cleared
格列兹曼在上半场破门
by Griezmann in the first half
由Giroud
by Giroud
我想要很久以后
I think it would be long before
他只是在耳边说了句话
he just has a word in the ear
让梅西转告他的队友
of Messi to tell him to tell his teammates
快一点
to hurry up a bit
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
和奥托门迪一起回来
back with Ottomendi
离目标还远着呢，马丁内斯
a long way from goal there, Martinez
他把它搞得很成功
and he's made a real hatch of it
我想多参与一点
wanted to get involved a bit more
我认为当你开始时你所承担的风险
I think the risks that you take when you start
让游戏慢下来
to kind of like slow the game down already
阿根廷确实需要继续做他们正在做的事情
Argentina does need to keep doing what they were doing
只要保持比赛的强度
just keep the intensity in the game
继续施压，把球赢回来
keep pressing, keep winning that ball back
埃尔南德斯
Hernandez
球
the ball
又是罗德里戈·德·保罗
Rodrigo de Paul again
他被伸出来的人拦住了
and he's been stopped by the outstretched
阿德里安·拉比亚的腿
leg of Adrian Rabia
他会得到一张黄牌
and he's going to get a yellow card
他说他拿到球了
he's saying he got the ball
我不确定你有没有
I'm not sure you did
没办法听到
there's no way to hear it
不，糟糕的挑战
no, bad challenge
他只是有点像尼克
he's just got a little nick of it
但这还不够，没关系
but not enough, that's no matter
还是保罗说了算
still down to Paul
马德里竞技的罗德里戈·德·保罗
Rodrigo de Paul of Atletico Madrid
谁做了这么无私的事
who has done so much unselfish
在世界杯决赛期间跑步
running during this World Cup finals
他们不会想让他爆炸的
they won't want him to go off
我们刚才看到的那个人
the man we've just seen there
丽珊德拉·马丁内斯
flexing his knee, Lisandra Martinez
你说你希望
you were saying you'd expect
65 - 70分钟
65-70 minutes
埃尔卡可能会在70英里后转到5英里
potentially Eierka go to a five after 70
我们知道斯科尼喜欢这么做
we know that Sconely likes to do that
《肮脏的铲球》，你知道，我看得越多
so Nasty Tackle you know, the more I look at that
拉比奥可能扭伤了脚踝
from Rabio probably rolled his ankle
剩下一个
that left one
对克罗地亚的比赛他就是这么做的
but yeah it's what he did against Croatia
在半决赛中，他们有过这样的经历
in the semifinal once they had that
作为第三个目标的缓冲
kind of buffer of the third goal
马丁内斯上场了
Martinez came on
我想是帕雷德斯
I think it was Paredes
在那场比赛中，他们在中场发挥失常
they took off in midfield in that game
保罗是正直的
Paul is upright
并将继续
and will continue
他们也会的
so will they
Ramira
法国队会得到一个任意球吗
will be a free kick for France
有一些
there is some
一些人仍对他们抱有希望
some hope still in this for them
塔利亚·菲科要处理的问题是什么
was Talia Fico getting to grips with
可乐Moani
Cola Moani
法国队必须把球传给他们的10号
France must get the ball to their number ten
比他们之前接近的要多得多
a whole lot more than they've been even close
在游戏中做什么
to doing in the game
当他们这样的时候很难
it's difficult when they're so
他们在游戏中很被动
passive in their play
格列兹曼在这里冒险前进给了昆德另一个选择
Griezmann's venturing forward here to give Kunde another option
迪玛利亚的假幻灯片
a fake slide from Di Maria
可乐Moani
Cola Moani
在他威胁要进入禁区时被拦截
stopped as he threatened to enter the penalty area
这个挑战是
the challenge that was
塔里亚菲科
Talia Fico
完全投入
fully committed
Kunde
可乐莫阿尼，触屏
Cola Moani with the touch back
拉比奥甚至可以追溯到瓦兰
Rabio even further back to Varan
瓦兰要回去了
Varan is going to have to go all the way back
因为朱利安·阿尔瓦雷斯施加了压力
because of the pressure that was applied by Julian Alvarez
和安逸猿
and Bapé
打不过第一个吗
can't beat the first in the chain
是费尔南德斯
it was Fernandez
格列兹曼回击梅西
Griezmann back at Messi
哨子已经消失了
the whistle's already gone for
之前的挑战
the previous challenge
如果我们去看保罗，他在这里有点应付
if we go to Paul, he's coping a bit here
我想是巴普尔
I think it was Bapé just
我觉得他有点失去理智了
I think he's lost his head a little bit here
只是感到沮丧，踢出去
just getting frustrated, kicks out
保罗承认这一点
Paul, he acknowledges it though
他举起手
holds his hand up
无法理解这种挫败感
can't understand the frustration
他没有踢过球
he's not had a kick
一点点
a little bit of
Lennist胭脂
Lennist Rouge
我认为他将不得不关注中场
I think he's going to have to look at that midfield
迪迪埃德尚
Didier Deschamps
Intramenny Rabio
Griezmann
这对他们来说太困难了
it's been so difficult for them in there
Kunde
迪马利亚
Di Maria
优势信号
advantage is signalled
有阿尔瓦雷斯
there's Alvarez
拉里斯觉得他必须下来
and Larisse felt that he had to get down
在那个岗位上
at that post
他不确定
he wasn't sure
不管它是不是偷偷溜进去的
whether it was sneaking inside or not
但这总是很艰难的
it's always going to be tough though
从那个角度打败拉里斯
from that angle to beat Larisse
为外面的世界而战
down for the outside
下来
down
巴普尔朝他走来
up towards him Bapé
当然越位了，现在旗子升起来了
surely offside and the flag is now raised
很多，即使不是越位
many, even if it's not offside
他要拿那个做什么
what's he supposed to do with that
Kunde
蒂娜在找迪玛丽亚
Tina's seeking out Di Maria
昆德跳得有点早，但是
Kunde jumped a little early but
抓住他的跳跃
held his leap
迪马利亚
Di Maria
迪玛利亚正在生孩子
Di Maria is slarling
在路上
on his way
在Kunde
at Kunde
这是一个可爱的球
it's a lovely ball
这球控制得很好，但终点偏远
it's brilliant control but the finish is wide
从梅西
from Messi
我认为拉比奥的铲球很棒
Big tackle I think from Rabio
我觉得他在梅西进球前得到了一些东西
I think he just gets something on this before Messi strikes it
迪玛利亚又干得漂亮
brilliant from Di Maria again
我们来看看他要打这个的时候
but let's have a look as he's about to strike this
梅西有
Messi there
拉比奥的小妙招
little touch from Rabio
到他
onto him
这就是为什么它会传播得很广
that's why it goes wide
重要的拦截
vital interception
阿德里安·拉比奥
from Adrian Rabio
这可能会让
that might just keep
法国在其中
France in it
每次迪玛利亚来参加舞会
every time Di Maria comes to the ball
这个球上了，这支球队就活过来了
this gets on the ball this team does come to life
朱尔斯Kunde
Jules Kunde
真的是中心错位吗
is a centre off really
右后卫
playing right back
一个炎热的夜晚
a torrid, torrid evening
那是阿尔瓦雷斯
that was Alvarez
倒车导致碰撞
backing in and causing the collision
维兰和图阿·马内之间
between Veran and Tua Mane
他知道自己在做什么
he knew what he was doing there
我想更重要的是着陆
I think it's more the landing there
特奥·埃尔南德斯失去了理智
Teo Hernandez has lost it
他一直不太会守住这一切
he hasn't been very good at keeping it all much
你在观察，想要找到
you're watching and you're trying to find
积极的事
something positive
在这个正面，但那里什么都没有
within this frontside but there's just nothing there
甚至肢体语言
the body language even
只是
is just
那一刻，我几乎接受了失败
almost accepting of defeat at the minute
这是他们的方式
that's gone their way
很快，阿尔瓦雷斯又出现了
quickly Alvarez was there again
让它更尴尬
to make it more awkward
也许比看起来的要多，这些数字很能说明问题，不是吗
than it perhaps looked and those are telling numbers aren't they
他是无情的
he's relentless
看看法国的数据，什么都没有
look at those French figures, nothing
右边一列没有
nothing in the right hand column
尝试进球，但没有击中目标
attempts on goal and nothing on target
泰奥·拉姆发现了油脂
Teo Ram finds greasement
这是一个舒适的头球
it's a comfortable header away
还有第三个
and there were the third
从热刺
from Spurs
参加世界杯决赛
to play in a World Cup final
后
following
雨果·洛里斯和
Hugo Lloris and
20年前，克里斯蒂安·齐格
20 years ago Christian Zieger
德国的
of Germany
麦卡利斯特
McAllister
梅西
Messi
阿尔瓦雷斯进了球
Alvarez plays it in
洛里斯在那里铲球
Lloris gets there with the tackle
麦卡利斯特左击重拳
McAllister left thumping the pitch
在沮丧中
in frustration
greasement
任意球法国队在那里
free kick France there
塔利亚·菲科的挑战
Talia Fico's challenge
他们只是没有搞错
they're just not getting it wrong
每分钟都有他们的通行证
at the minute with their passes
阿根廷
Argentina
正好穿过法国
just cutting through France
梅西的球太容易了
so easy the ball from Messi's spot on
你认为麦卡利斯特能做到
and you think McAllister's going to get there
在背后轻推一下
a bit of a nudge in the back
就在街角
going up on the corner
但却逃脱了惩罚
but gets away with it
就像《拉比奥》里那样
looks like that from Rabiot
格里兹曼想要回它
Griezmann wants it back
拉比奥到舒尔曼
Rabiot to Schuermain
可能是现在
it may be now
法国可以问一两个问题
France can ask a question or two
Kunde
把它藏在里面
kept it in
不，他没有
no he didn't
我想了一下
took a bit of thinking about
它
it
就靠在麦卡利斯特身上
just there just leans on McAllister
不过他戴着它很可爱
he's cute with it though
他不太明显，所以他侥幸逃脱了
he's not too obvious so he just gets away with it
能轻易得到吗
could have easily been given
就像并排在一起一样
it's as close to side by side
肩并肩，尽你所能
and shoulder to shoulder as you can get
合法
legally
安吉尔·迪·玛利亚要爆炸了
Angel Di Maria is going off
他并不是每场比赛都首发
he's not started every game at this tournament
因为他一直受到腿筋的困扰
because he has been troubled by hamstring
本季问题
problems this season
他在尤文图斯的比赛中出场次数并不多
hasn't played too many times to Juventus
但他今天为阿根廷队效力了
but boy has he played for Argentina today
他一直都很棒
he has been terrific
真的发挥了他的作用
really has played his part
完美
to perfection
举起一枪
and raised a shot
在他的左手边
around his left hand side
引起了
has caused
法国一个接一个的问题
France problem after problem
并受到英雄们的欢迎
and getting the heroes welcome
他的队友也理应如此
by his teammates and rightly so
他的一个队员来了
one of his players comes
马科斯Acunha
Marcos Acunha
从左后卫或左翼后卫开始
started at left back or left wing back
在比赛中，但更多的是作为一个
in the tournament but it's more as an
正统左翼来帮助塔利亚·菲科
orthodox left winger to help Talia Fico
必要的时候也可以出去
out as well when needs be
这是来自西班牙塞维利亚的球员
there is the player from Sevilla in Spain
发现麦卡利斯特
finding McAllister
他通过了
he's got through
梅西
Messi
麦卡利斯特
McAllister
和寿曼在正确的地方
and Shoumane in the right place
塔里亚菲科
Talia Fico
击中了昆德的手
and that hit the hand of Kunde
他认为没有
he doesn't think there was
有什么故意的吗?
anything deliberate in that
他给了法国队一个进球
and he gives a goal kick for France
是他的胳膊吗?
does it his arm
试着把它弄出来
trying to get it out of the way
那里有一具尸体突然转向
a body swerve there
对于梅西
for Messi
扔了两个
throws two of them
所有的掌声都会消失
all the plaudits will go
像梅西和迪玛利亚这样的球员
to the likes of Messi and Di Maria
但我对麦卡利斯特也印象深刻
but been so impressed with McAllister as well
在中场
in midfield
他打了一场精彩的比赛
he's had a brilliant game
最伟大的球员
greatest in the game can have
了晚上
off nights
当他们真的不想要的时候
when they really don't want one
不禁想起20年前
can't help but think of 20 years ago
罗纳尔多，这是他的球队
Ronaldo it's his team
你也不能一个人去做
as well you can't do it on his own
团队没有发挥作用
the team is not functioning
当梅西24年前离开的时候
when Messi's out 24 years ago
20年前他很棒
20 years ago he was terrific
这是一点粗心大意
it's a little bit of carelessness
悄悄溜进了阿根廷的比赛
creeping into Argentina's play
有时
at times
就在对面
right the way across
没有再触球，好球
with no further touches great ball
Kunde
不是一个很好的球
not such a great ball
Talia Fico再次报道
Talia Fico is there again
向哥伦比亚施压
putting the pressure by Colomuani
他改变了世界，哥伦比亚
he's made a difference Colomuani
他一直是那个
he's been the one that
他似乎很有天赋
seems to have it in him
回到卢尔德
back to Lourdes
他一直在精力充沛地战斗
energetic he's been fighting
Griezmann
这是一个不错的组合
it's a decent combination
近球是有意为之
nearly ball was intended for
德黑兰
Tehran
在奥托门迪的身后
turned behind by Ottomendi
法国队只赢了几个
France corner just a few
早期迹象表明弗朗西亚
little early signs that Francia
做点什么让这些涓涓细流
doing something to make those trickle
进球后似乎多了一点
behind the goal seem a little bit more
而不是涓涓细流
than a trickle
我已经习惯了从弗朗西亚那里看到什么
what's been used to seeing from Francia
球进禁区打得好
balls into the box good play down
左手边
that left hand side
这就是他们需要的
that's what they need
但不会再有一个角落了
won't get another corner though
射门阿根廷
goal kick Argentina
还有一点之后
and a little bit of afters
拉米罗一直很想参与
Ramiro involved he's been keen to
在整场比赛中留下他的印记
make his mark all game
他应该做得更好，他在那里
he should do better he's there
看着它掉下来
watches it all the way it comes off
他的肩膀
his shoulder
看看他的右肩
look right off his right shoulder
这是最接近机会的事了
it's the closest thing to a chance
很有可能
yeah big chance that
更多的变化
more changes
另一个人
another who has been
身体不适
under the weather
爱德华多·卡文加是最年轻的球员
and Eduardo Camvinga youngest player
在法国队
in the French squad
只玩了一个游戏
played just the one game
在比赛中，就是那时
at the tournament and that was when
迪迪埃·德尚为
Didier Deschamps altered things for
最后一场小组赛对阵突尼斯
the final group game against Tunisia
当他们已经通过了
when they were already through
他们输掉了那场比赛，表现不佳
and they lost that one and didn't perform
这是早春作物
there's Rabia
格列兹曼和巴普尔搬家了
Griezmann and Bapé had moved
内部
inside
现在轮到卡利斯特了
now Calister with the touch
回来
back
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
梅西
Messi
Kunde
加上昆德
combined with a Kunde
昆德再次拥有了它
Kunde has it once more
给定球
and ball given
对费尔南德斯
against Fernandez
法国想做两个改变
France wanted to make two changes
但是球员们决定了
but the players out there decided the
最好的办法就是继续干下去
best course of action was to get on with
的事情
things
拉米罗也很懒
and there was Ramiro to rather lazily
和
and
轻轻拂去
easily stroke it away
继续播放，因为有一点提升
played on because there's a little bit of a lift
在他们的表演中
in their performances
我只是想顺势而为
just trying to ride this little wave
只是把球借给了我
just lent on to the ball
然后
and then
懦夫越过球确保没人
coward over the ball to make sure nobody
能接近它吗
could get anywhere near it
Kunde
罗曼和卡莫文杰还在等待
Roman and Kamovinger still await
他们把
their turns
高度不够
not enough height on that
为拉米罗洗脱罪名
to clear Ramiro
早春作物
Rabia
还剩20分钟
still 20 minutes left of this
加上添加的东西
plus whatever's added
和安逸猿
and Bapé
和巴普尔一起抓拍
and Bapé with the snap shot
只是有点太投入了
just a little too much into it
还是从
better though again from
还有巴普尔和法国
and Bapé and France
应该做得更好吗
should be doing I think a lot better
真的
with that really
只是往后靠
just leaning back
格列兹曼退出了
Griezmann has come off
特奥·埃尔南德斯也在让位
Teo Hernandez is making way as well
格列兹曼没能做到
Griezmann's not been able to
打断比赛，然后
disrupt the play and then
做他的短传，让事情发生
make his little short passes and make something happen
这是法国的代表
for France in this one
这是他整场比赛中最精彩的五分钟
the best five minutes he's had in the whole game
去格列兹曼酒吧
to go into the Griezmann
他下定决心要跳下去
and he made his mind up this jump
还剩19个
19 to go
仍然是2比0
and it's still 2-0
阿根廷
to Argentina
麦卡利斯特
McAllister
这是从阿库纳回来的
that's the return from Acuna
又是麦卡利斯特
McAllister once more
梅西
Messi
听听为亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特鼓掌吧
listen to the applause for Alexis McAllister
梅西
Messi
这是费尔南德斯
that's Fernandez
他们正在跳舞
while they're dancing now
麦卡利斯特最初
McAllister initially
丹在他的左手角
with Dan in his left hand corner
但那是进不去的
that was never going to go in though
需要更多的动力
needed much more power
那一天到来了
and the day comes
然后梅西做决定
and then Messi does decide
够了够了
enough is enough
在国际足坛
in international football
在每场比赛中
in every match
我在这场比赛中看到他的每一分钟
every minute more that I've seen him at this tournament
亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特有可能取代他
there's a case for Alexis McAllister to replace that
他的衬衫上有一个
Teo on his shirt with the one
20岁变成10岁
20 to become 10
这是一个巨大的呼喊
it's a big big shout
但是他在表演
but he's performing
现在在最大的舞台上
on the biggest stage right now
我不得不说，没有什么让我吃惊的
one surprise me either I have to say
特殊特殊才能
special special talent
乔凡尼
Giovanni
塔里亚·菲卡著
by Talia Fica
现在是他孤注一掷的时候
stage in the game now where he's just risking it all
他们几乎
they shall almost
四人在上面，搭档图兰
four up top with co-man Turan
回到科伦坡瓦尼
back there in Colomawani
早春作物
Rabia
但对麦康纳来说
but for McCona
好了看
well watched
精彩的预测，然后赢得了任意球
brilliantly anticipated and then winning the free kick
Christian Romero做得很棒
super work from Christian Romero
他整场比赛都做得很好
he's done that really well all game
这实际上是他比赛中最精彩的部分之一
it's one of the best parts of his game actually
只是预测事情
just anticipating things
他还故意让自己受伤
and he made sure he was going to get hurt
Giovanni写的
by Giovanni there
再也不急于起床了
no rush again to get up
有法国来的东西
there has been something from France
真的麻烦
really trouble
Leonel Scoloni的团队
Leonel Scoloni's team
剩下的东西肯定还有很多
there has to be a whole lot more in what remains
他在尽他所能
he's doing everything he can
他在下面
he's down there
向他的队员们提出劝告
remonstrating with his players
切换玩家
switching players around
他现在在问莫阿尼
he's now asking Moani
Colomawani回到右边
Colomawani to come back out to this right-hand side
图兰在左边
and Turan over to the left
这对他来说是件苦差事
it's tough work for him
确实如此
it really is
和
and
Mbappe
他们在追他
they're after him
还有罗梅罗
and there is Romero
德保罗
DePaul
比赛开始了
and the race is on here now
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
进度被上麦康纳阻碍了
progress stalled by Upper McConaugh
不能偷球
couldn't steal the ball
法国已经得到了它
France have been given it
Coman
绝望的
desperate
抓回他
grab back at him
如果有机会，可能会有一辆黄色的车
there might be a yellow car when the chance arises
他就是停不下来，是吗?
just don't stop, does he?
他一分钟前还在进攻
he's just attacking a minute ago
库恩错过了这一点
Coon has missed that
阿根廷队得到一个界外球
and a throw-in is gifted to Argentina
我认为这个想法是
I think the idea is
Shump不以为然
Shump is less than impressed
今晚所有的事情
with everything generally tonight
理应如此
rightly so
皇家级球员只是在传球
Royal class players just passing the ball
在场外，这也不是第一次了
out of play, it's not the first time either
今晚已经发生了三四次了
it's happened three or four times tonight
切线已经宣布
Tangence has been announced
这一点也不奇怪，毕竟满座了
it is no surprise at all, it is a full house
88966年
88,966
和
and
世界杯决赛的最高上座率
highest attendance at a World Cup final
自
since
94,000人涌入帕萨迪纳玫瑰碗
94,000 flocked to the Pasadena Rose Bowl
1994年
in 1994
最大的体育场，这就是原因
biggest stadium since that's why
那真是太好了
that was good that time
我认为这是有道理的
makes sense I think
梅西
Messi
德保罗又被撞了一下
DePaul took another bump
卡玛文加的一脚
from Camarvinga and then a kick
任意球阿根廷
free kick Argentina
罗德里戈·德保罗吸收了
and Rodrigo DePaul has soaked up
在这场比赛中
a whole load in this match
他一直是目标
he's been the target
他也会继续这样做
he'll keep doing this as well
每次他被踢的时候
any time he gets kicked
他会倒下的
he'll go down
顺便说一下，我和杰梅因
incidentally, myself and Jermaine
同时为今天做准备
whilst getting ourselves ready for today
我们正在看迭戈·马拉多纳的合辑
we're looking at a compilation of Diego Maradona
在开球前的网上
on the internet before the kickoff
只是为了证明他的伟大
just showing why he was a great
天哪，他绝对得到了
goodness me he got absolutely
在他的球员生涯中，他一次又一次地缺席
taken out time and again throughout his playing days
不同的游戏
different game
完全不同的游戏
completely different game
德保罗
DePaul
梅西
Messi
他也被踢得很惨
he's been kicked to fair bit too
拉里斯会帮你保管
and Larisse will hold that
但好景不长
but not for long
法国必须继续前进
France have got to get on with it
杰梅因有什么争论吗
is there an argument Jermaine to say
77分钟是什么
what is the 77 minutes played
在世界杯决赛中
in the World Cup final
他们在冒险，但还不够
they're taking risks but not enough, yeah
他们已经决定了，不是吗
they've decided aren't they
它们会让出空间
that they're going to be giving up the space
去阿根廷，看他们是否能跟上
to Argentina whether they catch them on
反击之类的
the counter attack or like that
他现在在场上有很多攻击型球员
he's got so many attacking players on the pitch now
让他们知道他们会被抓住
they show them that they're going to get caught
或者这对他们来说是有回报的，但现在
or it's going to pay off for them but at the minute
他们没有得到足够的机会
they're not offered enough
我想这个故事是关于这个游戏的
I think the story post this game
听起来会很有趣吗
is going to be an interesting one to hear
关于集中营里发生的事
about what's happened in the camp
用这个
with this
触碰赢得那一点
touch win that bit
一点也不好，他已经领先一步了
not a mend, he had the head start
但他现在被塔拉姆打败了
but he's been beaten now by Taram
一只公羊倒下了
that's a ram's down
这是一个罚分
and that's going to be a penalty
可能是一种方法
possibly a way
为了维京人为了法国
for the Vikings for France
就是这样
that was that
Colomouane
Colomouane who got
Ottomendi的黄金面
gold side of Ottomendi
它来自奥图门迪
it's poor from Ottomendi
可能是聪明的
and brilliant from possibly
这是法国队上场以来的最佳表现
France's best play since coming on the pitch
Colomouane
他应该马上处理这件事
he should have dealt with it straight away
我们提到过哥伦比亚
we mentioned about Colomouane
他在比赛中有过这样的经历
he's had that bite in his game
的侵略
that aggression
让他的团队重回正轨
that will to get his team back into it
他可能就是这么做的
and he might just have done it
这是巨大的
well this is huge
从同一个地方
from the same spot
那是阿根廷的10号
that Argentina's number 10
随便
casually
地中海为王
Cooley regally
把球放进网里
put the ball in the net
姆巴佩有机会
Kylian Mbappe has the chance
他有过一些重要的时刻，而且更多
he's had some big moments and he more
阿根廷的
Argentina's
一个会比这个大
one would be bigger than this
Mbappe
让比赛重新开始
to get the game back on
他做到了
he's done it
和法国现在
and France are now
匆匆忙忙地
in one big hurry
他说总统
and he says the president
这场比赛开始了
this game on
这是姆巴佩的杰作
and it's massive from Mbappe
他走对了路
he goes the right way
马丁内斯
Martinez
刚刚够了
just gets enough on it
把它插在底部的角落里
to stick it in that bottom corner
这就会得到
and that's going to give
这边是一些能量
this side some energy
还有15-20分钟
big big 15-20 minutes left
在这个游戏中
in this game
本届世界杯决赛再次不容放松
no relax again to this World Cup final
还记得阿根廷发生了什么吗
remember what happened to Argentina
对阵荷兰队
against the Netherlands
就在几场比赛前
just a couple of games ago
已经够了
there's been enough
对他们的伤害
injuries for them
在这个游戏中需要添加很多时间
a lot of time to be added on in this game
相信我
trust me
我们第一次看到这种程度的骚动
first time we've seen that level of agitation
莱昂内尔·斯科洛尼的情感
in the emotion of Lionel Scoloni
这就是他们一直在等待的
that's what they've been waiting for
什么，任何事，一个错误
something, anything, a mistake
他们得到了，奥托·门迪给了他们
and they got it, Otto Mendy gave it to them
他们最有经验的球员之一
one of their most experienced players
我得清理他的台词
just had to clear his lines
还有波梅卡诺
and there's a Pomecano
梅西
Messi
阿库尼亚在左边的路上
Acunha's on the way down the left
梅西也在路上
Messi's on the way there too
但他被科马抢了
but he's been robbed by Koma
有一种对法国的渴望
there's a hunger about France
一直缺失的欲望
the desire that's been missing
和Mbappe
and Mbappe
获得回报
gets the return
Okrable
Mbappe
在一瞬间
in a flash
in a heartbeat
比赛开始不到90秒
in under 90 seconds of the match
法国队在0 - 2落后的情况下反败为胜
France have come from 2-0 down
保持水平
to be level
它就在那里
and it is there
斯塔尔
Starr
在那里,10
there, 10
谁有X因素
who has the X factor
因为它的路线
for the route of it
完成了
they were finished
但是当你拥有世界级的人才
but when you've got world class talent
在你的团队中
in your team
你总是有机会的
you've always got a chance
这是耸人听闻的
and that is sensational
一个1 - 2
a 1-2
结束了
and a finish
为之而死
to die for
是梅西丢了球
it was Messi who lost the ball
跟我说说那个收尾
but talk to me about that finish
的Mbappe
of Mbappe
纯
pure
被质量所打动
struck with quality
他一击中就知道了
he knows as soon as he hits it
那是在球网后面
that's in the back of the net
他的赌注得到了回报
and his gambles paid off
世界卫冕冠军
the defending champions of the world
让自己兴奋起来
have turned themselves on
并扭转了局面
and turned this game around
3分钟前
3 minutes ago
又被拖回去了
dragged back into it again
阿根廷领先2球
Argentina 2 goals up
和巡航
and cruising
没能过线
not able to get over the line
现在他们必须有效地做到这一点
now they have to effectively
重新开始
start again
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
Acuna
Acuña
一扭一转
a twist and a turn
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
找到了麦康纳家的人
finds up a McConaugh in his way
Camovinga
哥伦比亚赢得了冠军
it was won by Colomuani
这是Taram
it's Taram
守住球，沿着触球线出发
to keep it and sets off down the touch line
他没走多远
he didn't go very far
阿根廷队又回来了
and Argentina are back to playing
他们一直在演奏，直到放慢节奏
as they were playing until they slowed it all down
能量是完全不同的
the energies that's completely different
在比赛中，情况发生了变化
in the game it shifted
这是多大的收费啊
what a charge that is
现在从塔兰和姆巴佩
from Taram and Mbappe now
寻找哥伦比亚人
looking for Colomuani
谁不能呆得足够高
who couldn't stay high enough
时间够长了
for long enough
这两个
these two
谁活过来了
who have come to life
他们是绝对的
they've been an absolute
讨厌的东西
nuisance
为法国
for France
他在两个进球上都不太对劲
he's out of the quality with the two goals
他搞得一团糟
he's done a messy
安静的
quiet
长久以来
for so long
然后是比赛中的主力
and then the main man in the match
他也超过了梅西
he's also overtaken Lionel Messi
90秒内
inside 90 seconds
参加金靴的角逐
in the race for the Golden Boot
这一切都在发生
it's all been happening
我们不要忘记
let's not forget
他赢了
he's won away
从成为史上第二名球员
from becoming only the second player ever
在世界杯决赛中上演帽子戏法
to score a hat-trick in a World Cup final
考虑到法国队的表现，这真是不可思议
it's incredible considering the game that France have had
第二个目标
that second goal
让比分变成2比2
to make it 2-2
这只是一个统计数据，今天已经不重要了
it's only a statistic it doesn't really matter today
这是阿根廷队丢的第100个球
when that's the 100th goal that Argentina have conceded
在世界杯上
in the World Cup
他们今天真的不应该丢球
they shouldn't really have conceded one today
他们无法处理物理性质
they can't deal with the physical nature
姆巴佩和塔拉姆带来的
that Mbappe and Taram have brought
放到桌子上
to the table
它也随之而去
and it goes along with it
但它们很强大
but they're powerful
这与他们对阵荷兰队时的情况类似
it was similar to when they played against the Netherlands
他们增加了一些规模
they brought on a bit of size
他们走了更长的时间
they went a bit longer
但法国的情况有所不同
but this has been different for France
一阵震惊的沉默
there's a stunned silence
往左边走
away to the left
有蓝啤酒
there is Ale Le Bleu
Le Marseillais
歌曲本从右边呼啸而出
and Songbook booming out from the right
迪迪埃·德尚又恢复了平静
and Didier Deschamps is calm again
也许他还是被赐予了圣水
maybe he was blessed with holy water after all
阿根廷突然陷入了困境
Argentina are struggling all of a sudden
被弹开了
that's bounced off
这是另一种惩罚吗?
is that another penalty
不，裁判给了它另一种方式
no the referee has given it the other way
黄牌也被罚出场
and the yellow card is out as well
给他兰看
shown to Taram
看一看会很有趣的
it's going to be interesting to have a look at it
他点头
he's nodding
这说明他确实是跳水了
which indicates to me that he did dive
爸爸并没有表现出太多的情绪
well dad's not showing a lot of emotion
他咬了一口
he has a nibble
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
他把它拉开
he pulls it out of the way
潜水
to dive
他把腿留在里面了
he leaves his leg in there
Taram
马奇尼亚克先生说得好
well spotted Mr Marciniac
我来告诉你什么没被提及
I tell you what wasn't mentioned
是
was
没拿到卡算什么
what's amending not getting the card
继续惩罚
in continuing the penalty
这只是第二届世界杯
it's only the second World Cup
最后的特色
final to feature
两个点球
two penalties
上一个是
previous one was
1974年当裁判是
1974 when the referee was
英格兰的杰克·泰勒
England's Jack Taylor
这是相同的模式
it's the same pattern
荷兰队先得分
Netherlands scored first
德国扳平了比分，就像西德一样
Germany equalised, West Germany as they were
西德后来赢得了胜利
West Germany then went and won it
这次会发生在法国身上吗
could be happening for France this time
会有延迟，所以
going to be a delay so that
治疗可以用于另一个
treatment could be administered for another
空中挑战
aerial challenge that's
引起的疼痛
caused pain
看这个，1 - 2
look at this, a one-two
精彩的表演
brilliant bit of play
这对莫利纳来说很糟糕，但是
it was poor for Molina but
你不能质疑
you cannot question
质量
the quality
在最重要的时刻
in the biggest of moments
来自这个星球上最大的玩家之一
from one of the biggest players on the planet
让他的国家重回赛场
to get his country back into this game
我没记错，那不是
I'm remembering rightly that wasn't
不同于其中一个目标
dissimilar to one of the goals
他在4-3的比赛中得分
that he scored in the 4-3
这两者之间的颤栗
thriller between these two
在上届喀山世界杯上
in Kazan at the last World Cup
当他又进了两个球
when he scored two again
他绝对是个超级巨星
he's an absolute superstar
只要几分钟
it's only a few minutes
或者就在他得分之前
or barely moments before he scored
我们说的惩罚
that penalty we were saying
我认为肢体语言是合理的
and I think with justification the body language
看，他似乎打败了玩家
look he seemed to have beaten player
不是现在
not now
他只是在等待
he's just waiting
我提到他的团队没有和他在一起
I mentioned that his team were not there with him
这些变化
the changes
就像我之前提到的
like I mentioned with
和
and
科曼赢得了第二个球
Koman who wins the ball actually for the second goal
只是增加了一些能量
just added some energy
一些信念融入身边
some belief into the side
但它给了我很大的信任
but it gave a lot of credit
给迪迪埃·德尚
to Didier Deschamps
他在里面看比赛
he was watching a beat inside
他什么都试过了
and he's tried everything
在上半场做了一些改变
made changes in the first half
他把事情搞混了，他改变了周围的事物
he's mixed things up, he's changed things around
他已经尽力了
he's done as much as he possibly can
作为一个经理，做他能做的
as a manager to do what he can do
旁观者
from the sidelines
他现在要求更多
and he's now demanding more
这就是赢家的做法
that's what winners do
Robbie很好
Robbie is OK
没有那么多的感觉
there's not as much feeling
在这些运动中
in those movements now
我们也会忍不住思考
we can't help but think as well
自从德玛丽亚下场后
since De Maria came off the pitch
这种威胁
that threat
为阿根廷队做了一些改变
was shifted a little bit for Argentina
这只是一种投掷
that's just given that as a throw
——德米罗
from De Miro
跳跃
leaping
早春作物
Rabia
从Colomawani带走
taken away from Colomawani
由Otamendi
by Otamendi
和Bapit
and Bapit
这是在美国
here's Koman
昆德要离开了
Kunde was leaving it
然后不得不迅速调整
for Shouimani and then had to adjust quickly
加时还有八分钟
into added time there'll be eight more minutes
现在是法国
and it's France now
谁看起来更像球队
who looked the team more likely
为了赢得这场比赛
to win this
在加时赛之前
before we go to extra time
科曼做得有点过头了
Koman's overdone that a bit
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
和Bapit
and Bapit
越位
offside
阿根廷人完全失去了镇静
the Argentine have lost all the composure
游戏的
of the game
多么精彩的比赛啊
what a game
他离我们那么近
he was so close
然后那个人出现了
and then that man turned up
对Akunya
towards Akunya
昆德有
Kunde's had a
一个直接去阿富汗
one straight to Taliafico
塔利班会试图到达那里
Taliafico will try to get there
但看起来好像
but it seemed as though
他在沙滩上跑了一会儿
he was running on the beach for a moment
软下来
soft down
会发生什么?
what could have been
如果没有他，还会是什么样子
what still might be but without him
Kunde
Toram
任意球法国队
free kick France
阿根廷的问题
the problem they've got Argentina
这绝对是一记重击吗
is it's been an absolute body blow
处理这两个目标
dealing with those two goals
他们在挣扎
and they're struggling
而现在法国突然之间
whereas with France now all of a sudden
那里的信仰
the beliefs there
要到加时赛了
got to kind of get to extra time
然后重新组合
and just regroup
我们在第3-4节看到了它的影子
we saw glimpses of it in the 3-4
中场休息前5-6分钟
5-6 minutes before halftime
当Toram和Cola Moane
when Toram and Cola Moane
是在
came on
这对阿根廷来说是个大问题
this is a big problem for Argentina
还有法国队在场上的球员
with the players that France have got on the pitch as well
交货无误
the delivery's right
没有联系到海军的任何人
doesn't reach anybody in Navy
轻轻一弹
that took a little flick
阿根廷队丢了球
off command for an Argentina throw it
还是重申
still reiterate
这是我们在前半部分讲过的
a fact we gave you in the first half
在本届世界杯开始之前
before this World Cup start
阿根廷队此前在世界杯上赢得了27场比赛
Argentina had won their previous 27 games at the World Cup
当他们在中场休息时领先时
when they'd been in front at halftime
现在看起来像
this now looks like
三个
three
在这场比赛中，他们没有
in this competition when they haven't
这里有一个后凸，它被偏转了
and there's a back bay going again and that's deflected
这可能是份好工作，但它确实是
and it might be a good job but it was
这将是一个角落，他现在是
it's going to be a corner and he is now
绝对是拼命的
absolutely hell bent
凭借一己之力赢得世界杯决赛
on winning this World Cup final single-handedly
他想要他的根
he wants his atroot
我认为这是一个很大的障碍
it's a big block I think from what's amending
只是把腿伸出来
just hangs his leg out
一直以来他
all the time he
拿到球，他的眼睛都亮了
gets the ball his eyes are just lighting up
这感觉就像
this has almost felt like
在一场比赛中火炬的传递
in one match the passing of the torch
你已经度过了你的辉煌时刻
you've had your moment ten
这个紧张的时刻
this tense time
马丁内斯说到了
Martinez gets to it
Camarvinga
Coman
在被犯规前轻松通过了挑战
breezing past the challenges before being fouled
就在外面，但好处是玩
just outside but the advantage is playing
Rabio拍摄
Rabio shot
马丁内斯控制不住，但他现在拿到了
Martinez couldn't hold it but he's got it now
科曼说得太棒了
it's brilliant from Coman
太犀利了，我觉得裁判应该继续比赛
so sharp I think referee's right to play on
罗梅罗只是扼杀了它
Romero just smothers it
用他的腿
with his legs
给马丁内斯一个大大的救球
keeps his call big big save for Martinez
他们还有时间
there is still time for them
梅西
Messi
扔
throwing
这里有这么多
so much in here
来到边线，他拿到了黄牌
coming to the touchline here and he's got the yellow
从口袋里掏出名片
card out of his pocket
他朝迪迪埃·德尚的方向跑去了
and he's running in the direction of Didier Deschamps
德尚指着另一个人
Deschamps is pointing at someone else
所以我不认为是德尚
so I don't think it is Deschamps
这不是
it's not
它是法国的一个
it's one of the French
我是奥利维尔·吉鲁
it's Olivier Giroud
他得到一张黄牌
he's getting a yellow card
因为你放弃了这个学期
for talking out of the term
他很生气那个任意球没有得到，但是
he's angry that the free kick wasn't given but
“继续玩下去”是喊声
playing on was the shout
梅西
Messi
试着摆脱一个
trying to get away from one
也看到了中路的奔跑
seeing the run in the middle as well
Colin Mewarney没能完成这项工作
Colin Mewarney not able to complete the job
现在还不可能
not yet he might yet
随着球回到他身边，他继续前进
with the ball coming back to him and he keeps on
取消
scrapping
阿根廷也有这样的数字
and Argentina had the numbers around
世界各地都会有足球手表
there will be football watches around the world
半决赛前对阵谁
who before the semi-final against
摩洛哥从未听说过兰德尔这个名字
Morocco had never heard the name Randall
科林Mewarney
Colin Mewarney
他在两场比赛中都发挥得太出色了
what a big party he's played in both matches
他们现在认识他了
they know him now
Alcunha
塔里亚菲科
Talia Fico
现在它粘不住了
now it won't stick
麦卡利斯特公司
with McAllister and Co
这是塔利亚·菲科不顾一切地想要赢回它
it's a desperate attempt to win it back by Talia Fico
塔里亚菲科
Talia Fico
麦瓦尼呼叫洛里斯
Mewarney to Lloris
忍不住觉得斯科洛尼搞错了
can't help but feel that Scoloni kind of got it wrong
有了这个变化
with that change
阿尔库尼亚上场了
Alcunha coming on to the pitch
我想知道迪马里亚这个赛季的伤病是否有问题
I wonder if DiMaria's injury problems this season
但他一直在去五分之一
but he'd been going to a five
部队决定不这么做
and Troop decided not to
这是阿库尼亚，这是阿尔瓦雷斯
there is Acunha and here is Alvarez
梅西举起了他的手臂
Messi's got his arm in the air
几乎是礼貌地在另一边
almost politely over on the other side
他自由了，保罗给了他球
he's free and DePaul has given him the ball
梅西来了
here goes Messi
普天同庆
Hugo Lloris
鹰一般的眼睛
eyes like a hawk
多么美妙的一刻
what a moment
他直接插了进来
he just cuts in
并将其皮革化
and leathers it
从中间直下
straight down the middle
洛里斯必须看着
Lloris has to watch it
一直到他的手上
all the way onto his hand
最后也会稍微动一下
moves a little bit at the end as well
在上面弄点东西真的很好吗
does really well to get something on it
把它越过吧台
and get it over the bar
我是Francis Jaundam
Francis Jaundam in chief
多棒的一站啊
what a stop
随着时间的流逝
as moments go
我想这是例行的守门
say it's routine goalkeeping I suppose
但在时间的背景下
but in the context of the timing
这场比赛停了下来
the match what a stop
大大节省
big big save
梅西
Messi
他来了
and he's coming
阿库尼亚要干掉他
and Acunha's taking him out
裁判已经吹响了哨子
referee had already blown his whistle
黄牌:阿库尼亚法国队只想继续比赛
yellow card Acunha France just wanted to get on with it
他是
he was
这太愤世嫉俗了
that was cynical
但他必须犯规
but he had to make the foul
在接下来的30分钟里
a roll on the next 30 minutes
如果我们到达那里
if we get there
我是说我很喜欢
I mean I'm loving it
科尔曼
Coleman
自从他上场以来，他一直表现出色
he's been terrific since coming on
金斯利·科尔曼给自己留了一些空间
Kingsley Coleman makes some room for himself
梅西
Messi
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
他还是可以走的
he can still go
阿尔瓦雷斯找到了他能找到的传球
Alvarez find the pass he can
梅西
Messi
无法完全恢复
unable to get it fully over
去舞会
to the ball
现在的游戏
and the game for now
已经结束了
is over
但感谢我们这些爱他的人
but thankfully for those of us who love
激动人心的足球比赛
thrilling football
在尽可能高的水平上
at the highest level possible
我们至少还要再听半个小时
we're going to get at least another half hour of this
因为他
because of him
基利安·姆巴佩活过来了
Killian Mbappe who came alive
当他的国家需要他的时候
when his country needed him
阿根廷2
Argentina 2
法国2
France 2
我善良
goodness me
足球运动员
footballer
那些阿根廷球迷想
those Argentinian fans thought
他们一直在胜利的路上，直到那个人
they were cruising to victory until that man
姆巴佩做出了不同的决定
Mbappe decided otherwise
首先是一个漂亮的点球
first a nicely taken penalty
第二，精彩的收尾
secondly an extraordinary finish
截击
on the volley
而法国不知从何而来
and France come back from nowhere
好一场决赛
what a final
我们将有多长的时间啊
what an extra time we're about to have
只有一支球队做到过
only one team has ever
从两个进球中恢复过来
come back from two goals
在赢得世界杯上落后
behind to win a world cup
最后，那是西德
final and that was West Germany
1954年对阵匈牙利
against Hungary in 1954
7分钟后，他们0 - 2落后
when they trailed 2-0 after 7 minutes
但最终以3比2获胜
but came back to win 3-2
这当然是第二次了
this is the second time of course
阿根廷已经放弃了
that Argentina have given away
在这次比赛中领先2球
a 2-goal lead in this tournament
他们对荷兰队也是如此
they did the same against Netherlands
当他们在最后阶段进了两个球
when they scored two late goals
这次是法国
this time though it was France
然后是姆巴佩
and then Mbappe
好一场决赛
what a final
疯了就是疯了
crazy it is bonkers
只有80分钟的时间，法国没有任何机会
only for 80 minutes France have not had a shot
在目标上看起来很长腿
on target look leggy
昏睡的累
lethargic tired
看起来好像它们正在慢慢消失
it looks as if they're just easing away
无处可去
and going nowhere
然后突然之间
and then all of a sudden
疯狂的挑战
a crazy challenge
他们达到了目标，每个人的精神都很好
they get the goal everyone's spirits are up
这就是它的背面
and then that's it the back in it
这是一场精彩的决赛
it's amazing what a final
地板上的那个人
that man there on the floor
姆巴佩没有踢球
Mbappe hadn't kicked the ball
整场比赛都没碰过球
hadn't had a touch of the ball at all game
两个时刻，作曲家来了
two moments come the composer
罚:迅速地接受惩罚
to take the penalty in dispatch
这就是截击技术
and that volley the technique
那一刻
takes that moment
在大舞台上，他想成为决定比赛的人
the big stage he wants to be the man to decide games
他的立场又回到了这里
and he's got his side right back in it
法国已经释放了潜艇
France have made free the subs
影响目标
impacted the goals
带来了青春带来了年轻的双腿
brought on youth brought on young legs
把事情扭转过来
and turned things round
两队的比分都是2比2
both teams after it was 2-2
有机会巴勃罗
had opportunities Pablo
这段时间对你来说很难熬
it's been a tough watch for you
伟大的复兴
great comeback
他们是朋友，有点相信
they're friends kind of believe it
说实话
to be honest
我们打得很好，2比0
we're playing well 2-0
只要停留一次，我们就会放弃点球
just one stay we give the penalty away
然后是姆巴佩
and then they have Mbappe
最伟大的球员之一
one of the greatest players
两个目标
two goals
三分钟后
in three minutes
但这就是为什么我们不是足球
but that's why we're not football
我是说我有点相信
I mean I kind of believe
但这是一场多么精彩的游戏
but what a game
多么精彩的比赛啊
what a game
与1986年的相似之处
similarities between 1986
这个也是一样的
and this one that was the same
阿根廷2-0领先
Argentina led 2-0
德国在最后时刻打进了两个进球
Germany came back with two late goals
然后是一个神奇的时刻
and then there was a moment of magic
马拉多纳打进的球
from Maradona where he put through
博罗查加和他进了球
Borochaga and he scored the goal
他差一点就得分了，不是吗
he nearly scored didn't he
巨大的努力
tremendous effort
在弥留之际
in the dying minutes
这是我们看过的最好的决赛吗
is this the best final we've seen
对我来说，这是我去过的最好的一次
for me it's the best one I've ever been to
可能是我认为最具戏剧性的，不是吗
possibly the most dramatic I would say wouldn't you
我从没看过比这更好的决赛
I've not been to a better final than this
他一直说法国是冠军
he keeps saying about France they're champions
出于某种原因
for a reason
他们找到了一种方式，他们找到了一种方式，回到这个游戏中
they find a way and boy have they found a way back into this game
现在谁是最好的赢家
whose best place to win now
我认为法国有这种势头
I suppose France have the momentum
他们是有信念的
they have the belief going into it
但阿根廷可以振作起来
but Argentina can pick themselves up
阿根廷在点球大战中占据优势
Argentina penalty shootout and dominated
冷静，只是在玩耍
calm and just playing
和我们做的一样
in the same way we did
上半场我知道当迪玛利亚
the first half I know when Di Maria
马尔菲就像
Malfi was just like
我们失去了一位重要的球员
we lost a big player
他没有因为受伤而参加比赛
he hadn't played from injury
他累了
he was tired
我在求一个超级明星
I'm begging one of the superstars
现在决定这场比赛
to decide this game now
他也是为其中之一而生的
he's made for one of them too
那个人是梅西还是姆巴佩
that man there Messi or Mbappe
看起来是这样的，不是吗
it looks that way doesn't it
这就是那种游戏，不是吗
it's been that sort of game hasn't it
难以置信的
incredible
真的太棒了
really awesome
现在领导着黄金工作的追逐，但这不是什么
now leading the golden work chase but that's not what
球员们现在会怎么想
will be on the players mind now
谁将举起那座金杯将是关键
it will be who's going to lift that golden trophy
让我们来看看
let's find out
回到杰梅因·格纳斯和盖伊·莫里
back to Jermaine Genus and Guy Mowry
谢谢你加里
thank you Gary
中场休息时又换了一个人
there has been one more substitution during the break
阿根廷队交换了右后卫
Argentina have swapped their right back
现在莫利纳付出了代价
now well Molina has paid the price for
最后被骗了
being ripped into finally
作者:Kylian Mbappe
by Kylian Mbappe
冈萨洛·蒙蒂尔就在这些地方
and on these places come Gonzalo Montiel
现在谁是更合适的退路
who is more of a proper act now fallback
不太关心前进
not quite as concerned with getting forward
前脚向前
front foot forward
两队在接下来的30分钟内进行比赛
for both teams over the next 30 minutes
他们看起来很震惊
they look shocked
阿根廷甚至在这个位置
Argentina that are even in this position
但他们必须找到一些东西
but they've got to find something
这火回到了眼睛里
this fire back in the eyes
噢,是的
oh yeah
如果你想在世界杯决赛中脱颖而出
if you want to attract in a World Cup final
它们也会刺激你的眼睛
they'll be firing your eyes as well
近乎荒谬
bordering on the ridiculous
接壤
bordering
所以我们走吧
so away we go
它是
it is the
第八次打入世界杯决赛
eighth time that the World Cup final
已经进入加时赛了吗
has gone to extra time
只有两个
only two
一直到点球
have gone all the way to penalties
94年的结果
94 result
特别是在2006年的美国
particularly in the USA in 2006
法国
France
失去
losing out
意大利和德国
to Italy and Germany
罗伯托·巴乔在球场报道
Roberto Baggio in the stadium
你不
aren't you
你从来没离我超过10码
you've never been more than 10 yards away
一位全球足球巨星的演讲
from a global football superstar in this stadium
今天晚上
this evening
谢谢你！
thank you
哦，亲爱的我
oh dear me
在球场上从来没有这样的机会
never took your chances like that on the field
太棒了
that was magnificent
偷猎者
poacher
木乃伊
mummy
F昨
Ac nggak
罗梅罗
Romero
有点太热心了
a little over zealous
只是一点点
just a little bit
在左边
to the left
顺便说一下
incidentally
没有父子
no father and son
这对组合都赢得了世界杯
combo have both won the World Cup
25号，他爸爸也是
the 25th who's dad was also
参加过世界杯
in a World Cup squad
金牌
gold medal
从来没有进入过
has never found its way into the
拥有两代人
possession of two generations
你没办法
you can't help it
由家庭
by family
03:18:19,600 --> 03:18:21,600
Rockerball
前锋
striker
一些许可
some clearances by
内存
Ram
深的
deep
和
and
想让科尔曼振作起来
trying to get Coleman going
这是麦卡利斯特
here's McAllister
港口
the port
梅西飘向右路
Messi floating away to the right
蒙蒂尔的支持
support from Montiel
梅西没有欺骗
Messi did not deceive
法国队最年轻的选手
the youngest player in the French
我是爱德华多·卡文加
camp, Eduardo Camovinga
我觉得他不能吃黄牌，梅西
I just don't think he can be booked, Messi
就好像他不能被记录在案一样
it's like he's not allowed to be booked
对荷兰人也是这样，不是吗
and that happened against the Dutch, didn't it
真的应该有
really ought to have
在他之前很久就看到了黄
seen Yellow long before he did
Verran
与
with
雨果Louris
Hugo Louris
他打了这么多年球
all of his years in the game
他的内心一定有一点感觉
he must have had a little bit of a feeling inside
那口井，这口溜走了
that well this one slipped away
这样看
seen that way
汤姆·拜特·拉姆
Tom Byter Ram
对弗朗西斯来说更鼓舞人心的是什么
what is even more encouraging for Francis
他们重回战场是因为他们的
that they've got back into this because of their
下一代即将到来
next generation coming through
然后你想想那些没有成功的球员
and then you think of the players who haven't
和他们一起打进了世界杯
made it to this world cup with them
比如
the likes of
金滕比，坎特，博格巴
Kintembe, Kante, Pogba
还有Konku，去了切尔西
and Konku, Chelsea bound
真是个天才
heck of a talent
本泽马
Benzema
本泽马也
Benzema too
金球奖得主
Ballon d'Or Holder
这是康纳·穆恩
and there's Conor Muane
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
这就是他们开始做的更多的事情
that's what they started doing more of
赢球了，穆恩
winning the ball, Muane
金斯利·科曼，这就是他们进球的原因
Kingsley Coman, that's how they got the goal
第二个是科曼从梅西身上抢过来的
the second one, Coman taking it off Messi
这太被动了
it was all too passive
在这70多分钟的大部分时间里
for the best part of what 70 odd minutes
阿昆雅跳进
Akunya jumping into
的解决
the tackle
比赛结束前，他被判玩世不恭的挑战
booked for a cynical challenge towards the end
在90人中
of the 90
看看这个，离这远着呢
look at this, it's not anywhere near
它不是在看球
it's not looking at the ball
他真的赢了，这对他来说是件好事
it's a pretty good job for him that he actually won it
另一次法国变革
another France change
拉比奥最后一次跑了
Rabiot has run his last
本届世界杯
at this world cup
优素福·法法纳将为他上场
it's going to be Yusuf Fafana to come on for him
在最后一场比赛中谁代替了他
who took his place in the last game
对摩洛哥
against Morocco
另一个
another one
前途光明，只有23个来自摩纳哥
with a bright future ahead, only 23 from Monaco
或者和摩纳哥队比赛
or plays with Monaco
是的，还有更多新鲜的腿
yeah, more fresh legs as well
面对现在
up against now
这是保罗和麦卡利斯特
and there's the Paul and McAllister
看起来有点疲惫
looking a bit weary
他走了
there he goes
凯末尔Vinga
Kemal Vinga
Fafana
Kunde
巴佩越位
and Bapay offside
不管怎样都不起作用
didn't work anyway
巴佩被这个挑战难住了
Bapay was caught by the challenge
他完全把他钉住了
he's absolutely nailed him here
罗梅罗
Romero
他完全没有思想
he's got no thought at all
他和他在一起
he's staying with him
巴佩一转身
as soon as Bapay turns
他就打他
he just hits him
砰的一声，整个脚掌
Wallop, full top of his foot
如此有侵略性的球员
such an aggressive player
罗梅罗
Romero
他几乎都想赢球了
he's almost wanting to win the ball
每次他挑战的时候都会给你留一点
and leave a bit on you every time he challenges
这就是
such is
以及巴佩现在的心态
and Bapay's mindset now
他一瘸一拐地走了，脸上带着一丝微笑
there's a little smile on his face as he limps away
他不想让他太兴奋
he don't want to light him up too much
Bapay
梅西
Messi
他的光芒有点暗淡了
his light has gone out a little bit
随着比赛的进行
as this game's gone on
可能还会有火花
there might be a spark left
Akunya
梅西将受到温格的挑战
Messi will be challenged by Kama Wenger
它是由保罗飞回来的
it's flighted back in by DePaul
飞出去了
got flighted out
射门法国队
goal kick France
Bapay
这里没什么大事发生
there's nothing much happening here
球飞向后门柱的动作还不错
not a bad flight at ball towards that back post
但
but
这都有点
it's all a little bit
现在即兴发挥
off the cuff now
在阿根廷
for Argentina
更少的临床
less clinical
拉比奥赢得了法国球迷的掌声
Rabio has taken the applause of the French fans
祝贺你
and the congratulations of
前阿森纳球员马泰奥·根都齐
former Arsenal man Matteo Genduzzi
谁在看他的
who's going through his
准备程序，以防万一
preparation routines just in case
法国还能有更多的改变
more change left available for France
科尔曼
Coleman
尴尬的
awkwardly
从拉梅罗的头上摘下来
off the head of Ramero
斯科洛尼亚现在需要检查一下
Scolonia needs to have a little look now
他的团队充其量看起来很谨慎
his team looked wary at best
需要开始利用他的阵容
needs to start utilizing his squad
他正在考虑做一些改变
he's looking at making a couple of changes
这是,
here's that
裴瑞兹莱安德罗
Leandro Paredes
芋头马丁内斯
Taro Martinez
准备
getting ready
这是打算
it's Montiel
费尔南德斯
Fernandez
把球直接传给特拉姆
running the ball straight into Terram
Kola Muane接手
Kola Muane takes over
可乐Muane
Kola Muane
像迷宫一样奔跑
went on a mazy run
只是没能把他弄进盒子里
just didn't get him all the way into the box
它最终导致了痛苦
it has resulted in pain at the end of it
德保罗
de Paul
由Camarvinga收集
collected by Camarvinga
和Bapay
and Bapay
水银
Quicksilver
和Bapay
and Bapay
再次比赛，但阿尔瓦雷斯领先
racing again but Alvarez there first
第一个
first
阿尔瓦雷斯正在接受挑战
Alvarez soaking up the challenges
干得漂亮，那将是一个任意球
that's brilliant work and that will be a free kick
为法国
for France
更好的
much better
那么好
so good
他们被激怒了，看看他们
they're fired up look at them
优素福·法法诺的演讲太棒了
just terrific that from Youssef Fafano
这只是压力
it's just pressure
现在他们在球场上到处都有压力
all over the pitch now they've got pressure
他们有能量
they've got energy
看起来更有可能在额外的时间里完成这项工作
looking the more likely to go and get this done in extra time
金斯利科尔曼
Kingsley Coleman
是否有责任做得恰到好处
has the responsibility of getting this just right
钻回
drill back
由Fafano
by Fafano
科曼又在争先到达那里
Coman's racing to get there first again
梅西先到的
Messi was there first
但现在它将成为法国的一角
but it will now be a France corner
这个伟大的人自从在绝望中就在他身边了
the great man since in the desperation in his side right now
科曼正试着深入讨论
Coman trying to get it into the thick of it
但我没有找到
but didn't reach
Kunde
梅西
Messi
Shoua Mane的挑战
challenge by Shoua Mane
他把早先越位的比赛恢复了
he's brought back the play for an earlier offside
我想当球从右边进的时候可能就是这种情况
I thought that might be the case when that ball's played in from the right
这位官员没有把他的旗子高高挂起
the official don't put his flag up so
他绝对是越位
he's definitely an offside in there
把球传给塞缪尔
the ball to Samuel
这是最后一个
that's the last
一些说明
couple of bits of instruction for
劳塔罗·马丁内斯和莱安德罗·科雷德斯
Lautaro Martinez and Leandro Corredes
蒙蒂尔不会再往前走了
Montiel isn't going any further
自从他上场以来，他一直是一个很好的人
he's been good kind of ingot since coming on
可乐Moani
Cola Moani
他变成了一个蝙蝠
he's turned into a bat play
可能
probably
他又回来挑战了
and he's back making the challenge again
那一个
that one
对麦卡利斯特太强硬了
too robust on McAllister
谁会因为试图亲自裁判比赛而被裁判斥责
who's going to get a ticking off from the referee for trying to referee the game himself
趁还能说几句
just a word whilst we can
对Marciniak先生来说
for Mr Marciniak
这是我见过的最好的广告
the best advert I've ever seen
不只是今天，过去几个赛季都是这样
not just today but over the last few seasons
对于一些顶级的职业裁判来说
for some professionals at the top level going into refereeing
鼻子对着游戏
nose to game
100%还
100% yet
非常非常好
been very very good
他很有权威，不是吗?
was it with authority don't he?
他简直就是个噩梦
he was a nightmare to officiate himself
火焰图像外场
a fire image fielder
以下是阿根廷的变化
here are the Argentina changes
下两个给保罗
the next two to Paul
是关闭的
is off
阿尔瓦雷斯走了
and Alvarez is off
他们都跑啊跑啊跑
well both have run and run and run
但本届世界杯将不再运行
but will run no more this World Cup
科雷德斯和劳塔罗·马丁内斯继续
Corredes and Lautaro Martinez on
劳塔罗马丁内斯
Lautaro Martinez
在点球大战中获胜
winning penalty aside in the
对阵荷兰的点球大战
shootout against the Netherlands
没有像我们知道的那样打开它
has not turned it on as we know he can
就像他为国米所做的那样
and as he does for Inter
也许舞台已经搭建好了
maybe the stage is set
他有过很多机会
well he's had lots of chances
只是还没有完全适应他
it just hasn't quite gone for him
他有一个很大的机会
he's got one big big chance to
为他的国家做点什么
do something for his country here
他不会为之前比赛中错失的机会而烦恼
he won't be bothered about all those missed chances in the previous games
他可以把球插在网后面
he can stick one in the back of the net here
别忘了在四分之一决赛中
don't forget in that quarter final
类似的故事甚至更戏剧性
similar story even more dramatically actually
最后2比0战胜荷兰队
so late against the Dutch 2-0 up to 2-2
但他们坚持住了
but they held it together
并在点球大战中获胜
and won on penalties
罗梅罗带球向前
there's Romero with the ball forward
我是麦卡利斯特
this is McAllister
同样，展望未来可能有点过早
also looking ahead perhaps a little prematurely
所有四名点球得分球员
all four of their penalty scorers
参加过四分之一决赛的选手现在都上场了
in that quarter final are now on the field
这是帕雷德斯，他就是其中之一
here's Paredes who was one of them
有昆热
there's a Kunje
真的有点疯狂
really is a little bit wild
真的很差
really poor
考虑到他是一名新出场的球员
considering he's one of the players that's come on with fresh legs
需要提供更多的东西
needs to offer a bit more than that
莫瑞斯期待着圆
Maurice looking forward to round
很棒的
terrific
我从麦卡利斯特那里抄来的
I jumped that from McAllister
现在马丁内斯找到了费尔南德斯
now Martinez finds Fernandez
麦卡利斯特
McAllister
梅西让自己有空
Messi makes himself available
梅西找到了麦卡利斯特
Messi finds McAllister
梅西找到了马丁内斯
and Messi now finds Martinez
Waterblock
蒙提尔的跟进和另一个
the follow-up from Montiel and another one
这次是为了Ran挡道
this time for Ran in the way
他只是给比赛注入了一些节奏
well he just injected some pace into the play
梅西
Messi
他和马丁内斯之间的默契
brilliant link-up between him and Martinez
但是那块呢
but what about that block there
巨大的
massive
巨大的块
massive block
在麦卡诺
up on McArno
尽自己的本分
doing his bit
为跑
for Ran
刚刚结束
just finishing it off
第一次真的
the first time really
这是我们这么长时间以来第一次见到
the first time really we've seen in a while
只是阿根廷活过来了
just Argentina coming to life
罗梅罗排在最后
Romero at the back of the pack
在最初的15分钟加时赛上加了一分钟
just one minute added to this initial 15 in extra time
费尔南德斯追逐
Fernandez chases
法国丢了一球给基奥梅尼
France throw one by Chioumeni
巨大的块
huge block
只是不知道马丁内斯能不能离开
just don't know whether Martinez could just move
他的脚足够快
his feet quick enough for
因为他不知道从哪里冒出来的，所以很苛刻
just being harsh because he come out of nowhere really
就在麦卡诺那边
up on McArno for that
Coonday
Cooman
阿库尼亚转身逃走了
Acunha turns and gets away with it
寻找劳塔罗·马丁内斯
and looks to find Lautaro Martinez
马丁内斯将球打偏
Martinez puts it wide
声称一个角落没有得到它
claims a corner doesn't get it
这是一次精彩的跑动和完美的传球
that's a brilliant run and the perfect ball
触感很好
the touch is fine
他要占领一个角落
he's claiming a corner
让我们看一看
let's have a look
是的，我认为他是对的
yeah I think he's right
在麦卡诺那边
up on McArno there again
又是两个巨大的防御
again two huge huge bits of defending
让他的国家陷入困境
to keep his country in this tight
这是加时赛第一节的关键球员
well there's the key player of the first period of extra time
就在最后
right at the end of it
这位拜仁慕尼黑的中后卫
the Bayern Munich centre-back
迪奥在麦卡诺
Deo up on McArno
两个至关重要的模块
two vital blocks
一个他拿满了
one he took full
一个是尼克
one he got a nick on
绝对必要的
absolutely essential
迪迪埃·德尚
Didier Deschamps having a
和马库斯·特雷特进行了激烈的交锋
a wild exchange there with Marcus Terrain
又一次因为某种原因离开了他
once more from him for some reason or another
现在他恢复了平衡
and now he regains his equilibrium
并吸引他的球员回来
and draws his players back in
我们现在还不应该谈论处罚
we shouldn't talk about penalties yet
杰梅因，我们是不是走得太早了
Jermaine should we went far too soon
还剩15块钱呢
there's a big 15 left in this
你知道吗?
you know what
加时赛有很多比赛
there's a lot of games in extra time
我们只是觉得这是一种无用的橡胶
we just think this is a bit of a dead rubber
让我们来看看罚球
let's just get to penalties
这个游戏有一些生命力
there's some life in this game
我想双方都表现出来了
I think both sides have shown
那些小小的能量火花
those little sparks of energy
那些小小的时刻，有人
those little moments where somebody
想要写下他们的名字和历史
wants to write their name and history
然后在点球之前完成
and go and get it done before penalties
我认为阿根廷在这方面做出了一些改变
I think the couple of changes that Argentina have made there
让他们活过来了吗
have brought them to life
他们又回到了游戏中
got them right back in this game
大
big big
加时赛下半场就要开始了
second half of extra time coming up
阿根廷
Argentina
真的来过这里吗
have been here before literally
在这个体育场之前
in this stadium before
这是他们的第五场比赛
this is their fifth game
在这个宏伟的场地
at this magnificent venue
这是法国的第一次
it's France's first time
这是他们第一次进入加时赛
and their first time in extra time
有趣的
interesting
在圆圈中间打了几枪
a few shots in the middle of that circle
他们只是想团结起来
there just trying to rally
军队
the troops
给他们最后一推
give them one last push
她做了我们之前提到的所有事情
she's done everything we mentioned earlier
的兑换商
the changers
出色的管理
brilliant management
那些北约峰会很容易，不是吗
those NATO Summits they're easy aren't they
而不是让你自己经历这些
compared to having to put yourself through this
顺便说一下，总统
incidentally the president
阿根廷
of Argentina
阿尔贝托·费尔南德斯不在这里
Alberto Fernandez is not here
他正在他的官邸观看
he's watching from his official residence
在斯-奥利弗斯
in Olivos
布宜诺斯艾利斯
Buenos Aires
他担心被打上烙印
he was worried about being branded
MUFA
坏运气
bad luck
并决定留在原地
and decided to stay put
在看电视
on watch on the television
我希望老费尔南德斯是
I hope senior Fernandez is
好吧
okay
他也经历过
he's been put through it as well
最后15分钟我们走
away we go the last 15 minutes
除非是点球大战
barring a penalty shootout
2022年世界杯
the 2022 World Cup
比赛
tournament that has
被问及
been asked questions of
完全正确地
quite rightly
一旦比赛开始
once the games have started
总的来说是足球
the football by and large
就像每一次
as happens at every
世界杯足球赛
World Cup tournament
几乎每个人
pretty much everyone
一切都好了吗
has taken care of itself
是一种享受
and been a treat
有什么好吃的?
what are the treats
行存储
line store
梅西的传球很漂亮
well there's Messi with a lovely pass
曾经过了头
once gone over the top
事实并非如此
that wasn't quite so
完成
accomplished
洛里斯没什么好担心的
nothing for Lloris to be worried about
这两名边路球员是新来的
the two wide players that have come on fresh
这是
that are
在游戏中呈现较差的质量
delivering the poor quality in the game
位置很好
good position there
在那种情况下
on that occasion
佩妮的想法，他就快到了
penny for his thoughts he was nearly there
他们在专心地看，不是吗
they're watching intently aren't they
他们都去过那里
they've both been there
一切为规则下来的巡回赛受伤
all for the rule down of the tour of injured
如果我没记错的话
if I remember rightly David Tresagay
有阿根廷血统吗
has some Argentinian ancestry
良好的知识
good knowledge
他在避开法国
he's avoiding France
全在这里
fully here
你会认为
you'd think
不是向前的球，但是洛里斯已经准备好了
not the ball forward but Lloris is ready for it
正好赶上时间
just got there in the nick of time
阵型上的微小变化
a tiny little shift in formation
法国队在下半场表现得更差
France in the second half gone much more
变成了4-4-2
to a kind of a 4-4-2
莫恩只会陷得更深一点
Mouane would just drop a little bit deeper
在后面用坏纸
in behind in bad paper
科曼和查拉姆走得更近了
Koeman and Charam have got a lot closer
他们的后卫
to their full backs
梅西
Messi
一定是把洛瑞丝搬下来了
must have been moving Lloris down
这似乎是一种费力的方式
it seemed in laboured fashion
但他还是坐了下来，百分百确定
but he got down and made absolutely sure
这里有一点争论
and there's a little bit of debate
是角球还是射门
about whether it's a corner or a goal kick
确实如此
and it is
起初，似乎有人给了他一个角
well at first a corner seemed to be given
现在助理裁判拿到了他的旗子
and now the assistant referee's got his flag
上面写着进球
up saying goal kick
洛里斯应该做得更好
Lloris should be doing better with that
我不知道他为什么要把它挡在盘子里
I'm not sure why he's parrying that into plate
他要么出去，要么直接接住
he's got to go out or he's got to just catch it
抬头看看大屏幕
look up at the big screens
它们分布在体育场的四个角落
that are in all four corners of the stadium
从Mbappe
from Mbappe
巴黎地铁有一站
there's a stop on the Paris metro
称为阿根廷
called Argentine
当局今天已经掩盖了这个名字
and the authorities covered the name today
并将其更名为法国
and just renamed it France
就在这一天
just for the day
这看起来确实像是法国的末日
and this did look like being the end of the line for France
但相反，他们可能会在以后都涌向那里
but instead they might all be flocking there later on
这里离胜利广场只有一站路
it's just one stop from the at the triumph
有梅西
there's Messi
梅西想要再次夺冠
Messi wants it again
洛丽丝挡道了
Lloris in the way
是越界了还是越界了
was it off the line or over the line
裁判看了一下表
the referee's had a look at the watch
裁判指着中间说进球
and the referee has pointed to the middle and said goal
它将被审视
it will be looked at
但是现在
but for now
这完全是阿根廷人的全员庆祝
it is at all Argentinian all-in celebration
姆巴佩希望得到澄清
and Mbappe wants clarification
梅西就在后腰的中间
Messi is in the middle of that back
他可能只是
he might have just
赢得世界杯
won the World Cup
好吧，到时候我会告诉你的
well, I'll tell you when it is
因为马丁内斯在这边
because Martinez is onside here
但是这个传球，他越位了
but it's this pass here and he's onside
马丁内斯
Martinez
这没什么错
nothing wrong with that
对梅西说
comes out to Messi
这个目标应该坚持下去
that goal should stand
雨果·洛里斯的扑救非常好
really good save from Hugo Lloris
明显越界了吗
is clearly over the line
没有任何理由
there's no reason whatsoever
这是不允许的
that this should be disallowed
我也不认为会是这样
and I don't think it will be
梅西
Lionel Messi
再来一个
with one more
尾巴上神奇而华丽的扭曲
magical magnificent twist in the tail
阿根廷再次领先
Argentina have their lead back
这次是用每一根纤维
and this time with every fibre
他们的存在
of their beings
他们必须坚持住
they must hold on
粉丝们都要疯了
and these fans are going wild
你就知道
you just knew
你知道还会有更多
you knew there was going to be more
在这额外的时间里
in this extra time
它没有完成
it wasn't done
他又回到了他的梅西
and he's at his same Messi
你必须看看法国能否卷土重来
you have to see if France can get back
再来一次
into it again
迪玛利亚是
Di Maria is
强忍着泪水
choking back the tears there
他看得太多了
too much for him to watch
阿根廷3
Argentina 3
法国2
France 2
还有10分钟
10 minutes to go
他会让你喘口气的
he's going to catch your breath
这出戏很精彩
the play is brilliant
对于马丁内斯
for Martinez
看那小小的触碰
look at that little touch there
的1 - 2
the 1-2
他不越位
he's onside
刚刚把他的跑步做到了完美
just held his run to perfection
从那里开始的一切
and everything from there
只是顶级游戏真的是
just top play really is
击中目标
hit the target
让管理员工作
make the keeper work
跟着它走
follow it in
看看这种情绪
look at the emotion
阿奎罗
Sergio Aguero
就像过去一样
just like old times has been
梅西的室友
Lionel Messi's roommate
在过去的一个多星期里
for the last week and a bit
现在他是啦啦队长
now he's chief cheerleader
他的得分
he's scored
想知道目标
wonder goals
他的得分
he's scored
793年的目标
793 goals
在一个了不起的职业生涯中
in an amazing career
但是今天这两个
but these two today
是最大的
are the biggest
也是他所拥有的最好的
and the best that he's ever got
不管他们怎么进去
however they went in
如果
if
阿根廷坚持他们所拥有的
Argentina hold what they have
他们已经马上给了
well they've already given it at once
如果斯科洛尼做不到，我绝对会感到震惊
I'd be absolutely shocked if Scoloni don't do
能让它更稳固一点的东西
something just to shore it up a little bit more
Acuna
Acuña
被斯科洛尼吼
being barked at by Scoloni
他把球传给劳塔罗·马丁内斯
as he plays it into Lautaro Martinez
谁要和瓦兰较量，然后输了
who's taking on Varan and losing
他一直都很好
he's been good
他还没有达到目标，但他表现得很好
hasn't got his goal but he's been really good
然后瓦兰绝对是
and then Varan was absolutely
腿部受伤了
gone in the legs there
当他把球轰出去时，他被打得粉碎
he was shattered as he bundled it out
这就是我们所说的付出一切
that's what we call giving everything
他是一个
he's been one that's been
与bug作斗争
struggling with the bug
只是把它留在那里
just left it all out there
这就是你所能做的
that's all you can do
在世界上最大的比赛中
in the biggest game in the world
然后来了卡纳特为一个受伤的瓦兰
and then on comes Canate for a stricken Varan
劳塔罗马丁内斯
Lautaro Martinez
赢得一次投掷
wins a throw
Scoloni
Acuna
Acuña
这是
it was
尽他所能保持这一切
trying to keep it as best he could
现在它被一个朋友踢进了球门
and now it's gone behind for a friend's goal kick
他们必须回到他们以前做的事情
and they have to go back to what they were doing before
赌博电荷
Gamble charge
让所有人穿深蓝色制服到现场
get everybody in dark blue up the field
这是Camo Vinga试图开始这个过程
here's Camo Vinga trying to start that process
也做得很好
doing well with it too
把它拿出来
take it out
这太愤世嫉俗了
that is cynical
那就是农会走向极端
that is Nong shall pass to the extreme
这是个糟糕的挑战，真的
it's a bad challenge, it really is
他给了自己一些时间来思考这个问题
he's given himself some time to think about this one
裁判
the referee
黄色已经过时了
the yellow is out
安德罗游行是
the Andro Parade is
提供他
offering his
解释和同情，因为他不是故意的
explanation and sympathy because he doesn't mean a bit of it
他只是说够了
he just said enough's enough
他们仍然可以这样做，法国
they can still do this France
他们已经证明，在0 - 2落后的情况下，他们有足够的能力让自己重新振作起来
they've shown they've got enough to get themselves back into it at 2-0 down
科曼地毯芯片
Kermans chip
这是昆德
this is Kunde
战斗正在这里进行
the battle going on here
卡尔纳特正试图赢得这位利物浦中卫
Karnat is trying to win the Liverpool centre-back
被选为中锋
has been brought on as a centre-forward
他也在仗势欺人
he's throwing his weight about as well
塔利亚·维卡想尽办法和他在一起
Talia Vika doing all he can to stay with him
更改完成了
the change is made
因为麦卡利斯特上了不同的课
because McAllister coming off in different class
和
and
日尔曼Petzella
Germain Petzella
会在他的中卫位置上上场吗
will come on in his play centre-back
麦卡利斯特在比赛中有点退色了
McAllister has faded a little from the game
但在他开始之前，他一直很棒
but until he started to he was fantastic
正如斯科洛尼所期望的那样
that as expected from Scoloni the change
预计在上半年会在下半年
expected in the first half to be in the second half of
正常的时间
normal time
他增加了佩策拉的身高
he brought on Petzella's height
去看对荷兰队的比赛，但那并不成功
to see the game out against the Dutch and it didn't work
做同样的工作
same job to do
佩泽拉放弃了马丁内斯的选择
the option of Martinez has gone with Petzella
科尔曼
Coleman
有Mbappe
there's Mbappe
它的收费是
it was charged at
裁判说
and the referee says
他就在外面，不是吗
just outside hasn't he
他指了指那个地方，我敢肯定
he pointed at the spot I'm sure he did
他所做的
he did
那只胳膊确实伸出来了
and the arm came out for sure
还有另一个
there is another
法国队的点球在这里发生了变化
change around here of France penalty
他马上举起手臂说
straight away lifted his arm and said
是的，伸出手臂，打肘部
yeah arm out hit the elbow
蒙特尔，黄牌
yellow card Montiel
法国的大好机会又来了
and here is the big France chance again
但这款游戏在情感上一直摇摆不定
but it just keeps swinging emotionally this game all over the place
姆巴佩正在上演帽子戏法，他手里拿着球
and Mbappe's on a hat trick he's got the ball in his hand
于是杰弗斯把目光移开了
so Jeffers look away now
这一刻
this is the moment
可能
possibly
这是第二次帽子戏法
only the second ever hat trick
在世界杯决赛中进球
scored in a World Cup final
比这更重要
bigger than that though
这是再一次拯救法国的时刻
this is the moment to rescue France once more
他做过一次
he's done it once
两次
twice
三次基利安·姆巴佩怎么样
how about three times Killian Mbappe
肯定不是装可爱的时候
surely not a time to be cute
本能会接管一切
instinct will take over
和Mbappe
and Mbappe
是男人吗?
is the man
帽子戏法
a hat trick
在最重要的比赛中
in the biggest game of all
三个三
three three
这无疑是有史以来最伟大的世界杯决赛
this will surely lay claim to be the greatest World Cup final that's ever been seen
我刚刚看到
I've just seen
总统
the president
那男孩是个国王
that boy's a king
在世界杯决赛中上演帽子戏法
a hat trick in a World Cup final
很显然他被困在这里，不管你怎么想
and apparently he's stuck away as cool as you like
有心理游戏他已经试过一次了
there was mind games he's already took one
他把它插在了同一个地方
and he's stuck it in exactly the same place
他破产了
and he's broke
又是那些阿根廷人的心
those Argentinian hearts again
但是阿根廷又来了
but Argentina go again
那个球被拉回了梅西的方向
and that one's pulled back in Messi's direction
他差一点就走运了
and he nearly got it by good fortune
Caravinga
梅西接手
Messi takes over
梅西在移动
Messi on the move
Acuña和幻灯片
Acuña with the slide
没有考虑过这两支球队的任何点球
there's no thinking about any penalties from these two teams
Acuña这是阿根廷队的角球
Acuña and that's going to go behind for an Argentina corner
加时赛还剩不到一分半钟
less than a minute and a half of extra time remains
肯定不会再有这样的时刻了
there can't be any more moments surely
他给了我们这场比赛的一切
he's given us everything this game
梅西的角落
Messi's corner
路易斯回到了他的线上
Luis stayed back on his line
这将由他前面的人来处理
it will be dealt with by those in front of him
而巴普尔不能把它留在肚子里
and Bapé can't keep that one in
投给阿根廷队
throw in for Argentina
世界杯决赛的进球从9到12
from nine to twelve World Cup goals in the final
他在世界杯上打进了12球
twelve World Cup goals before
他快二十四岁了
he reaches the edge of twenty four
与佩纳持平
level with Pena
和安逸猿
and Bapé
在中间寻找科伦坡
looking in the middle for Colombo
他只是需要再多一点
he just needed a little bit more
稍微碰一下它
the tiniest more touch on it
但就是那一刻
but that was the moment
他只是没能做到
he just couldn't quite get there
他在伸懒腰祈祷
he's stretching and praying
他们可以在上面找到任何东西
they can just get anything on that
大家等一下，还有三分钟
hold on everybody there are three minutes more of this
更多的变化正在发生
and more changes happening
Axel Dizzasi代表法国队出场
Axel Dizzasi is on for France
保罗·德·巴拉上场了
Paulo de Bala is coming on
在阿根廷
for Argentina
从阿根廷的角度来看一些关于点球的想法
some penalty thoughts from Argentina's point of view
我们之间有一点分歧
a little bit of a disagreement going on
那些负责管理的人
those in charge of the admin
koundoff，继续
Koundé off Dizzasi on
然后就走了
and off goes
塔利亚·菲科换阿根廷换德·巴拉
Talia Fico for Argentina for de Bala
走上舞台
to take the stage
处理解决
crunching tackle
来自加拿大
comes in from Canata
不再是中锋了
a centre forward no longer
他回到了他的老地方
he's back in his usual place
不修改
not amending
科尔曼一幅
one by Colman
拉达
La Cunha
科尔曼挑战
challenge by Colman
我们都在看中间那个人
we're all looking at the man in the middle
当德·巴拉试图把球放到某个地方时，裁判突然停住了
the referee now as de Bala tries to put it somewhere
La Tera Martinez
梅西·拉特拉·马丁内斯
Messi La Tera Martinez
他够强壮吗?
is he strong enough?
他够酷吗?
is he cool enough?
拉丽莎和越位的旗子升起来了
Larissa's and the flag is up for Offside
但看起来很紧
but it seemed tight
但这只是一小步
but it's a tiny little step there
而卡纳特恰好在最佳时机挺身而出
and Canate just steps up at the perfect time
抓住马丁内斯越位
catches Martinez offside
被Automandy带走了
headed away by Automandy
卡纳特还有一艘船
there's Canate with one more punt forward
科伦坡尼入选了!
Colomboani is in!
马丁内斯扑救
Martinez with the save
挽救了阿根廷队
the save that has kept Argentina in
有机会获得世界荣誉
with a chance of world glory
梅西
Messi
他们又去了哪里
where they go again
马丁内斯在中间等着
Martinez waits in the middle
那一定是
that had to be
但他不能再要求更多了
but he couldn't have wished for any more
给马丁内斯留点东西
end-to-end stuff to save for Martinez
他是巨大的
he's massive
他打得很好，莫阿尼
he strikes it well, Moani
但马丁内斯刚刚完成了他一生中最重要的一次拯救
but Martinez has just made the biggest save of his life
深呼吸
take a breath
拉里萨
Larissa
能走这么远吗
will get this far far away
舒曼的一首
one by Schuemann
他肯定不会再有机会了
he's surely not one more chance
巴普尔也希望如此
and Bapé hopes so
罗梅罗试图把他挡在边路
Romero tries to keep him wide
祝你好运
good luck with that
和安逸猿
and Bapé
我刚想说不可能
that was about to say no way
到最后已经没有出路了
and there was no way through at the end
几乎是
there nearly was
到目前为止
and that for now
是,
is that
基利安和巴普莱尔
Kylian and Bapé
在世界杯决赛上演帽子戏法
with a World Cup final hat-trick
展示精神力量
with a display of mental strength
从罚球点开始
from the penalty spot
你只需要惊叹
that you just have to marvel at
未来还会有更多
and there's more to come
他们关心的地方
where they're concerned
因为第22届世界杯决赛
because the 22nd World Cup final
已经进入了点球阶段
has gone to penalties
没有出路了
there's no way through
已经进入了点球阶段
has gone to penalties
这个和其他的不一样
this one, like no other
今天
today
我觉得
I feel
疲惫
exhausted
在你的生活中
in your life
你见过那样的足球比赛吗
have you ever seen a game of football like that
更不用说世界杯决赛了
let alone a World Cup final
真的，真的很了不起
truly, truly extraordinary
看起来像梅西
it looked like Messi
又把他的队伍拉回来了
pulled his team back again
从悬崖边缘
from the brink
然后是梅西
and then Messi
从另一头下去，巴普尔
went down the other end and Bapé
第二次被罚
got his second penalty
第一对上演帽子戏法的球员
in the first pair to score a hat-trick
在世界杯决赛中
in a World Cup final
自1966年以来
since 1966
还有杰夫·赫斯特爵士
and a certain Sir Jeff Hurst
体育场里令人难以置信的场景
incredible scenes inside the stadium
不可思议的气氛
incredible atmosphere
我觉得没人会相信
I don't think anyone can quite believe
他们看到了什么
what they're seeing
艾伦，你见过这样的期末考试吗
well Alan, have you ever seen a final like this
更不用说世界杯决赛了?
let alone a World Cup final?
不，永远不会，我也不确定永远不会
No never, I'm not sure ever will either
这只是
it's just
疯狂，我是说珠宝
crazy, I mean the jewel
在沙漠里，你可以做任何事
in the desert, anything you can do
我能做得更好，因为你得到了两个
I can do better, seeing you get two
我的意思是，我会得到三个
I'm going to get three, I mean
我们问谁会脱颖而出
we asked who was going to come out on top
谁要在舞会上表演
who was going to perform at the very
非常高的水平
very highest level
反对最好的
against the best
在最重要的比赛中
in the biggest tournament of all
他们俩都是，只是
and both of them have, it's just been
绝对的无情的
absolutely relentless
来到这里真是难以置信
it's incredible to be here
两个球员都站起来了
both players have just stood up
他们是这场比赛的与众不同之处
they've been the difference in this game
如我们所愿，如我们所愿
as we hoped, as we wanted
现在我们有了终极的
and now we've got the ultimate
点球挑战
challenge of penalty shooting
真正有质量的时刻是他们两个球员
The real moments of quality has been them two players
我又踢了一脚，你知道这是什么吗
Bapé having another kick and do you know what it is
这种期末考试
this type of final
你想看看这两个
you want to see the two
最好的选手总是正面交锋
best players go head to head
他们已经针锋相对了
and they've just gone toe to toe
和绝对
and absolutely
他们的生活水平是我们从未见过的
they're living on a level that we've never ever seen
在这种阶段，这是最好的决赛
on this type of stages, this is the best final
我想这是每个人都梦寐以求的
I think anyone could have ever wished for
巴勃罗，我能听到你的心跳
Pablo, I can hear your heart pumping
从这里
from here
世界杯决赛太紧张了
This World Cup final is way too tense
我的意思是
I mean
不，只是
No, it's just
我们永远不会忘记那场比赛，这是肯定的
we'll never forget that game, that's for sure
我们很幸运能来到这里
we're so lucky to be here
我可以享受这样的比赛
I can enjoy a game like that
多么精彩的比赛啊
what a game
谢谢这位法国球员和阿根廷球员
thank you to the French player and Argentine
为了这个，为了那个游戏
for this, for that game
这太不可思议了
it's been incredible
我是说，决赛就在这里
The final will be up here, I mean
罚款单就在这里，离我们很近
the penalties will be up here near us, please
我要问你，你觉得谁会赢
I'm going to ask you who you think might win
我们真的不知道
we really don't know
Martínez的点球表现非常出色
Martínez has been superb from penalties
半决赛的点球大战
penalty shootout in the semi-final
对哥伦比亚
against Colombia
美洲杯冠军
in the Copa America
在对阵荷兰的第2次扑救中
in save two against Netherlands
让他们进入半决赛
to get them into the semi-finals
两届世界杯
two World Cups
是否由点球大战决定
have been decided by a penalty shootout
巴西在1994年击败了意大利
Brazil defeated Italy back in 1994
还记得巴乔时刻吗
remember the Baggio moment
意大利击败了法国
and Italy beat France
2006年
in 2006
阿根廷已经参与了六次点球大战
Argentina have been involved in six penalty shootouts
是世界杯历史上最多的
the most in World Cup history
并且赢得了最多的枪战胜利
and have claimed the most shootout victories
有5个
with five
他们唯一的败仗是德国
their only defeat came to Germany
回到2006年的1 / 4决赛
back in the 2006 quarter-finals
梅西和斯科洛尼
Lionel Messi and Lionel Scoloni
在那场比赛中有未使用的替补吗
were unused substitutes in that game
法国队赢得了世界杯四场点球大战中的两场
France won two of their four World Cup penalty shootouts
在1986年
in the 1986
1 / 4决赛对阵巴西
quarter-finals against Brazil
1998年1 / 4决赛对阵意大利
and 98 quarter-finals against Italy
法国在1982年输了
Les Bleus lost in the 1982
半决赛对阵西德
semi-finals versus West Germany
2006年的决赛
and in the 2006 final
对阵意大利，这些都不算数
versus Italy none of that counts
现在做什么都行
for anything now
回到杰梅因·格纳斯
back to Jermaine Genus
和盖伊·莫里
and Guy Mowry
谢谢你加里
thank you Gary
也是最重要的一次掷硬币
and the most important toss of the coin
本届世界杯
at this World Cup
走阿根廷的路
went Argentina's way
处罚将会被采取
the penalties will be taken
最后
at the end
在那里
at which there
粉丝戴着面具
fans are masked
并准备好发挥他们的作用
and ready to play their part
就像
as are
阿斯顿维拉的埃米·马丁内斯
Emi Martinez of Aston Villa
雨果·拉里斯
and Hugo Larisse
托特纳姆热刺队
of Tottenham Hotspur
马丁内斯喜欢心理游戏
Martinez likes the mind games
他要和大家谈一谈
he will have a word with everybody
敢于击球
daring to strike the ball
朝着他的目标前进
towards his goal
拉利斯多一点
Larisse a little more
一只很酷的猫
of a cool cat
好吧，好吧，好吧，到了这个地步
well well well it comes to this
你知道没有人比他更酷
you know no one's been as cool as this lad though
这是第三次了
stepping up for the third time
他大步走上去了
he's strided up there
充满自信
with so much confidence
应该是这样的
as it should be
姆巴佩将代表法国队率先出场
Mbappe will go first for France
姆巴佩将为法国队进球
and Mbappe will score for France
三次
three times
当场
on the spot
三次入网
three times in the net
这次他走对了路，马丁内斯
he goes the right way this time Martinez
我想他的手也在那里
gets his hand there as well I think
只是
just
烦恼地关闭
agonisingly close
无论你能做什么
whatever you can do
我也会努力做到的
I will endeavour to do as well
梅西要传达的信息是什么
is Lionel Messi's message
一个队的两个尖子生是什么意思
what are two top boys in a team
先迈出一步
stepping up first
如你所愿
as you like to see
而巴西却没有
as Brazil didn't do
任何东西
anything
与内马尔
with Neymar
他在想
he was left wondering
莱昂内尔·梅西永远不会这样
never going to be the case with Lionel Messi
他把它滚了进去
and he rolls it in
这很时髦
well that's stylish
这是难以置信的
that's incredible
这就是荒谬
ridiculous is what it is
只是冰而已
it's just ice
冷
cold
这不是正常的处罚
that is not a normal penalty
也不能在粉丝面前说
not in front of those fans as well
在这个时候这个场合
at this time this occasion
你每天都看到一些额外的东西
you've seen a bit of everything extra with every day
金斯利为法国队出场
Kingsley coming on the spot for France
马丁内斯说
say by Martinez
第一次欢呼
the first cheers
是阿根廷航空
are Argentinas
那个大个子是什么
what is the big man
在点球大战的大舞台上
for the big stage when it comes to penalty shootouts
马丁内斯
Martinez
他又猜对了
he's guessed the right way again
大大节省
big big save
打在他身上
hits him in the body
不重要
doesn't matter
他保存了它
he saved it
保罗·德·巴拉
Paulo de Bala
肯是替补
Ken was a substitute
在最后
at the very end
额外的时间
of extra time
这就是他被派来做的事
this is what he was brought on to do
德巴拉做到了
and de Bala does it
从中间直下
straight down the middle
2-1后2
2-1 after 2
对阿根廷有利
in Argentina's favour
谈谈梅西的点球
talk about Messi's penalty
顺便说一下，这也需要一些勇气
that takes some courage as well by the way
他没有从中间把球撞碎
he's not smashed it down the middle
把它从中间传下去
just passed it down the middle
还有一种疲劳
and the one tiredness
会造成损失
will take its toll
因为
because
这是一个年轻人
here's a young man
这几周谁做了些报道
who has covered some ground these last few weeks
蛹的
Aurelian
确定的人
sure man
马丁内斯刚刚把球扔了
Martinez has just thrown the ball away
他以前也这么做过
he's done that before
这都是他的一部分
this is all part of his
处罚程序
penalty routine
让他们工作
make them work
把它扔掉
just throw it away
令人难以置信的
unbelievable
只是裁判说了些难听的话
just stone words from the referee
当然，他得去取
sure man he had to fetch
当然，他真的必须得分
sure man he really has to score
宽
wide
马丁的心理战起作用了
the mind games of Martin has worked
他只是拖着它
he just drags it
毫无疑问，那个人就在那里
there's no doubt that man right there
会产生巨大影响吗
is having a massive impact
精神上
mentally
在这场点球大战中
in this penalty shootout
勇气
courage
感谢你一开始就站出来
for stepping up in the first place
你必须尊重它
you have to respect it
安卓的游行是
the Android parades is
现场的常客
a regular from the spot
你可以把阿根廷推到悬崖边上
you can put Argentina on the brink here
游行并
parades does
这正是他必须做的
exactly what he had to do
不管怎样
on one way or the other
阿根廷队踢了一脚温暖的球
Argentina a warm kick away
这不是他最好的
well it's not his best
重要的是它能打到网后
all that matters is it hits the back of the net
把脚伸进去就行了
just puts his foot through it
拉里斯走对了路
Larisse goes the right way
就是找不到足够强的人手
just can't quite get a strong enough hand on it
他又来了
there he goes again
马丁内斯
Martinez
裁判已经取得了球的所有权
the referee has taken ownership of the ball
这一次
this time
这是一张黄牌
and it is a yellow card
埃米·马丁内斯的支持者
for Emi Martinez as those French supporters
从另一端看
look on from the other end
他做到了
and he has
这就是他打球的方式
that's been the way he's played the game
他有一个巨大的机会
he had that huge chance
然后他让加时赛结束
then he let the end of extra time
我想他当时肯定是这么想的
I'm sure was on his mind then
但他完成了任务
but he's done the job
中路的点球猛击
great penalty smash right down the middle
这是为了世界杯
this for the World Cup
冈萨洛蒙特埃尔
Gonzalo Montiel
在一次踢球中
in one kick at the ball's time
他可以创造他的国家
he can make his country
足球世界的冠军
champions of the football world
这是阿根廷
it's Argentina
足球之王
Kings of football
第三次了
for the third time
眼泪也会落下
and the tears will fall
下来
down
第一届世界杯
the first World Cup
已经发生
to have taken place
自从迭戈死后
since the death of Diego
第一个赢了
the first one won
在莱昂内尔的生活中
in the life of Lionel
它触动了神经
it came down a nerve
阿根廷有瓶子
Argentina had the bottle
还有信念
and the belief
还有一个守门员
and a goalkeeper
谁尽其所能
who did everything within his power
为了绝对确定
to make absolutely sure
他们做到了
that they did it
艰难的道路
the hard way
再一次
again
那个人
and that man
最伟大的之一
one of the greatest
可以说是最伟大的
arguably the greatest
永远不要玩这个游戏
ever to play the game
谁是世界杯冠军
is a World Cup winner
我不能
I can't
想想刚才看到的是什么
get my head around what I've just witnessed
作为一个游戏
as a game
最伟大的时刻之一
one of the greatest moments
在足球史上
in football in history
法国人的荣誉
credit to the French
敬那边那个人
to that man right there
他们尽一切努力重返赛场
they did everything to get back into this game
他有一个世界杯孵化场
he's got a World Cup hatchery
他会再来的
and he will come again
哦，他会的
oh yes he will
他太好了
he's too good not to
这支法国队也将如此
and so will this France team
它有这么多的年轻人
that's got so much youth on its side
潜力巨大
and so much potential
特别是对一对夫妇来说
for a couple particularly
阿根廷蓝白罢工
in the Argentina blue and white strikes
梅西和迪玛利亚
Lionel Messi and Angel Di Maria
就是这样
this was it
最后一球
last shot
这是比赛所能给予的最大荣耀
at the greatest glory the game can give
在他们都发挥了各自的作用之后
and after they both played their part
在一场不朽的比赛中
in a monumental match
整整两个多小时
all two hours plus of it
你会相信吗
would you believe it it's somebody rather
更多的无名
more unsung
冈萨洛蒙特埃尔
Gonzalo Montiel
谁曾有过辉煌的时刻
who had his moment in the sun
和塞尔吉奥·阿奎罗
and Sergio Acuero
只是一个普通的粉丝吗
is just a regular fan
今晚剩下的时间
for the rest of the night
你能想象布宜诺斯艾利斯的情景吗
can you imagine the scenes in Buenos Aires
及以后
and beyond
这是1986年以来的第一次
for the first time since 1986
阿根廷
Argentina
世界杯冠军
World Cup winners
哦，我的天
oh my word
一场永恒的决赛
a final for the ages
在等了36年之后
after a wait of 36 years
已故的伟大的迭戈
when the late great Diego
阿曼德马拉多纳
Armando Maradona
举起了世界杯奖杯
lifted the World Cup trophy
阿根廷又赢了
Argentina have won it again
这是他们历史上的第三次
the third time in their history
比如1986年的那支球队
like the team of 1986
他们在别人的帮助下完成了这件事
they have done it with the help
左脚的，矮小的天才
of a left footed, diminutive genius
比如86人的队伍
like the team of 86
他们以两比零领先
they led by two goals to nil
只剩几分钟了
with only minutes remaining
86年他们恢复了
like 86 they recovered
他们赢了
and they won
他们在点球大战中做到了
and they did it in a penalty shootout
而他们的对手
and they did it against a side who had
下一个真正伟大的足球运动员
the next truly great footballer
我们的时代
of our time
在Killianon Bapay
in Killianon Bapay
有一个球员做到过
one player has ever done before
这是1966年的杰夫·赫斯特
so Jeff Hurst in 1966
想象一下在世界杯决赛中上演帽子戏法
imagine scoring a hat-trick in a World Cup final
没有赢
and not winning
多么精彩的足球比赛啊，艾伦
what a game of football Alan
我从来没见过这样的事
I've never seen anything like it
只是
it was just
很高兴来到这里
it was a pleasure to be here
向他们俩说声谢谢
to say thank you to those two
梅西和蒂姆·巴佩
the Messi and to Tim Bapay
我在比赛前说过
I said before the game
我觉得这是写在星星上的
I felt it was written in the stars
为了最大的明星
for the biggest star
这是
it was
他们一直走的路
the way they kept going
他们的心态
the mentality they had
显示
to show
在处罚方面
in terms of the penalties
信念，勇气
the belief, the courage
罚点球在任何比赛中站在那里罚点球
to stand there and take a penalty in any game
更不用说最大的游戏了
let alone the biggest game
在他们之中
of them all
在比赛中
in the way the game shaped
干得好，谢谢你招待我们
well done and thank you for entertaining us
真是难以置信
it was just unbelievable
这当然是梅西为阿根廷队的最后一场比赛
Messi's last game of course for Argentina
最后一支舞
the last dance
产生了一个完美的10
has produced a perfect ten
我可以坐在这里
I can sit here
我可以告诉我的孙子们
and I can tell my grandkids
我就在这一刻
that I was here for this moment
为了这次决赛
for this final
能够坐在这里，我感到很幸运
I feel blessed to have been able to sit here
见证的不仅仅是梅西
and witness not only Messi
捧起世界杯
lift a World Cup
像他那样表演
and produce a performance like he has
而是为了看到下一代
but to see the next generation
伟大的到来
of greatness coming through
在Bapay
in Bapay
今天罚进三个点球
scoring three penalties today
在正常时间上演帽子戏法
and a hat-trick in normal time
这样结束国际职业生涯真是太好了
what a way to finish an international career
这是童话故事
this is fairy-tale business
巴勃罗，你会说话吗?
Pablo can you speak
告诉我这对阿根廷意味着什么
tell me what this means to Argentina
我的意思是
I mean
这是其中的一个时刻
it's one of those moments
对不起
sorry
没关系
that's okay
她在看梅西
she's looking at Messi
我知道这是什么意思
I know what it means
当我在阿根廷时，我也有同样的感觉
I feel the same when I'm at Argentina
这对法国来说真是太好了
it's just well done to France
和Bapay
and Bapay
大家都知道
everybody for that
伟大的比赛
great game
我们真的很喜欢
we really enjoy it
但是一个完美的故事
but a perfect story
对于梅西
for Messi
但我的意思是我们真的很喜欢
but I mean we really enjoy it
就像那个人说的
like the guy said
我很高兴，很开心
I'm so pleased and so happy
来到这里
to be here
享受它吧
be enjoying it
我知道你的情绪，我很清楚
I know your emotion and quite rightly
里面的人也是
so are all those people in there
告诉我们这意味着什么
tell us what it will mean
给莱昂内尔·梅西一个你非常熟悉的人
to Lionel Messi someone that you know very well
我的意思是
I mean
我也参与其中
I've been part of that
团队
team
青年队
the youth team
当他第一次来的时候
when he came for the first time
为国家队效力
to play for the national team
他是来代表
he came to represent
他的国家和激情
his country and the passion
还有尊重
and the respect
他总是为我们的国家效力
he always shown for our country
这是我们一直需要感激的
something that we always need to appreciate
那不是很久以前的事
it's not that long ago
当然，他退出了国际足坛
of course he retired from international football
因为在美洲杯的失利
because of the defeat in the Copa America
他们在决赛中的第三个进球
the third one that they had in the final
他再也受不了了
he couldn't handle it anymore
但他现在回来了
but he's come back now
他不仅赢得了美洲杯
he's won not only the Copa America
但现在最大的奖赏是
but now the greatest prize of them all
当然，这是他应得的
absolutely and he deserved it
100%
看，每个人都在哭
look everyone is just crying
给了他很大的伤害
and giving him a big hurt
Pablo Mar和大家
Pablo Mar and everybody
因为
because
他就是其中之一
he's one of those players
这是他应得的
he really deserves it
他总是住在
he's always had to live in
尽管他是个小个子
even though he was a small guy
马拉多纳的巨大影子
the giant shadow of Diego Armando Maradona
这是很困难的
and that has been difficult
但他现在已经结束了
but he's now done
迭戈做了什么，他要举起来了
what Diego did and he's going to lift
那个小
that small
金质美丽奖杯
gold beautiful trophy
足球史上最伟大的奖杯
greatest trophies in football
为了我们的国家
and for our country
我们将收到图片
we'll receive picture of
马拉多纳
Maradona
和梅西都是最伟大的球员
and Messi two of the greatest players
是有史以来最伟大的球员
of all time with the World Cup trophy
这是
that's something
难以置信的
incredible
他给了我们很多快乐
he's given us so much pleasure
近二十年来有这么多的欢乐
so much joy over nearly two decades
我看了无数场比赛
I mean I've watched countless games
和你在一起
with those you Rio
你和艾伦在一起的时候
and you Alan when we've been
离开座位看着那个人
off our seats watching that man
执行
perform
这是表演者的水平，但令人震惊的事情
it's the level of performers but the staggering thing
仅仅是做这件事的时间
is just the amount of time it's done it for
就像你说的，这家伙已经上位二十年了
like you say two decades this guy's been at the top
做这个迷人的动作
doing this mesmerising
不仅是球迷，还有对手
not only fans but opponents
你没什么可说的了
there's not much more you can say
他们都说了
they've said it all
但它只是能够在这个阶段
but it's just being able to be in this stage
能站在这里我感到非常非常幸运
and I just feel very very blessed that I'm here
能够做到这一点
to be able to do that
那里的人会被摧毁
and those guys there will be destroyed
但他们已经发挥了自己的作用
but they've played their part
我现在不会考虑或担心这个问题
not that I'll think about that or worry about that now
但法国人扮演了怎样的角色
but what a role the French did
精神了，心就回来了
the spirit, the heart to come back
在我八十分钟没有真正待在这里之后
after my honest 80 minutes of not really being here
在游戏中做出一款惊艳的游戏
in the game to make a stunning game
结束这场游戏
with an end to this game
他们可以在法国人面前昂首挺胸
they can hold their heads up high though the French
因为至少在最后
because at least in the end
在将近80分钟的时间里，他们都没有
for almost 80 minutes they didn't
他们没有踢
they didn't have a kick
80分钟加里
for 80 minutes Gary
他们看起来非常疲倦
they looked very leggy and tired
我们以为它会渐渐消失
and we just thought it was going to drift away
对他们来说，突然之间他们得到了点球
for them and all of a sudden they get the penalty
和
and
我们说了多久了
how long have we been saying it goes
改变了游戏，那一个确实改变了
change games and that one did
然后突然间他得到了他的
and then all of a sudden he gets his
第二个，后面这个
second one and back here
额外的时间呢?
what about extra time
两支球队都有难以置信的机会
both teams had incredible opportunities
然后是杂乱的分数
and then messy scores
最后有一个点球
at the end there's a penalty
厄普马卡诺有几次不可思议的抢断
Uppermakarno with a couple of incredible tackles
马提尼来了
Martini's came on
错过了一个机会，然后他拿到了把手
and missed a chance and then he had the handle
最后是科林·莫尼
and then Colin Moani at the end
这是无情的
it was relentless
有人写了这个剧本
someone who wrote in this script
把它变成了一出戏剧
and just made it an absolute drama
这是非凡的，我们上下起伏，我们尖叫
it was phenomenal we were up and down we were screaming
我们有时几乎失声了
we almost lost my voice at times
但法国发挥了他们的作用
but France playing their part
他们进入了决赛，并取得了绝对的胜利
they've got into the final and made an absolute game of it
少了六七颗星
with six or seven stars missing
它告诉你这个团队的深度
it tells you the depth of this team
那角色呢?
what about the character
这支阿根廷队
of this Argentina team
经理
and the manager
太零了，不能巡航
to be too nil to be cruising
突然你就倒在地上了
and all of a sudden you're on the floor
这是2 - 2
it's 2-2
然后你开始追逐游戏
and then you start chasing the game
你会想，我的天哪
and you think oh my goodness
然后他们又进了一个球，然后法国又反超了
and then they get another goal then France come back again
回到这里，然后他们走了
and back here and then they go
赢点球再起来
win the penalties again to get up
然后继续
and keep going
真的很惊人
really is staggering
真的是，让我们提醒自己
really is, let's remind ourselves
点球大战的闹剧
the penalty shootout drama
因为这是戏剧
because drama it was
在一场
after a game of
令人难以置信的戏剧
incredible drama
你不可能真的编造出来
you couldn't really make it up
我只是，我觉得
I just, I felt what
让他们重新回到了游戏中
sort of got them back into the game
法国的情况是
France was in terms of
他们的青春，他们的活力和他们的腿
their youthfulness and their energy and their legs
两者我都想要
I really wanted both
还有巴佩和梅西
and Bapay and Messi
无论结果如何都要得分
to score whatever the result
因为他们应该那样做，而不是做那个人
because they deserve to do that and not be the person
这可能会让你打领带
that perhaps let you tie
顺便说一下，我们提到过
by the way we've mentioned
梅西和他周围的其他球员
Messi and all the other players around him
我们可能还没有提到
we perhaps haven't mentioned
也是最大牌的明星之一
one of the biggest stars as well
马丁,
Martin as
我是说他
I mean he's
这是不正常的
that was out of order
以自由
taking liberties
然后科曼来到这里
and then Corman comes up here
他想给他们上发条
and he's trying to wind them up
他把球踢开了
he's kicking the ball away
他在和球员们说话
he's talking to the players
你可以看到他在做什么
you can see what he's doing
给他们尽可能多的压力
much pressure on them as possible
他是他们所谓的大师
he's a master of what they call
一些housary
something housary
甚至连他的动作都在线上
even his movements on the line
他在线后面移动，就像
he's behind the line moving just like
试图吸引击球者的目光
trying to get the eye of the person who's striking the ball
看这个小东西
watch this little thing here
就像
just as
他的点球太多了，不是吗
too many isn't it going on to take his penalty
从
watch this from
真是厚脸皮
just cheeky really
只是你知道
just you know
看，他也在让他的群众行动起来
see he's getting his crowd going as well
给你，去拿那个伙计
there you go, go and get that mate
让他走，让他等
make him walk, make him wait
下山的路够长了
the walk down is long enough
他们看起来很长腿
they look leggy that
不管怎样，不管我们看到了多么优秀的球员
no matter what and no matter how good we've seen the best players
罗伯特·巴乔在台湾报道
Roberto Baggio in Taiwan
他是世界上罚丢点球最好的球员之一
one of the best in the world missing penalties
看看这家伙，伙计
look at this guy man
这是制胜点球
and this is the winning penalty
好了
there you go
打算到
Montiel until
对他来说，这是多么难忘的一刻啊
what a moment for him to remember
永远
forever
这种事发生了两次，不是吗
it happens twice haven't they
点球大战中的阿根廷
Argentina with the penalties
看到他们对阵荷兰
saw them against the Netherlands
很好
very good
我认为这将是非常聪明的
I think it's going to be really smart
这里供您享用
here for your pleasure
和快乐巴勃罗
and joy Pablo
阿根廷的解说员是怎样的
is how the Argentinian commentators
描述获胜的时刻
describe the winning moment
蒙特埃尔冈萨洛
Montiel Gonzalo
打算阿拉
Montiel Alarcón
阿根廷
Argentina
世界冠军
world champion
阿根廷
Argentina
世界冠军
world champion
我们都是蒙蒂尔
we are all Montiel
在波特的幻觉中
in that illusion of potter
在阿根廷的土地上
in that Argentinian soil
肯佩斯来的那个
the one from Kempes
迪·斯蒂法诺的那个
the one from Di Stefano
马拉多纳的那个
the one from Maradona
从蒙蒂埃尔来的那个
the one from Montiel
来自梅西的那个
the one from Messi
我们是世界冠军
we are world champion
永恒的眼泪
the eternal tears
眼泪
tears
现在
now
一切都结束了
it's over
阿根廷
Argentina
新的世界冠军是谁
is the new world champion
阿根廷
Argentina
世界冠军
champion of the world
我想我们不知道那是什么意思
I think we don't know what that means
绝对精彩的
absolutely brilliant
我的意思是看到所有的球员
I mean see all the players
他们只是继续庆祝
they just keep celebrating
多么美妙的一刻
what a moment
我们一直在等待的国家
country we've just been waiting
那么久的一刻
so long for a moment
说说莱昂内尔·斯科洛尼
a word on Lionel Scoloni
不是梅西，而是另一个莱昂内尔
not Messi's the other Lionel
我是说他做了很多工作
I mean a lot of job he's done
想象一下要去接球员
imagine having to pick the players up
在正常时间结束的时候
at the end of ordinary time
在加时赛之后
and again after extra time
这两次法国都是无中生有
both times France have grasped something from nowhere
做了一个
made a
今天的明智决定
some smart decision today
带着迪·瓦拉
bringing Di Vala
去平原塔
to the Plain Tissier Tower
我们做了很多斯科洛尼
we created a lot of Scoloni
我们参加过美洲杯
we've been in Copa America
和没有经验的世界杯
and World Cup with no experience
而且他从来没教过俱乐部的招牌
and he's never coached a club sign
这一点很重要
that's a huge point
所有这些都说你必须有经验
all of that talk about you have to have experience
你必须有一份工作
you have to have had a job
你必须在这个游戏中管理很长时间
you have to have been in the game a long time managing
他不知从哪里冒出来的
he's come out of nowhere
指导这个团队
and just guided this team
马克龙总统与姆巴佩在一起
President Macron there with Mbappe
和
and
他是姆巴佩的英雄
well he's been a hero of Mbappe
我知道这是小小的安慰
small consolation I know
但他当然赢了
but he does win of course
梅西即将夺冠，直到
Messi was about to win it until
他得到了第二次罚球
he got his second penalty
他的第三个进球是哪个
which was his third goal
在游戏中
in the game
帽子戏法打入世界杯决赛
Hattrick had a World Cup final
没有赢
and not winning
难以想象的
unimaginable
但他的
but he's
确认他的地位
confirmed his status
他要上场了
he's taking the bat on
他不是来自梅西吗
isn't he from Lionel Messi
他会交出的
he'll hand that over
他会知道这将是一个舒适的手
and he'll know it's going to be in comfortable hands
我之前在一个节目里说过
I said this before on one of the shows previously
我只是希望我们能参加这次比赛
that I was just wishing that we'd come into this tournament
超级明星们带着他们的
and the superstars came out with their
心中的名声
reputations in hearts
这两个家伙姆巴佩和梅西
these two guys Mbappe and Messi
他们的表演真的做到了吗
have absolutely done that with their performances
他们的目标和重要时刻
their goals and big moments
他们生产的
they've produced
我刚收到一张纸条
I've just been handed a note
杰夫·赫斯特爵士发了一条推特
on a tweet from Sir Jeff Hearst
祝贺姆巴佩
many congratulations to Mbappe
不管发生什么，我都跑得很好
whatever happens I've had a great run
他当然有
he certainly has
56年
56 years
差不多就是这样，直到别人做了
something like that until somebody else did it
有一天它碰巧发生了
it happened to happen one day
但从没想过你会对失败者做什么
but never envisages you doing to the loser
加时赛太棒了
extra time was amazing
让我们提醒自己
let's remind ourselves
梅西如何看待阿根廷
how Messi put Argentina
三人一头
three to a head
这是令人窒息的加里
it was breathless Gary
我们只是毫无头绪
we just didn't have a clue
它要往什么方向走啊
what way it was going to go
它是首尾相连的
it was end to end
我们只是在想不可能
and we're just thinking no
然后你可以看到
and then you can see
他的胃口很饿
he's hungry on his appetite
无论如何，这都是一次难以置信的扑救
it was an unbelievable save to get in there anyway
但
but
这不是他的好作品之一
it wasn't one of his better ones
但他不会介意的
but he will not mind it
但他也参与了建设
but he was involved in the build-up as well
但是，很明显
but it was, yeah, obviously
这就是我们所说的适当的目标
it was what we call a proper goal at it
他的反应很好，不是吗
he reacts really well doesn't he
他走了，你可以看到
and he's off you can see
他的离开
he's away
好一个时刻，以为他真的赢了
what a moment, thinks he's won it really
谁在加时赛中一球扳回
and who comes back from a goal in extra time
巴普莱尔做了什么
on Bapé does
没错，他们是一支年轻的球队
exactly and they were a youthful side
法国
France
他们表现出了惊人的韧性
they showed ridiculous resilience
和性格
and character
然后又回到了那里
and got himself back in it
在巴普尔前进的步伐中不甘落后
not to be outdone in Bapé's step forward
是的，这是一个点球，但是这个点球是巴普尔赢得的
yes it was a penalty but it was a penalty won by Bapé
这是
it was
戏剧性的时刻
a dramatic moment
你知道我们在谈什么吗
do you know what we talk about
巴普尔的步伐是你首先提到的
in Bapé's pace being one of the first things you mentioned
不管怎么说，他的顶角不是
aim top cornerish wasn't it anyway
当你谈论他的时候，每个人都在谈论
when you talk about him everyone talks about
这是你喜欢的平静
this is calm as you like
这不是他的目标
not one of his goals
在本届世界杯上是建立在速度上的吗
was built on pace in this World Cup
他是在整个
he's all from being inside the entire
区域精密整理
area's precision finishing
他有很多优点
he's got so many strengths
就在我们表演得非常非常好的时候
just while we're on very very good performances
顺便说一下
by the way
我认为裁判也值得赞扬
I think the referee deserves great credit as well
他做决定时很勇敢
he was brave with his decisions
他的决定是
his decisions were
他们中的绝大多数是正确的
the vast majority of them were correct
裁判的表现非常出色
and it was a big performance from the referee
这是一个伟大的团队
it was a great team
精彩的表演
good show
梅西
Messi
拉开比分
opened the score
顺便说一下，如果你想看国家文件
by the way if you want to see Countryfile
现在
it's now
已经转到BBC了
it's been shifted to BBC
BBC2
我们正在关注阿根廷
we're watching the country of Argentina
在看台上庆祝
celebrate in the stands
那是很久以前的事了
it was an awfully long time ago
现在,
now that
梅西首开纪录，这是真的
Messi opened the score and it came from
迪玛利亚赢得了一个点球
a penalty won by Di Maria
他扮演了重要的角色
he played an important part
没有参加比赛的阿根廷队
for Argentina who hasn't played
在淘汰赛阶段超过九分钟
in the knockout stage beyond nine minutes
在我之后是最好的球员
after me was the best player
阿根廷在上半场的表现
for Argentina in the first half
我的意思是
I mean
当他下来的时候，他能看到不同
he could see the difference when he came off
他已经火了
he's been on fire
其中一个球员
one of those players
他是个大玩家
he's a big game player
绝对
absolutely
我们谈到了迪玛利亚下场的事
we spoke about Di Maria coming off the pitch
他绝对是一个点球，他一直在射门
he's definitely a penalty he kept clips in there
让他夹到自己的脚踝，但当他离开球场时
makes him clip his own ankle but when he came off the pitch
我希望有一个小球员来顶替他
I'd love to have had a little player come on him
那么长时间他都在板凳上
for that amount of time he's on the bench
因为他哭得泪流满面
because he was up and down crying tears
情感
emotion
也许他不该把他带走
perhaps he shouldn't have taken him off
也许他有能力再多打一点比赛
perhaps he had it in him to play a bit more
若无其事地收起来
nonchalantly put away
有点像他在点球大战中的点球
a little bit like his penalty in the shootout
它不是在等守门员吗
wasn't it just waiting for the goalkeeper
我就走那条路
I'll go that way
哇
wow
然后迪玛利亚拿到了第二个
and then Di Maria got the second
还有
and there's
梅西的孩子们在球场上
Messi's children on the pitch
显示
show
我告诉你，你爸爸不坏
your dad's not bad I tell you
他不坏
he's not bad
他是最伟大的球员之一
he's one of the greats
那不是很美吗?
isn't that beautiful
梦想的东西
stuff for dreams
想象一下，梅西是你的父亲
imagine having Messi as your dad
我每天在学校都是队长
I'm captain every day at school
每一次都为你而战
every single time playing for you
我是队长
I'm captain
ambulous
这就是庆祝的意义所在
that's what it's about though celebrating
离你最近的人就在你身边
and you've got the nearest and nearest next to you
当然，他也参与了第二件事
and he was involved of course in the second
进球很漂亮
goal which was a beautiful
团队继续
team go on
这是一个惊人的传球
it was an amazing goal passing
在这个阶段
and moving and at this stage
法国就是无法接近
France just couldn't get near
这支阿根廷队
this Argentine team
因此你可以看到斯科洛尼
because of this you can see Scoloni
在场外给他们带来压力
on the sidelines putting them under pressure
赢回球
winning the ball back
抓住最早的机会，然后当你得到它的时候
at the earliest opportunity then when you get it
通过这个吗?
do this pass
搬到后面
move in behind
Callister把它平方了
Callister squares it
迪玛丽亚去了
Di Maria took to the
我们真的真的很好
we're really really well
把它插进土里
so stabs it into the ground
他不知道是谁结束了
doesn't he which gets it over
lorice
很好的完成
good finish
你认为他是去敷衍了事吗
do you think he went to bobble it over
我在那里有点幸运
I was a bit fortunate there
我不确定这个游戏会发生什么
I'm not sure what happens in this game
确实如此
it really was
就这样了
and that was it for
80分钟后，我们真的认为这个游戏
80 minutes and we actually thought this game
在阿根廷鬼鬼祟祟的鬼鬼祟祟
was just creeping out in Argentina in control
他们往后坐了一会儿
they sat back a little bit
但法国从来没有真正的样子
but France never really looked like
做任何事
doing anything
他们没有射中目标
they hadn't had a shot on target
那是一次糟糕的防守
that was a poor defending
他们只是一对一的
one on one they had just
一出场就改变了一切
made a difference coming on
你可以看到
and you can see what
科芬在细节上有所选择
Coffin had chooses about details
他是一个经验丰富的后卫，他不应该这么做
he's an experienced defender he should not
做这样的挑战
be making that kind of challenge
我总是觉得自己很有钱
I always feel with lots of money
在比赛中你有一个机会
there is one in a game you have a chance
反对他，就是这样
against him and that was that
他差点就救了那个人，不是吗
he nearly saved that one didn't he
有几个姆巴佩的手被他摸过
there were a couple of Mbappe's he got a hand on
这完全改变了游戏的势头
and this changed the complete momentum of the game
他们根本就不存在
they were never anywhere near being
在这场比赛中，突然之间
in this game and all of a sudden
这发生了，你想
that happens and you think
现在姆巴佩活过来了
wow Mbappe just comes alive
那是在86秒之后
it was 86 seconds later
我去的时候我们都快疯了
we was going crazy when I was going
你曾经是你曾经
you were you were
我在尖叫，我知道你疯了
I was screaming I know you're messy mad
我只想要美丽的
I just wanted the beautiful
故事
story
换元的好处是什么
what was great was the substitution
科芬在这里又起了作用
again Coffin plays a role here
他把它掐掉了，尽管它很值钱
he pinched it off messy it's worth
他说你知道，人无完人
saying he's you know nobody's perfect
加油吧，这里有助攻
cheer on with it with the assist here
这是一个很棒的头向下看
it's a great little header down look at
他跑过了他的选手，完成了比赛
he runs off his runner and that finish
伙计们带我走过
guys took me through it
技术令人难以置信
the technique is unbelievable
你几乎没有机会踢他，直到点球
you barely had a kick did he until the penalty
事实上，点球是他们的第一次努力
in fact the penalty was their first effort
瞄准目标80分钟
on target for 80 minutes
然后突然你就得到了点球
and then all of a sudden you get the penalty
信心随之改变
confidence then changes
大男孩
great boy
我还以为他会有点本事呢
I was thinking he would have a touch
我想把它拿走，然后插进去
I was thinking take it and then slot it
但你这么厉害就不需要了
but you don't need to when you're that good
这也是一个伟大的运动
it's a great movement as well
把球放进去，然后旋转
lays it off inside and spins
你看，它们还在那儿
look at that and they're still there
他们会庆祝到深夜
they'll be celebrating all into the night
他们平静了一点
they've calmed down a little bit
整个体育场都陷入了一片黑暗
the stadium's gone into a little bit of darkness
我想我们可能已经很接近了
I think we're probably quite close
到演讲环节
to the presentations
我们有一些场景
we've got some scenes from
布宜诺斯艾利斯，我想你可以想象
Buenos Aires I think you can imagine
它们可能相当辉煌
they're probably quite glorious
时间在上面
the time's up there
现在是早上6个小时，不是吗
it's six hours in the morning isn't it
没有
no
他们必须输
they have to lose
20-3
在夏天
in the summertime
看看这有多神奇
look at the fancies this is
一个我们平常待的地方
a place where we're normally
赢得世界杯
wins world cup
这是制胜时刻
this is the winning moment
很多球员
a lot of the players
直行
just went straight
像他们那样胡闹
to messing as they did
美洲杯冠军
in the Copa America
这群球员
this group of players
他们只是
they've just been
为…而战
fighting for the
阿根廷的衬衫
Argentine shirt
为了国家
for the country
但对梅西来说
but for Messi
这太疯狂了，不是吗
it's crazy that isn't it
阿根廷赢得了6次点球大战
Argentina have won six penalty shootouts
世界杯历史上七场比赛中
in world cup history out of seven
比其他任何国家都多
more than any other country
在竞争中
of the competition
你真勇敢，巴勃罗
you're a gutsy lot Pablo
心态
mentality
心态的怪物
mentality monsters
我想我们有
I think we have that
心理总是
mentality always
我们有那种韧性
we have that toughness
那些时刻
those moments where
我们真的需要
we really need to bring
每个人都在一起
everyone together
你们这群人很坚强
there's a ruggedness about you guys
我们担心自己
we worry us
再给你一个小数据
another little stat for you
这是第一个得分的球员
this is the first player to score
在小组赛阶段
in the group stages
16强进入四分之一决赛
the round of 16 the quarterfinal
半决赛
semi-final
现在我知道你会告诉我
now I know you'll tell me
你在世界杯的每一场比赛都有进球
you scored in every game in the world cup
但我确实知道
in 1970 but I do know
那时候没有16强赛
in those days there was no round of 16
好了
so there you go
在阿根廷
in Argentina
你说这对球员来说是很大的压力吗
is that a big pressure you say for the players
当你也玩的时候
when you played as well
你是想为那位伟人赢得什么
you're trying to win something for that great man there
因为我们的主题是针对玩家的
because our theme for the players
我们有机会和他并肩作战吗
is that we have the opportunity to play alongside him
我们知道怎么做
and we know how
他是一个人
he's as a person
以及这对梅西来说意味着什么
and what it means for Messi playing
为了他的国家，然后
for his country and then
当我们连续输掉决赛时
when we lost to the consecutive final
他受到了很多批评
he's got a lot of criticism
我想是其中之一
I think it was one of those
每个人都想玩的时刻
moments that everyone wanted to play
为梅西赢得胜利
and win for Messi
因为我们看到他哭了
because we saw him crying
在更衣室里
in the dressing room
在公共汽车上
in the bus
这就是为什么我认为
and that's why I think
压力是存在的
the pressure was there
这是给梅西的
which is for Messi
这就对了
well there you go
梅西跳起来
Messi jumps up
现在有13个进球
with 13 goals now
所以只要杀了巴普，他就有12个
so just killing Bap he's got 12
他才23岁
he's only 23
我们不能在这张图上再深入一点吗
can't we go down a bit further on that graphic
你已经看过你的名字了
you've seen your name enough
也许他有赔率
Bap he's got to be odds on
我觉得他会打败所有人的
I think he's going to beat everyone
就目标而言
in terms of goals
我们永远不知道发生了什么
we never know what happens in
球队
the squad
是27 31
it will be 27, 31
也许还有3个
maybe 3 more
就像现在的球员一样
the way players are now
他们的职业生涯更长久
they've got greater longevity in their careers
他参加过球队吗
did he play in the squad
他在人群中
he was in the crowd
他不在队里
he wasn't in the squad
但最后他跑下来了
but he came down running down at the end
他是我的超级粉丝
he's a big fan
很明显
obviously
他为阿根廷踢了很多场比赛
he's played so many games for Argentina
他显然是非常亲密的朋友
he's obviously very close friends
致莱昂内尔·梅西
to Lionel Messi
你相信这就是我们的团队
and you believe this is the team
最终输给了沙特阿拉伯
that actually lost to Saudi Arabia
沙特可能在庆祝
Saudi are probably celebrating
我们击败了世界冠军
we beat the world champions
别担心，我们没有丢照片
don't worry we've not lost pictures
它完全陷入了黑暗
it's just gone into complete darkness
他们把灯熄了
they've put the lights out
现在你可以看到一些人把他们的
now you can see a few people putting their
火把在
torches on
天啊，我很喜欢
God I enjoyed that
我的意思是
I mean
我们上气不接下气了
we're breathless up here
真是难以置信
it was just an unbelievable
最后
final
很高兴来到这里
it was great to be here
我从来没见过这样的事
I've never seen anything like it
我想我再也见不到这样的事了
and I don't think I'll ever see anything like it
这又是
again it was
惊人的
staggering
在我们等待报告的时候
while we're waiting for the presentations
我们也许可以回顾一下其他重要的时刻
we can perhaps run through some of the other major moments
在游戏中
in the game
塔兰和裁判一起跳水
Taran dive with the referee
我们都认为这是惩罚
we all thought penalty from up here
然后裁判给了他一张黄牌
and then the referee gave him a yellow card
我们想，哇
and we thought wow
然后我们看回放你就知道为什么了
and then we see the replay you can see why
很好，我认为裁判很棒
it was good I thought the referee was magnificent
我们当时都在喊罚点球
we were all up here shouting penalty
但他就快成功了
but he was right close to it
他很清楚自己是果断的
he was clear he was decisive
他马上就知道了，马上就做出了决定
he knew straight away made his decision straight away
很好
very good
我还以为他能应付这么大的场合呢
I thought he handled it such a big occasion
非常非常好
really really well
他以前是一名球员，我想知道这是否有什么不同
he's a former player I wonder if that makes a difference
我以为他只是把他的
from there I thought then he just puts his
然后你看到塔兰把他的腿放进
and then you see Taran puts his leg into
这名后卫
the defender
这是一个伟大的决定
it was a great decision
非常非常好
very very good
在加时赛结束时
in the end of extra time
这很不寻常
which was extraordinary
梅西差一点就赢了，不是吗
Messi nearly won it didn't he with his shot
那只是一个普通的时间，不是吗
that's just an ordinary time wasn't it
我在这个游戏中得到了很多东西
I'm getting so many things going on in this game
我记得是在第98分钟
this was I think in the 98th minute
那不是很平常吗，然后我们想
wasn't it an ordinary time and then we thought
另一个神奇之处
another bit of magic
一记突然转向的凶狠的打击
and a swerving vicious strike
不管怎样，都可能进一码
a yard either way it probably goes in
他总是处在危险的边缘
he was always just on the edge of this
像这样的游戏
this game like this
你可以看到他只是在制造那一刻
you could see him just producing the moment
结束游戏
to end the game
他的扑救很漂亮
he's had a good save
他在世界杯上表现非常出色
he's had a really good world cup
但他不会扑出点球
but he doesn't save penalties
我们说的是这种状态的梅西
we're talking about Messi in this form
像他那样决定所有的比赛
and deciding all the games like he has
他35岁了
he's 35 years old
这是荒谬的
it's ridiculous
也许他是我的，他想参加下一届世界杯
maybe he's mine and he wants to play a next world cup
称他为小快乐吧
call him a lessen joy
正式的季节
formal season
只要踢下一届世界杯
just play the next world cup
如果他赢了可能会很好
probably good if he won it
在赢得这场比赛之后
after winning this one
人们现在会喜欢它的
people will love it now
你说现在就这样了吗
would you say that's it now
完全做到了
doing it completely
还没有完成游戏
haven't completed the game
我觉得他很好，我是说
I think he's well I mean
他还需要什么呢
what more does he need
他现在不需要向任何人证明什么了
he doesn't need to prove anything to anyone now
梅西想要一切
Messi does he want absolutely everything
游戏必须提供
the game has to offer
他给了我们很多快乐
he's given us so much joy
他进了成百上千个球
he's scored hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of goals
还有一些非常非常重要的
and some really really important ones
在主要比赛中
in major competitions
你知道吗?
he does you know
他最不可思议的运球手
his most unbelievable dribbler
他有非凡的远见
he has an extraordinary vision
目前已有793个进球
793 goals now
那太荒唐了
that's ridiculous
今天之后
after today in
1003年奥运会
1003 games
阿根廷98分
98 for Argentina
你知道，这并不坏
it's not bad you know
还不错，如果他能
it's not bad and if he could
他在本届世界杯上打进的两个点球
the two shootout ones he scored in this world cup
如果能进100个球，那就很不错了
that would be 100 goals that would have been quite good
这不公平，不是吗
it's not fair is it
把它们分享出去，给别人一个机会
share them out and give someone else a chance
我想姆巴佩可能会跟进
I think Mbappe might follow on
他将
he will
绝对是一个球员
absolutely what a player
多么精彩的表演啊
what a performance
Martínez也制作
Martínez also made
真是个英雄
quite a hero
另一个英雄
another hero to now
他的左脚扑救真是太棒了，不是吗
it was a fantastic save with his left foot wasn't it
绝对精彩的
absolutely brilliant
你需要
and you need
门将,
goalkeeper to
你知道怎么救
you know to make a save
我想可能是为了比赛
probably save for the tournament I would say
然后它直接到另一端
and then it went straight to the other end
它和另一个Martínez
didn't it and the other Martínez
那个出现的
the one that came on
梅西的一个漂亮的重球
a nicely weighted ball from Messi
在右手边看看这个
down the right hand side look at this for a chance
我是说这真的就像
I mean it's a really it's like
你以前说的话
what you used to say ahead
它就像油门一样在前面
it's got ahead like a throttling bit
真是节省啊
what a save
多么精彩的扑救，然后又是一个大失误
what a save and then a big miss
它的优点是什么
what was great about it
在任何时候都没有人处于不利地位
there was no one on the back foot at any point
没有人会想要后退一步
no one ever was like taking a step back
就像两个盒子围在一个圈里互相厮杀
it was like two boxes in a ring just slugging it out
我们能看这部电影真是太棒了
it was brilliant for us to watch it
显贵们来了
here come the dignitaries
那边是范蒂诺先生
Gnm Fantino there
带他们出去
leading them out
为
for the
我想他们会在仪式上
ceremony where I think they would give out the
发出
give out the
金色的球
golden ball the golden
金色手套
glove the golden
年轻球员奖
the young player award
是的
yeah
在演讲开始前一段时间
so about a little time before the presentation
本身
itself
这里的运动鞋选择很有趣
interesting choice of trainers there from
Gnm Fantino
他多大了?
how old is he?
这是卡塔尔的埃米尔
there's the Amir of Qatar
当然是马克龙总统
President Macron of course
加里，我们知道我们会拿到金靴的
Gary we know we're going to get the golden boot
显然还能拿到世界杯奖杯
and obviously get handed the World Cup
我们认为谁是年轻球员?
who are we thinking young player?
贝灵汉还有机会吗
will Bellingham have a chance
这取决于年龄，因为如果
it depends on the age because if
如果数到23，可能是姆巴佩
it could be Mbappe if it counts up to 23
这取决于年龄
it depends on the age
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez
有什么安慰吗?
is there a consolation
你觉得姆巴佩怎么样
do you think from Mbappe
艾伦赢得了金靴
Allen winning the golden boot
不是真正的
not really
你在大赛中赢过一次
you've won one in a major tournament
一切都是为了赢得比赛
it's all about winning it
当然，这是事实
of course and that's the truth
这是奖金，仅此而已
it's a bonus but nothing more
就是这样
that's all it is
这是一场精彩的表演
it's quite a show
也许是午夜时分
maybe it's about midnight
很抱歉
sorry about this
我们最终会到达的
we'll get there in the end
所有重要的人都到位了
all the important people in place
现在球员们
now the players
他做得很好
he did a great job
令人印象深刻
very impressive
环境也很艰难
tough circumstances as well
如何裁判
how to referee
在极端压力下
under extreme pressure
如何处理这一切
how to handle it all
我认为所有的重大决定都是正确的
got all the big decisions right I think
他很坚定，不是吗
he was firm wouldn't he
从不觉得有压力
never looked under pressure
他处理得非常非常好
he handled it really really well
真正的公司
really firm
你说他打橄榄球
the fact that you said he played football
大人物
a big shot
我不知道这是否会鼓励
I wonder if this will encourage
也许更多的是前球员
more perhaps ex-players
对裁判
to referee
你觉得这是件好事吗
do you think that would be a good thing
我觉得这是件好事
I think it would be a good thing
我不会这么做的
I wouldn't do it
你把所有的
what you made over all of the
比赛中裁判的标准
standard of refereeing in this tournament
艾伦
Allen
我认为首先
I think to begin with
这是一份艰苦的工作
it's a tough job
绝对是的
absolutely yeah
我想这就是为什么它很重要
and I think that's why it was important
实际上，我们对这个人的做法表示赞赏
we actually give this guy credit for the way
这
this
今天的期末考试
this final today
这很艰难
it's been tough
我的意思是
I mean
我还是回去了
I still go back to the
他罚了三个点球，没错
he gave three penalties he did yeah
他拿到了钱
he got the money
美泰劳
Mattel Lowe was
阿根廷对纽伦堡
Argentine against Nuremberg
14年本地生活
14 year local
那是最好的裁判
that was the best referee
我从来没见过这样的
I've ever seen that one
这是肯定的
that's for sure
所以
so
我不认为这是最佳年轻球员奖
I don't think that's the young player award
如果是的话，我们还有希望
if it is there's still hope for us
我想这可能是第一个奖项
I suspect that may be the first award
这是已知的
that's going to be given
我要为我们俩出去
I'm going to go out for us
他们为我们挑选的
that they pick out for us
年轻裁判奖
the young referees award
恩佐费尔南德斯
Enzo Fernandez
他一直很出色，不是吗
he's been excellent hasn't he
他一直是世界牌上的明星
he's been a star of the world card
是的
yeah
展示他的个性
show his personality
他在球场上很有水准
he's got this class in the ball
他在对墨西哥的比赛中进了一个漂亮的球
he's got a great goal against Mexico
他在为一个大球队效力
he's playing for a big team
他有三个球门球
he's got three goal balls
他有最好的线索
he's got the best lead
你认为他还会再玩一会儿吗?
do you think he'll go on to play for a bit?
也许这次
maybe this time
我认为最好的球员都想离开
I think best players all want to go
在最好的领导下打球
and play in the best lead
艾伦，你觉得他穿黑白相间的衬衫好看吗?
do you think he'll look good in a black and white shirt Alan?
绝对是的
absolutely yes
如果你想和伯恩茅斯比赛
save you wants to play against Bournemouth
星期二晚上
on Tuesday night
你喜欢罢工
you like strike
这是一场多么伟大的比赛啊
what a great tournament he's had
赢得那个奖
and to win that award
同时也赢得了奖杯
as well as winning the trophy as well
他所做的只是提高他的名声
he's done nothing but enhance his reputation
会有俱乐部围着他打探
there'll be clubs sniffing around him
顶级俱乐部
top top clubs
他这么小，今天却很镇定
he was so composed today for a kid so young
在这个层面上
in this level
战术上也很好
tactically very good as well
哇
wow
非常完全填充
very completely filled
能铲球吗
can put tackles in
球控能力强
good in the ball
他做得很好
he's done a great job
下一个
the next one
我们认为会是这样
we think it's going to be
金手套奖
the golden glove award
你觉得应该是谁
who do you think should
有一些
there's a few
列瓦科维奇的诗真的很好
Levaikovic's poem was really good
我想是埃米·马丁内斯吧
Emi Martinez I would imagine
他来了
there he is
他太值得了
he's so deserving
两次点球大战
two penalty shootouts
他是英雄
he's been the hero
再看看他的故事
also look at his story
在很小的时候
between the very young age
两个不同的俱乐部
two different clubs
去了西班牙
went to Spain
在lictu中演奏
playing in a lictu
疯狂的故事
crazy story
和她的
and she's
他绝对是仆人
he's absolutely the servant
做得好
well done
不，我不那样做
no I don't do that
这是我在美洲杯上看到的
it is something that I in Copa America
但他不需要这么做
but he doesn't need to do that
当然
of course
他应该疯了
he should be crazy
他十年前是牛津队的队员
he was playing for Oxford ten years ago
当然，他还是阿森纳的替补门将
and of course he was the Arsenal's reserve goalkeeper
我认为这是有道理的
and I think there was a point
当他真的闯入阿森纳队时
when he did break into the Arsenal team
那里有谣言
where there was rumours
我不知道它们有多真实
I don't know how true they were
足总正在调查
that the FA were looking
看看能不能弄到英国护照
to see if he could get a British passport
因为他很小的时候就在这个国家了
because he'd been in the country since he was very young
那样的话，他也许可以上场
in which case he could have perhaps played
英格兰，甚至威尔士
for England or even Wales
苏格兰或北爱尔兰
or Scotland or Northern Ireland
他就不会赢得这个奖杯
he wouldn't have won this trophy
他又要接电话了
he's about to pick up again
他最后过得不错，不是吗
he's ended up ok though don't you
至少他没有掉奖杯
at least he didn't drop his trophy
这是最重要的
that's the most important thing
现在是金靴
now the golden boot
这将是一场复杂的感情纠葛
this is going to be a mixed emotions run back
这是球迷们的欢呼
this is some sort of cheer from the fans
巨大的欢呼声
huge cheers
他活该
he deserves it
如果有什么区别的话
if anything
这显然是巨大的失望
it was obviously huge disappointment
由此得出结论
coming out of this
但他再次提高了自己的声誉
but again he's enhancing his reputation
如果可能的话
if that's possible
由此得出结论
coming out of this
这是一届多么精彩的世界杯啊
what a world cup he's had
他是个明星
he's been a star
他已经有一段时间了
he has been for quite some time
但他完全被证实了
but he's totally confirmed
他的显赫地位
his magnificent status
实际上，他有80分钟都没有
he didn't even actually, for 80 minutes
说实话，他很穷
he was poor if you've been honest
然后时刻就来了
and then the moments come
大玩家们站起来了
and the big players stand up and arrive
他做到了
and he's done that
多么了不起的球员
what a player
作为前锋，你能做到吗
do that as a forward though can't you
你不需要在90分钟内表现出色
you don't have to be brilliant for 90 minutes
你可以享受瞬间的魔力
you can just have one moment of magic
或者当你的国家或球队
or when your country or teams
都在游戏中
are in the game
他不仅是用
not only did he do it with the
八个目标
eight goals
那是一个能进8球的球员
that's a player to score eight goals
赢得金靴
to win the golden boot
某些罗纳尔多
certain Ronaldo
当然是巴西的罗纳尔多
Brazilian Ronaldo of course
El非凡的
El Phenomenal
那是在日本和韩国
that was in Japan and South Korea
下一个
the next one
我们认为是金球
we think is the golden ball
本届锦标赛最佳球员
best player of the tournament
肯定是莱昂纳多·梅西没有
it's got to be Leonardo Messi hasn't
我觉得他是个枪手
I think he was a shooter
谁今天又赢了
whoever won today again
它可以进入它们中的任何一个
it could have gone into either of them
胜者通吃
the winner takes all
大的快乐
big cheer
好了
there you go
这是他第二次赢得这个奖项
it's the second time he's won this
他在2014年赢得了这个奖项
he won that in 2014
在巴西
in Brazil
当他没有赢的时候
when he didn't win
但是他已经好多了
but he's been much better
100%
这是怎么出去的
what a way to go out
本届锦标赛最佳球员
best player of the tournament
赢得奖杯本身
win the trophy itself
7球
seven goals
完成力矩
moments of complete
魔法
magic
感觉就像，不是吗
it felt like didn't it
感觉每个人
it felt like that everyone
酒吧法国人
bar French people
也许是一些法国人希望这个人赢得比赛
and maybe some French people who wanted this guy to win this tournament
为了他的事业
for the career he's had
这说明了他的什么
what does that say about him
他给我们的快乐
the joy that he's given
感谢我们这么多年
to us for so many years
我喜欢这个镜头
I love that shot
哇
wow
你很快就能拿到了
you'll have it in your hands shortly
拿在手里吗
have it in your hands
他说过世界杯吗
did he ever speak about the World Cup
因为这显然是很重要的一部分
because it's obviously such a big part
他周围的故事
of the narrative around him
迭戈·马尔多纳等
with Diego Mardona etc
你有坐在那里听他讲过吗
did you ever sit there and hear him speaking about it
不，不，只是因为
no, no, just because
那可能是在2014年
that was probably back in 2014
我们就这么近了
we'd be that close
然后当然
and then of course
我很久没见过他了
I haven't seen him in the last
他走了两年了
two years since he went
到巴黎
to Paris
我从没想过我会看到一个更好的球员
I never thought I'd see a better player
而不是迭戈·马尔多纳
than Diego Mardona
比较他们有点不公平
it's slightly unfair to compare them
因为他们在不同的时期比赛
because they played in different times
但我认为通过他所取得的成就
but I think through what he's achieved
还有他的长寿
now and the fact that he's longevity
也许是迭戈
Diego for maybe
七、八、九、十年
seven, eight, nine, ten years
是如此相似
was so similar
但他已经做了将近二十年了
but he's done it for nearly two decades
七座金球奖
seven ballon d'or
你现在可能有八个了
you probably have eight now
每个人都说他必须这么做
and everyone said he had to do this
没有他
didn't he
这不是问号
it's not a question mark
但他总是被问到这个问题
but that was the thing that was always put to him
他会去赢吗
is he going to go and win
阿根廷赢得世界杯
the World Cup for Argentina
35岁的时候
at the age of 35
他在35岁左右就完成了这两件事
and he's done them both in his mid 30s
赢得两个大的
to win the two big ones
这可能是留住他的原因之一
it could be one of the drivers to keep him
在那种水平上打了这么久
playing at that level for so long as well
因为他没有赢的事实
because the fact that he hasn't won
也许他也有份
maybe he played a part
你觉得他现在会把脚抬起来一点吗
you think he'll put his feet up now a little bit
冷静点，我敢打赌他迫不及待地想看下一场巴黎圣日耳曼的比赛
chill out, I bet he can't wait for the next PSG game
这支球队参加了这次锦标赛
this team came into this tournament
36场不败
36 unbeaten
然后它们会相等
and then they were going to equal
对沙特阿拉伯的战绩
the record against Saudi Arabia
然后他们输掉了首场比赛
and then they lost the opening game
让它们继续反应
so for them to then go on and react
就像他们做的那样
like they have done
他是怎么做到的，哇
and how he has, wow
哇,确实
wow indeed
你认为他会腋下夹着奖杯走进巴黎圣日耳曼吗
do you think he walks into PSG with the trophy under his arm
我来展示给你们看
I'm going to show you
那东西也有一个
that thing has got one as well
他不能带着他的来对抗它
he can't bring his just to counter it
好吧，这比现在的新好多了
well that's good more than newly now
我认为仪式
I think the ceremony
即将开始
is about to begin
所以我们可以递回去了
so we can hand back
给盖伊·莫里
to Guy Mowry who's
主力小队还跟他在一起
got to main team is still with him
谢谢各位
thank you gentlemen
这是雨果·拉里斯和他的公司
this is the walk that Hugo Larisse and Co
会一直害怕过去吗
will have been dreading over the last
半小时左右
half an hour or so
不是他们想要的那个
not the one they wanted to take
只是为了跟进
just as a point to follow up
你在说什么啊
what you were talking about
日期是12月28日星期三
it's a week on Wednesday 28th December
巴黎圣日耳曼主场迎战斯特拉斯堡
PSG are at home to Strasbourg
在法甲
in Ligue 1
让我们看看是莱昂还是梅西会上场
let's see whether Leon or Messi will be playing
在那篇文章中
in that one
只要有一点机会，他就会这么做
given half a chance he will
因此,
so the
consulatory拥抱
consulatory hugs
这是个漫长的夜晚
it's been a long night
莉迪亚·德尚负责管理
Lydia Deschamps is managing
尽可能地笑
as much of a smile as he can
正如马克龙总统所威胁的那样
muster as President Macron threatens
永远不要让他走
to never let him go
问题是会发生什么
there's the question of what happens
和他在一起的还有
next with him there are
越来越多的报道称这是他干的
increasing reports that this is him done
还有齐达内
and that Zinedine Zidane no less
将会接手，这样他们就会得到很好的照顾
will be taking over so they'll be in good hands
杰梅因，哦耶
Jermaine oh yeah
顺便说一下，法国这边
I have to say by the way this French side
一无所有
have handled themselves with nothing
但类
but class
在整个过程中
throughout the whole time whilst
我们在等待这个仪式
we're waiting for this ceremony
以及阿根廷方面
and the Argentinian side
和球迷一起庆祝是正确的
rightly so celebrating with their fans
他们已经
they've
他们在失败中岿然不动
stood their gracious in defeat
他们真的有
they really have as they
周围的一切都相当精致
all mill around the rather elaborate
领奖台很有象征意义
podium it's quite emblematic
这届世界杯作为一个整体
of this world cup as a whole in that
组装起来又快又容易
it was quite quickly and easily put together
这里的人
by those here
它将被拆除
it will be dismantled
我可以想象很快
I would imagine pretty quickly
快闪世界杯在很多方面
pop-up world cup in many ways
沙漠里的十二月
December in the desert and all that
但足球确实起到了作用
but the football has certainly delivered
还有许多问题悬而未决
many other questions linger
一个大型的额外轨道
a big scale extra track
玩家将收到
on which the players will receive
银牌
the silver medals
就法国和即将到来的黄金而言
in the case of France and the gold to come
你可以看到
you can see
他们宁愿去别的地方
they would rather be anywhere else
但是站在那里拍照
but standing there for a photo
最后
at the end
顺便说一下，这些达官贵人是
the dignitaries incidentally are the
卡塔尔埃米尔谢赫·塔米姆
Amir of Qatar, Sheikh Tammim
本·哈马德·阿尔塔尼
Bin Hamad Al Tani
国际足联主席
FIFA president
拳击新教练和所有的詹尼和凡蒂诺
box fresh trainers and all Gianni and Fantino
曼纽尔·马克龙我们已经看到了很多
Manuel Macron we've seen plenty of the
法国总统阿尔贝托·费尔南德斯当选总统
French president Alberto Fernandez the president
阿根廷的总统已经是这样了
of Argentina will already be
开一瓶或三瓶什么的
opening a bottle or three of something
在布宜诺斯艾利斯的特别之处
special back in Buenos Aires
欧足联主席亚历山大·塞费林说
UEFA president Alexander Seferin
Conmobol的总裁
president of Conmobol
亚历杭德罗·多明格斯，巴拉圭人
Alejandro Dominguez who's a Paraguayan
但他一直在拥抱和亲吻
but he was hugging and kissing the
阿根廷球员克劳迪奥·塔皮尔
Argentina players Claudio Tappier
是AFA主席和诺利·瓦莱
is the AFA president and Nolig Valle
法国总统是谁
is the president of the French
足球联盟
Football Federation
来自
special words from
就像你之前说的，杰曼，这句话很好
as you said earlier Germain really nice line
总统对国王
a president to a king
当然是一个年轻的王子
certainly a young prince
我想他已经毕业了
you know yeah I think he's graduated
从王子
from Prince
这次比赛
this tournament
他今天竭尽所能了吗
did everything he could today to
把奖杯拿到他手里
get that trophy in his hands
他刚才走过的时候
on his walking by just now
不是这样的
wasn't to be
但他会回来的，这是毫无疑问的
but he'll be back again there's no doubt about that
我刚刚提到了巴拉圭人
I just mentioned the Paraguayan
Conmobol的主席满脸笑容
president of Conmobol was all smiles
和
and
我们听到了很多报道，也看到了
we've heard so many reports and we've seen it
用我们自己的眼睛
with our own eyes that
你相信吗?
would you believe
在世界杯上
at a World Cup
巴西人一直支持
Brazilians have been supporting
阿根廷出局后
Argentina once they were out
这是事实
and that's a fact
我们已经看到了
we've seen it
我们已经落后于他们的大陆
we have got behind their continent
最终
which has finally
战胜了欧洲
got the better of Europe
第一次
for the first time
20年后
in 20 years
这是一场欧洲阅兵
it's been a European parade
从那以后，他就一直在世界杯上比赛
in World Cups ever since
我们有一个非洲团队
we've had an African team
进入半决赛
through to the semi-finals
摩洛哥的一个阿拉伯国家
an Arab nation in Morocco
克罗地亚队可以再次夺冠
Croatia can found in the odds again
获得第三名
to finish third
半决赛本身，所以有很多故事
in the semi-finals themselves so there are so many stories
但现在是阿根廷的时刻
but now it's Argentina's moment
以及颁奖典礼
and the presentation ceremony
增加一点，再多判断一点
ramps up, judges that a little bit more
它们都是按数字顺序来做的
they're all going to do it in number order
首先
so first up
是某人
is somebody who
还没有参加过锦标赛
hasn't had any playing time at the tournament
弗兰科·阿玛尼，河床守门员
Franco Armani, the river plate goalkeeper
他会珍惜的
and he will treasure that
金牌和其他人一样多
gold medal as much as anybody else
2号
number two
胡安Foyt
Juan Foyt
托特纳姆热刺的前任
ex of Tottenham Hotspur
他只在一场比赛中替补出场
he only came on as a substitute in one game
现在在西班牙流行开来
now a virial in Spain
接着是3号
and he's followed up by the number three
尼克拉斯·塔利亚菲科，然后是4号
Niklas Taliafico and then the number four
活下来的人
the man who will live
那一刻永远永远
that moment for ever and a day
冈萨洛蒙特埃尔
Gonzalo Montiel
被踢的那个人
the man who took the kick
并且罚进了点球
and scored the penalty
为阿根廷赢得世界杯
that won the World Cup for Argentina
几十年又几十年
after decades and decades
等待它再次发生
of waiting for it to happen again
第七名罗德里戈·德·保罗
number seven Rodrigo de Paul
被打得遍体鳞伤
has been battered and bruised
踢了一下
and kicked a bit
不仅在这款游戏中，在之前的一些游戏中也是如此
not just in this game but in a few previously as well
但我们还有足够的能量上去
but we've got plenty of energy left to get up there
然后是马科斯·阿库纳
and then Marcos Acunha
塞维利亚的球员
of Sevilla who came on and
尽力扼杀法国戏剧
tried his best to stifle the French play
还踢了他们几个
and kick a few of them as well
他是替补上场的
and he came on as a substitute
现在这是一个竞争者
and now here is a contender
或者也是本届锦标赛年轻球员的有力竞争者
or was a contender for young player in the tournament too
朱利安·阿尔瓦雷斯
Julian Alvarez
我们希望他能多呆几分钟
we hopefully get to see him have a few more minutes
从现在起，我将成为英超联赛的一员
in the Premier League from here on in
我想我们一定会的
I think we definitely will
他为阿根廷队贡献了很多
he offered so much in this Argentinian side
他的精力，他的步伐，他的努力
his energy, his pace, his endeavour
他工作的意愿
his willingness to work
以及他所带来的品质
and the quality that he brought with it
当然漏掉了数字10
missed out the number ten of course
因为他会以船长的身份走到终点
because he will bring up the end of the line as captain
迪马利亚
Di Maria
多么美妙的一刻
what a moment
如果这是他最后一场国家队比赛的话
if this is to be his last game in international football
谢谢你，安吉尔·迪·玛丽亚
well thank you Angel Di Maria
因为你给了我们一场表演
because you gave us a show
他确实照里奥说的做了
he did indeed and as Rio was saying
他今天经历了情绪波动
he went through the emotions today
迪·玛丽亚，摄影师
Di Maria, the cameraman
不停地打断他
kept cutting to him
在泪水和笑声和
in tears and laughing and
剩下的，但是
the rest of it but
这是一个顶级的表现
it's a top performance overall
几乎每一个球员
and pretty much every single player
是占用他们的私人时间吗
is taking their own personal moment
只是惊叹于奖杯
to just marvel at the trophy
有一个激动的时刻
have an emotional moment
拿着奖杯
with the trophy
哪个是36厘米半高
which is 36 and a half centimetres high
体重刚刚超过6公斤
weighs just over six kilograms
5公斤18k黄金
five kilograms of 18 karat gold
还有一个包含两层孔雀石的底座
and a base that contains two layers of malachite
这是最
it is the most
珍贵的奖杯
prized trophy
在足球世界里
in the football world
很少有球员能自称
and so few players get to call themselves
世界冠军
world champions
但
but
阿根廷人现在可以做的事情
things Argentinians can now
奥塔门迪的吻
a kiss from Otamendi
他走过时瞥了我一眼
a little glance on his way past
来自亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特
from Alexis McAllister
多么年轻的巨星啊
what a young superstar
已经过去一个月了
has come over the last month
精彩的世界杯
what a world cup
他的表现非常出色
he's been absolutely brilliant
你知道吗，他今晚在最盛大的舞台上做到了
and you know what, he did it on the biggest stages tonight
就像他上场打球一样
as well turning up and playing the way he did
就像你说的伙计
as you said guy
绝对的巨星
an absolute superstar
内米·马丁内斯已经死了
Nemi Martinez was already
在阿根廷备受尊敬
revered in Argentina
太迟了
and too late
他早该这么做了
he should have been years and years ago
他不得不在阿森纳等待时机
he had to wait at Arsenal for his time
他必须等待祖国的到来
he had to wait for his country
在他那个时代
for his time
去年的美洲杯冠军
Copa America winner last year
多亏了他扑救点球的英勇表现
thanks to his penalty saving heroics
现在他做了类似的工作
and now he's done a similar job
在FIFA世界杯上
at the FIFA World Cup
阿斯顿维拉
be proud Aston Villa
非常自豪
be very proud indeed
那这个人呢，莱昂内尔·斯科洛尼
what about this man, Leonel Skoloni
2016年
in 2016
他当时在马略卡岛当地的一支青年队执教
he was coaching a local junior side in Mallorca
在那之后不久
shortly after that
他在社交媒体上发了一片混乱
he sent out a social media mess
他说在报告出来后别去找利奥
he's saying don't go Leo after the reports
梅西退出国家队的传闻
of Messi quitting the national team
和他一起为阿根廷效力
played with him for Argentina
只有几次
just a handful of times
现在他帮了忙
and now he has helped
他的队长是最伟大的
his captain the greatest
献给最伟大的球员们
to the greatest players of all
精神
the spirit
昔日伟大的阿根廷
of the previous great Argentina
10号我们将拭目以待
number 10 we'll be looking on
迭戈·阿曼多·马拉多纳
Diego Armando Maradona
一个字2到
a word 2 to
亚历克斯Cervella
Alex Cervella
2014年差点就成功的教练
the coach who came close in 2014
在巴西的决赛中被击败
beaten in the final in Brazil
他不幸去世了
by Germany he sadly passed away
两年前的这个月
two years ago this month
我相信他的家人也会为他感到骄傲
I'm sure his will be a proud family as well
谢菲尔德联队的海克斯
Hex of Sheffield United
和利兹联队有很多联系
and Leeds United there are many connections
整个过程都是英式比赛
with the English game right throughout
阿根廷足球
Argentinian football
这是一个夜晚
this is a night
为所有在布宜诺斯艾利斯的人准备的
for all of those in Buenos Aires
再到拯救者
and beyond to Saver
一个晚上
a night
当真正的足球之王
when the true king of football
最终加冕
was finally coronated
一个皇帝
an emperor
我们的术语用完了
we run out of terms
来描述
to describe
最伟大的，看看这个
the greatest and look at that
他一直在等这一刻
he's waited for this all of
他的生活
his life
在成为专业人士之前，这是一个关键时刻
before becoming a professional this is the moment
他会梦见
he will have dreamt about
这是我认为的时刻
this is the moment I think
我们都认为这是他的命运
we've all thought would be his destiny
这是我们期待已久的时刻
that's the moment we've all waited for
看这里
look here we
在这里见证这一切
to be here to witness it
以及卡塔尔的埃米尔
and the Amir of Qatar
詹尼·因凡蒂诺将会离开
and Gianni Infantino will pass on
世界杯
the World Cup
献给世界上最好的人
to the world's best
队长梅西
Lionel Messi the captain
阿根廷人将捧起奖杯
of Argentina will hold that trophy
他整晚都不肯松口
close he won't let it go all night
它可能会被借用一段时间
it might be borrowed for a bit by
小队的其他成员
the rest of that squad
但那是他应该珍惜的
but that's his to cherish
这意味着整个世界
this means the world
对梅西
to Messi
到阿根廷再到南美洲
to Argentina to South America
这是一个意义重大的时刻
it is the moment that means
阿根廷
Argentina
澳洲冠军
champion down under
世界冠军
champions of the world's
最大的游戏
greatest game
令人惊叹的场景
amazing scenes
哇
wow
上面的照片很棒
great pictures from above
在地面上有很棒的照片
and great pictures inside the ground
在阿根廷
as Argentina
第三次赢得世界杯
win the World Cup for the third time
这是1986年以来的第一次
in the first time since 1986
当然，他们也在1978年赢得了冠军
they also won it of course in 1978
在他们自己的国家
in their own country
但这是一个神奇的时刻
but this is a magic moment
在某种程度上似乎是一种耻辱
seems a shame in a way
他们掩盖了梅西
that they've covered up Messi
穿着阿根廷球衣
in his Argentina shirt
你觉得巴勃罗?
do you think Pablo?
究竟是为什么
just why
没理由这么做
no reason to do that
我不认为是因凡蒂诺
didn't think Infantino
你也打算放手吗
was going to let it go either
没有人
no one got
在那场比赛中，标志很接近
marks in that closely in the game
把奖杯给他
give him the trophy
不过他在狭小的空间里表现得很好
he is good in tight spaces though
所以他最后还是设法从他身边逃走了
so he managed to get away from him in the end
把它提起来
and lift that
美妙的奖杯
wonderful trophy
今晚布宜诺斯艾利斯会是什么样子?
what's it going to be like in Buenos Aires tonight?
哦,不
oh no
一定是疯子
must be crazy people
今天就像
today would be like
好孩子们又来了
nice children are there again
在阿根廷，每个人都会发疯的
everyone will go mad in Argentina
接下来
for the next
不仅仅是今天
not only today
但接下来的三四天
but for the next three or four days
希望所有的球员
hopefully all the players
这是阿根廷的好消息
the good news for them in Argentina
现在才差一刻四点
it's still only quarter to four
但我认为
but I think
所有球员都将被允许前往阿根廷
all the players will be allowed to go to Argentina
待了三四天
for three or four days
他们必须去，然后回来
they have to go and come back
他们至少要给他们
they have to give them at least
他们都是一个星期
all of them a week
你应该回到你的祖国去庆祝
you've got to go and celebrate in your homeland
我在想
I was thinking
亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特，他打得很好
Alexis McAllister who played so well
布莱顿战胜了南安普顿
Brighton have got Southampton away
在节礼日
on boxing day
我怀疑他不会在那里
I suspect he won't be there
这样你就不会觉得我不在了
so you won't think I would not be there
如果我赢得了世界杯，那将是一场噩梦
I would be a nightmare if I had won the World Cup
这一季剩下的比赛你就得把我删了
you would have to delete me for the rest of the season
多么奇妙的画面啊
what a fantastic image
这可能是他梦寐以求的东西
it's the thing he's probably dreamed of
他的一生
all his life
一个人完成
someone completed
完成甲板
completed the deck
他们在这次比赛中买了很多东西
they've bought so much this tournament
阿根廷也是如此
Argentina as well
和粉丝在一起
with the fans
因为很明显这不是一场正常的比赛
because obviously it's not been a normal tournament
从某种意义上说，有大量的粉丝
in the sense that huge amounts of fans
特别是来自欧洲
particularly from Europe
他们没来过这里
they've not been here
但阿根廷球迷
but Argentina's fans
成千上万的人来了
came in their thousands
他们所做的
they did
对他们来说，这是一个多么美好的夜晚啊
what a night for them
阿根廷是最好的球迷
Argentina the best fans
最好的球队，他们赢了
best team they won it
在比赛中拥有最好的粉丝
and had the best fans at the tournament
这是一个可爱的时刻，不是吗
this was a lovely moment wasn't it
梅西
Lionel Messi
梦想梦想梦想
dreams dreams dreams
盖伯瑞尔
Gabriel
这正是他非常想要的
that's what he so badly wanted
多么了不起的成就啊
what an achievement
多么优秀的一面啊
what an excellent side
当然是输了第一场
losing the first game of course
每个人都认为
and everyone thought this
他们并没有大家想象的那么好
not as good a team as everyone thought they might be
这是麦卡利斯特
there is McAllister
显然已经在想了
obviously already thinking
关于他去南安普顿的旅行
about his trip to Southampton
顺便说一下，麦卡利斯特非常出色
McAllister was excellent by the way
他真的真的很可靠
he was really really solid
每场比赛的玩家
player for every game
坚实可靠的
solid reliable
一些神奇的时刻
some magic moments
下一届世界杯完全不同
very different world cup next time
当然是三个不同的国家
of course three different countries
三个大国在广阔的空间
three large countries over big space
48个团队
48 teams
他们现在已经开始重新思考了
they've already now starting to rethink
显然是小组赛阶段，我认为这是明智的
apparently the group stage which I think is sensible
要做到这一点
to do that
但它会给一些国家和一些参与者
but it will give countries and some players
参加世界杯的机会
opportunities to play in a world cup
否则这可能行不通
that perhaps otherwise won't do
比如本届世界杯
for example in this world cup
我们没有哈兰，不是吗
we didn't have Harland did we
他会有更好的机会
he'll have a better chance
其他国家也错过了
other countries missed out
萨拉赫当然没有入选
Mo Salah of course didn't make
世界杯也一样
the world cup either
虽然他四年前打过
although he did play four years ago
最后说说你对比赛的看法
final your thoughts on the tournament
总的来说，对你来说很明显
as a whole probably obviously for you
对我来说，这是一次很棒的经历
for me it's been a great experience
世界杯之前我就知道了
I know that before the world cup
他们可能是最
they were probably one of the most
有争议的
controversial
但我不得不说，我从来没有参加过世界杯
ever world cup but I have to say
这真是太棒了
that it's been brilliant
在我看来
from my point of view
就足球而言
in terms of football
惊喜
surprises
再也不会像以前那样了
and never the things it's been
太棒了，我真的很喜欢
fantastic I really enjoy
我的时间
my time
梅西的球衣上有三颗星
three stars on Messi's shirt
我想我发现了
I think I spot
他在拿
there and he's taking
脱下小袍子
the little robe off
但
but
足球智慧
football wise
有一些令人难以置信的比赛
there's been some incredible games
一些真正的烦恼是好的
some real upsets which is good
一支非洲球队进入了半决赛
an African team got to the semi final
最令人难忘的决赛
and the most memorable final
可能我们都见过
probably we've ever seen
我们再也不会看到这样的事了
we'll never see anything like this again
我无法想象当你拥有两支伟大的球队时，这种情况会发生
I can't imagine that happening where you get two great teams
从头到脚，没人退一步
go toe to toe no one takes the back step
我们队的两位超级明星
the two superstars on our team
又是一场恶战
again slugging it out
黄金换黄金，如此瑰丽
gold for gold so magnificent
我真的很喜欢
I've really enjoyed it
不知道会发生什么
didn't know what to expect
什么都吃了一点
had a bit of everything
今晚比那更好
better than that out there tonight
在我告别巴勃罗之前
before I say farewell Pablo
你手里拿的是什么
what you got in your hands there
把它挂起来
put it up
好了
there you go
许多祝贺
many congratulations
顺便说一句，我不得不说
by the way I have to say
这绝对是我的荣幸
it's been an absolute pleasure
你的到来是我的荣幸
it's been a pleasure to have you
一路走来
and all the way
非常感谢
thank you very much
谢谢你让我参与其中
thank you for making me so part of that
伟大的BBC团队
great team from BBC
这是一次很棒的经历
it's been a great experience
就是这样
that's it
阿根廷第三次赢得世界杯
Argentina win their third World Cup
感谢大家在过去的一个月里参加我们的节目
thank you for joining us over the last month
开始有感觉了
it's beginning to feel
很有圣诞节气氛的
quite Christmasy
再见
goodbye
我太爱你了
I'm so in love with you
梦想就像
dreams are like
天使
angels
他们把坏人拒之门外
they keep bad at bay
陷入困境
bad at bay
爱是光明
love is the light
可怕的
scary
黑暗了
darkness away
是的
yeah
我坠入爱河了
I'm so in love
和你在一起
with you
灵魂的一部分
part of the soul
让爱
makes love
你的目标
your goal
爱的力量
the power of love
来自上天的力量
a force from above
净化我的灵魂
cleaning my soul
归咎于燃烧的欲望
blame on burn desire
爱
love
火舌
tongues of fire
伤害灵魂
hurts the soul
做爱
make love
你的
your
我会保护你
I'll protect you
来自兜帽
from the hood
留着吸血鬼吧
keep the vampires
从你的门口
from your door
关键时刻
when the chips are down
我会在你身边
I'll be around
带着我的永恒
with my undying
具有欺骗性的
deceptive
爱你
love for you
和你
and you
会伤到自己
will hurt itself
让自己
let yourself
是美丽的
be beautiful
闪闪发光的
sparkling
鲜花和珍珠
flowers and pearls
漂亮女孩
pretty girls
花朵像一种能量
flowers like an energy
刷牙和刷牙
brushing and brushing
在我内心深处
inside of me
是的
yeah
的力量
the power
爱的
of love
来自上天的力量
a force from above
净化我的灵魂
cleaning my soul
哦
oh
归咎于燃烧
blame on burn
欲望
desire
爱
love
火舌
tongues of fire
伤害灵魂
hurts the soul
做爱
make love
你的
your
目标
goal
哈利凯恩
Harry Kane
已经错过了
has missed
从罚球点开始
from the penalty spot
的力量
the power
爱的
of love
来自上天的力量
a force from above
打扫我的
cleaning my
灵魂
soul
的力量
the power
爱的
of love
来自上天的力量
a force from above
天空刮倒
a sky scraping down
归咎于燃烧
blame on burn
欲望
desire
带着火舌
with tongues of fire
伤害灵魂
hurts the soul
做爱
make love
看D玛丽亚
look at D Maria
那是一个支架
that's a ramstand
这会被罚的
that's gonna be a penalty
和Bappe
and Bappe
他做到了
he's done it
哦cahabla
oh cahabla
在一瞬间
in a heartbeat
朋友们在0 - 2落后的情况下回来了
friends have come from 2-0 down
米西又想要了
missy wants it again
曼扎诺小姐
Leonel Missy
点球
penalty
巴佩就是那个人
and Bappe is the man
这是阿根廷
it's Argentina
足球之王
Kings of football
第三次了
for the third time